<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"

  >
<channel>
  <title>Comments on: Primary Reader &#8211; Said and Shah&#8217;s Orientalism and Politics of Knowledge</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

  <item>
    <title>By: Linda He</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/#comment-3</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 03:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=186#comment-3</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[&quot;Medias and literature were being used to portray negative image of Asians in the western world, and that created discriminations and against the east side.&quot; I agree that media and technology can produce certain types of knowledge and biases against some Asian populations that are discriminatory. This discrimination is most obvious in United States legislation such as the Chinese Exclusion act which would &quot;decrease the white workers’ unemployment rate.&quot; As Shah mentions, &quot;White workers started to lose their job because of the Chinese workers and the cholera and smallpox epidemic in San Francisco built discriminations toward the Chinese immigrants&quot; which I think is clearly referenced in how Chinese immigrants were treated in San Francisco in 1949 and beyond after Gold was found. It always seemed that Caucasions did not want to compete with the Chinese or Asian population as referenced by the competition between the two or more races in building in the United States transcontinental railway system. I think the fact that Chinese populations built the transcontinent system is the same sentiment as African populations who build the slavery system in Southern America with cotton picking reminiscent of how this country was &quot;built on the backs of slaves&quot; in the 18th century. Shah also mentions about the &quot;investigations&quot; that shaped many political and medical discourses on the Chinese populations as filthy and disease prone - most notably &quot;Chlorea.&quot; These discourses are very much in the sentiment that seems to be expressed in today&#039;s remarks and opinions but that doesn&#039;t change the fact of the the racial discrimination and the unfair treatment of Chinese populations through United States legislation such as the Exclusionary Acts and Gentlemen&#039;s Agreement during Theodore Roosevelt&#039;s presidency in the 19th century. I have never seen San Francisco&#039;s Chinatown but Shah seems to go into great detail in mentioning the discourses and nuances in how policies were made and how inspections were to follow, all which discriminated the Chinese populations in some way.
I think Edward Said&#039;s comment about &quot;unlearning&quot; ways of thinking is similar to comments made by other people of the Asian community. I like how he identifies the &quot;occidental&quot; and the &quot;oriental&quot; but he ultimately states it is a theory just as how some come to find the first, second, and third worlds as non-existent. I think it is useful for different authors to have different methods of comparison and investigation. Said goes into a much more historical context than Shah in investigating political discourses, actions, intentions, and motives while Shah focuses on San Francisco&#039;s Chinatown relative to the ones that could be found in Flushing, Sunset Park, and Manhattan.
Discussion Question: What other ways could Shah have built his investigation on his description of San Francisco&#039;s Chinatown and is Said&#039;s argument of the Orient and Occident compelling?]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Medias and literature were being used to portray negative image of Asians in the western world, and that created discriminations and against the east side.&#8221; I agree that media and technology can produce certain types of knowledge and biases against some Asian populations that are discriminatory. This discrimination is most obvious in United States legislation such as the Chinese Exclusion act which would &#8220;decrease the white workers’ unemployment rate.&#8221; As Shah mentions, &#8220;White workers started to lose their job because of the Chinese workers and the cholera and smallpox epidemic in San Francisco built discriminations toward the Chinese immigrants&#8221; which I think is clearly referenced in how Chinese immigrants were treated in San Francisco in 1949 and beyond after Gold was found. It always seemed that Caucasions did not want to compete with the Chinese or Asian population as referenced by the competition between the two or more races in building in the United States transcontinental railway system. I think the fact that Chinese populations built the transcontinent system is the same sentiment as African populations who build the slavery system in Southern America with cotton picking reminiscent of how this country was &#8220;built on the backs of slaves&#8221; in the 18th century. Shah also mentions about the &#8220;investigations&#8221; that shaped many political and medical discourses on the Chinese populations as filthy and disease prone &#8211; most notably &#8220;Chlorea.&#8221; These discourses are very much in the sentiment that seems to be expressed in today&#8217;s remarks and opinions but that doesn&#8217;t change the fact of the the racial discrimination and the unfair treatment of Chinese populations through United States legislation such as the Exclusionary Acts and Gentlemen&#8217;s Agreement during Theodore Roosevelt&#8217;s presidency in the 19th century. I have never seen San Francisco&#8217;s Chinatown but Shah seems to go into great detail in mentioning the discourses and nuances in how policies were made and how inspections were to follow, all which discriminated the Chinese populations in some way.<br />
I think Edward Said&#8217;s comment about &#8220;unlearning&#8221; ways of thinking is similar to comments made by other people of the Asian community. I like how he identifies the &#8220;occidental&#8221; and the &#8220;oriental&#8221; but he ultimately states it is a theory just as how some come to find the first, second, and third worlds as non-existent. I think it is useful for different authors to have different methods of comparison and investigation. Said goes into a much more historical context than Shah in investigating political discourses, actions, intentions, and motives while Shah focuses on San Francisco&#8217;s Chinatown relative to the ones that could be found in Flushing, Sunset Park, and Manhattan.<br />
Discussion Question: What other ways could Shah have built his investigation on his description of San Francisco&#8217;s Chinatown and is Said&#8217;s argument of the Orient and Occident compelling?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
