<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Announcements &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/category/announcements/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>	<item>
		<title>Primary Reader on June 26th</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 04:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=660</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Asian American Displacements” by Wanni Anderson and Robert Lee focus on a few frame works including what Asian Americanists study about, the relationship between Asian settlement and the patterns of American history and society, Asian immigrant workers’ role in shaping both the land and social terrain, the connection between American imperialism and the trajectories of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Asian American Displacements” by Wanni Anderson and Robert Lee focus on a few frame works including what Asian Americanists study about, the relationship between Asian settlement and the patterns of American history and society, Asian immigrant workers’ role in shaping both the land and social terrain, the connection between American imperialism and the trajectories of class, race and gender in the U.S. What I found interesting is their idea of four forms of displacement which is including the refugee, the exile, the expatriate, and the migrant.  These four forms have to deal with physical, cultural, psychological, and the intellectual displacement.  The structure of this piece is interesting because it contains a collection of scholar’s references to support their central idea.</p>
<p>In the other piece “Deporting Cambodian Refugees: Youth Activism, State Reform, and Imperial Statecraft” by Soo Ah Kwon is a case study and it includes author’s experience with the AYPAL youth and their campaign to put an end to deportations.  First she chronicles young people’s direct engagement with the state and the political process, and second, “I critically examine how, in confronting the limits of their relationship to the state, AYPAL youth uncovered that the neoliberal state is an imperial state” (Kwon 739).  I think Kwon’s piece is so different from the other pieces we have read because it actually based on author’s own experience in a case study.  Her topic of deportation of Asians got caught my attention because I did not know how these South Asians are living unfairly before I read her article.  She includes documentations in her piece.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">660</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#8211; July 8th Readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-july-8th-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-july-8th-readings/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 09:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=636</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think this TED talk shows how space and mobilization have helped her not only escape and reach freedom but shaped her struggle. She has found &#8216;safe spaces&#8217; in her quest for freedom in China and South Korea, but they are not completely without danger. Her movement between these safe spaces define a refugee network [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/lang/en/hyeonseo_lee_my_escape_from_north_korea.html" width="500" height="750" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
<p>I think this TED talk shows how space and mobilization have helped her not only escape and reach freedom but shaped her struggle. She has found &#8216;safe spaces&#8217; in her quest for freedom in China and South Korea, but they are not completely without danger. Her movement between these safe spaces define a refugee network for North Koreans.</p>
<p>These &#8216;safe&#8217; spaces she found with their own inherent dangers present a new perspective. In China, she <em>knew</em> she was North Korean, but had to pretend she was Chinese, or risk repatriation. But in South Korea, she began to question her own identity because of the division between North and South Korea even though they were one country. The implication that <em>one</em> country and space (Korea) is divided into <em>two</em> spaces (North and South Korea) with <em>two</em> racial identities (North and South Korean) rather than <em>one</em> racial identity (Korean, which is more normal in America) makes me wonder what nuances exist between them that can cause an identity crisis (is it another difference due to culture or more due to loyalty?).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-july-8th-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">636</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; July 1st Readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/15/primary-reader-july-1st-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/15/primary-reader-july-1st-readings/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 07:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=634</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Something I found interesting in Junaid Rana&#8217;s piece Racial Panic, Islamic Peril, and Terror was how the &#8216;moral panic&#8217; that spread through America in the aftermath of Sept. 11th was warped and transformed into a &#8216;racial panic&#8217; even though Muslim isn&#8217;t a race, it&#8217;s a religion. Something else I also found odd was how it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Something I found interesting in Junaid Rana&#8217;s piece <em>Racial Panic, Islamic Peril, and Terror</em> was how the &#8216;moral panic&#8217; that spread through America in the aftermath of Sept. 11th was warped and transformed into a &#8216;racial panic&#8217; even though Muslim isn&#8217;t a race, it&#8217;s a religion. Something else I also found odd was how it appeared that anybody perceived to be &#8216;Muslim&#8217; was subjected to the same racial profiling and treatment even though there were few documented cases of other Asians being mistaken for Japanese during World War 2. This is especially odd since it is easier to distinguish who is Muslim and who is not by their religious dress compared to being able to distinguish between the different Asian populations which could easily cause confusion.</p>
<p>In the case that Rana mentions of Homeland Security and the FBI attempting to locate five individuals who&#8217;s names and birth dates were possibly fictitious and were not likely to have terrorist affiliations according to the information they have so far, the vagueness of the situation allowed for the case to easily become a mass panic. This case I think especially highlights how easily and closely linked racialization and illegality is to terror and panic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/15/primary-reader-july-1st-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">634</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#8211; June 26th Readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-june-26th-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-june-26th-readings/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 05:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=631</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the Lisa Lowe&#8217;s Heterogeneity, Hybridity, and Multiplicity: Asian American Differences and Wanni Anderson and Robert G. Lee&#8217;s Asian American Displacements readings, it brought to mind an episode of Cold Case which embodied several of the elements we spoke about in class (online stream here: Cold Case Season 02 Episode 05). In this episode, there are brief references to what Lisa [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the Lisa Lowe&#8217;s <em>Heterogeneity, Hybridity, and Multiplicity: Asian American Differences</em> and Wanni Anderson and Robert G. Lee&#8217;s <em>Asian American Displacements</em> readings, it brought to mind an episode of Cold Case which embodied several of the elements we spoke about in class (online stream here: <a href="http://www.tubeplus.me/player/796073/Cold_Case/season_2/episode_5/Who's_Your_Daddy/">Cold Case Season 02 Episode 05</a>).</p>
<p>In this episode, there are brief references to what Lisa Lowe refers to as the idea of a homogeneous Asian American population and the different kinds of displacements experienced by Asians. For the first example, Brad Atwater (the victim&#8217;s boss) incorrectly refers to Channary Dhiet (the murdered wife) as &#8216;Miss Saigon&#8217; when in fact, the Dhiets are Cambodian. This plays into the misconception that Asians are all one population. For the second example, we look at Sen and Channary Dhiet (the murdered couple) who are physically, culturally, and psychologically displaced as a result of being Cambodian refugees. They are also socio-economically displaced rather than intellectually displaced as they were members of the royal family in Cambodia and in America they were illegal immigrants who ended up taking the identities of fellow immigrants to stay alive.</p>
<p>These brief references to several elements that have been mentioned in class display how vulnerable (Asian) immigrant populations are after they come to America. This episode reveals the darker possibilities of displacement and the susceptibility that displaced immigrants encounter.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-june-26th-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">631</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher for 7/10</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/10/researcher-for-710/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/10/researcher-for-710/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 07:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=592</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://encyclopedia.jrank.org/articles/pages/5968/THE-SHIFT-TOWARD-RACIALIZATION.html The above article elaborates on the racialization of Arab women in America both currently and 30+years back.  It makes an interesting point about the relation between religion and race (namely racism&#8217;s conflation of &#8216;Arab&#8217; and &#8216;Muslim&#8217;), saying that Arab Americans have faced plenty of racism since before the majority of Arab American immigrants were [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>http://encyclopedia.jrank.org/articles/pages/5968/THE-SHIFT-TOWARD-RACIALIZATION.html<br />
The above article elaborates on the racialization of Arab women in America both currently and 30+years back.  It makes an interesting point about the relation between religion and race (namely racism&#8217;s conflation of &#8216;Arab&#8217; and &#8216;Muslim&#8217;), saying that Arab Americans have faced plenty of racism since before the majority of Arab American immigrants were even muslim.  This article cleanly sweeps aside any argument that Arab Americans are simply considered &#8216;white&#8217; in America, reminds readers that Arab Americans can be discriminated against for their race <em>and </em>their stereotyped [imagined] connection to Islam, not to mention the racism against Arab Americans is so strong (and, of course, not kept distinct enough) as to spill over onto virtually all middle-easterners as well as Indian Americans and some other Asian peoples in America.  This article is relevant to the Andrea Smith reading, particularly the bit about the &#8220;whiteness&#8221; of Arab Americans, plus it references Omi and Winant&#8217;s famous Racial Formation paper.</p>
<p>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/daniel-little/where-is-student-activism_b_1654460.html<br />
While the above doesn&#8217;t really focus on <em>Asian American</em> student activism, I feel that it does speak to the Umemoto and Yamashita readings by investigating changes in student activism (specifically racial activism) since the 1960s. The article makes reference to the birth of Asian-American studies (amongst other race and identity studies) from the success of the African American civil rights movement in popularizing race &amp; identity studies, starting with African American studies.  This goes to show that the decision for Asian American and African American activist groups to cooperate as in &#8220;On Strike!&#8221; did, at least in some way, pay off in the long run.  It also takes a few jabs at figuring out why such fervent student activism has since died down, stating that it isn&#8217;t a matter of the amount of support for a cause, but a slew of other factors that allow for large-scale activist movements to take hold as they did in the &#8217;60s.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/10/researcher-for-710/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">592</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader: Asian American Studies</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-3/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-3/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 03:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akash Sharma]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=584</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week&#8217;s readings focused on Asian American Studies and how they are constantly in change since the begining. The readings for the week talk about what factors influence this change. From all the three reading for the week, I really liked Unemoto&#8217;s chapter 1 &#8220;On Strike&#8221; that was focused on the series of strikes that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week&#8217;s readings focused on Asian American Studies and how they are constantly in change since the begining. The readings for the week talk about what factors influence this change. From all the three reading for the week, I really liked Unemoto&#8217;s chapter 1 &#8220;On Strike&#8221; that was focused on the series of strikes that occured in the San Franciso State College from 1968-69. The strike was conducted by various student leaders of Thris World Liberation Front who with the help of others marched demanding relevant education and easy access to their communiites (Umemoto 24). Accroding to the author, such movements &#8220;produce major changes in the economic or political structure&#8221; and I think, whether in State colleges or not, results in contentious politics (Tilly and Tarrow). What these types of movements especially in colleges result in formation of various organisations which further produce number of activists. </p>
<p>Similarly, the article &#8220;A Full-on CRAASh at Hunter College&#8221; talks about the same. Student of Hunter College wanted relevant education and when denied, took steps that the author talks about very well. Similar situations can also be seen where students often use various propaganda techniques to focus their demands or raise their voices. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">584</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader: Asian American Studies</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-2/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 01:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=595</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I really liked the article “A Full-on CRAASH at Hunter College” because I have met members who were part of the organization in the spring of 2011. They seemed very committed to the cause so I did not find it a surprise that this article showcased the passionate leaders of the organization. I took several Asian [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I really liked the article “A Full-on CRAASH at Hunter College” because I have met members who were part of the organization in the spring of 2011. They seemed very committed to the cause so I did not find it a surprise that this article showcased the passionate leaders of the organization. I took several Asian American courses and I found them really helpful in understanding the discourse of various liberation movements. I thought it was really helpful for future students of that rally to continue to be able to take courses because it offers insight into Asian American history and sentiment. It is a different telling of history in the eyes of several Asian American scholars as well as an education in how we can fight for Asian American rights.</p>
<p>It is difficult to maintain a Hunter College Asian American Studies Program without enough funding as well as the constant change of faculty but otherwise looking at the courses that Hunter College offers, I actually think it is plenty. It did not surprise me that Hunter College had more Asian American Studies Courses than most schools in New York and the only CUNY to offer the program but I do think it is necessary to continue to fight for more funding and better resources to teach the material better. The more courses I took, the more I could relate the material to other discourses in political science and the more I understood how the world worked under systems of oppression, marginalization, and empire.</p>
<p>That being said, I was not surprised to read that within the CUNY system, administration gave apathetic responses when students fought for greater funding for Asian American Studies Program and more resources. I think it is a predictable response by the Hunter College administration to students who want to break the status quo for a program that promotes awareness. It is a predictable response in terms of understanding neo-liberalism why the administration would want to push off the interests of the Asian American Studies Program. I think it is easier for the administration to push off the interests of the students in comparison to the response by the college administration during the San Francisco protests.</p>
<p>In “’On Strike!’: San Francisco College Strike, 1968-1969’” by Karen Umemoto, while a School of Ethnic Studies was created at San Francisco State due to many days of protest, I would not be surprised if students have to continue to fight a dreary and long-drawn fight. I think it is hard for students to have to fight for greater awareness at Hunter College because it always seems like there is a barrier between the many offices of Hunter College, the administration, and the attitude to students. It is particularly hard to students who want to break the status quo to be heard or even be recognized as a group because the CUNY system in itself is a system that was segregated with no real glue in terms of student action and collective action.</p>
<p>The administration seems to not want to be involved in movements led by Asian American students but perhaps this is due to the way the CUNY system is set up. There are no real dorms for the entire student population or general housing, and so it is particularly hard for students to really gain a sense of community and fight for a common cause.</p>
<p>Discussion Questions:</p>
<p>How can we promote a greater understanding of the Asian American Studies Program and how is it fought for in other colleges around the state?</p>
<p>How can we rally more funding for the Asian American Studies Program and how is it done in other colleges around the state?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">595</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher- Civil Rights and Militant Radicalism</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism-2/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/09/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 17:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akash Sharma]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=583</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Uploaded: The Asians American Movement Here&#8217;s a video from YouTube and is a trailer of a recently released film called, &#8216;Uploaded: The Asian American Movement&#8217;. What this film foucses is on stererotypes relating to Asian Americans and how these stereotypes are reflected in the media. Also, the film talks about YouTube being a &#8220;space&#8221; of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_D_1KuubkFs">Uploaded: The Asians American Movement</a></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a video from YouTube and is a trailer of a recently released film called, &#8216;Uploaded: The Asian American Movement&#8217;. What this film foucses is on stererotypes relating to Asian Americans and how these stereotypes are reflected in the media. Also, the film talks about YouTube being a &#8220;space&#8221; of refuge where anybody can raise their voice and protest as the actors are doing in the film.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/09/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">583</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#124; Civil Rights and Militant Radicalism</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 02:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=564</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.asianfortunenews.com/2013/07/race-talk-asian-american-as-a-political-identity-blog/ In this brief article, a half-Japanese American college student reflects on what being Asian American is. In particular, she speaks about the model minority myth and the expectations others have on her in school. She states that she would be labeled with &#8220;foreign-ness and high grades.&#8221; Therefore, the model minority myth has continues to exist [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.asianfortunenews.com/2013/07/race-talk-asian-american-as-a-political-identity-blog/">http://www.asianfortunenews.com/2013/07/race-talk-asian-american-as-a-political-identity-blog/</a></p>
<p>In this brief article, a half-Japanese American college student reflects on what being Asian American is. In particular, she speaks about the model minority myth and the expectations others have on her in school. She states that she would be labeled with &#8220;foreign-ness and high grades.&#8221; Therefore, the model minority myth has continues to exist in the current generation. To add on to the stereotype of Asian-Americans being foreign, the writer says she felt isolated from the customs of her grade-school mates because she would be enjoying a brown rice ball among a lunch table of peanut butter and jelly sandwiches. Somehow she felt different in the sense of identity because for her, she was the one who had to conceal what she was &#8211; she says she ate her brown rice ball as quickly as possible so no one would notice it&#8217;s <em>uncleanliness </em>or <em>odor</em>. For this reason, I see that the writer notices these myths/stereotypes but does not see them as an obstacle but more of a step towards understanding and empowerment. Furthermore, the writer speaks about the role Asian Americans have in the political system. She writes that Asian-Americans are seen as &#8221; apolitical and, as a consequence, suffers from not having much of a say in changing or adopting new laws that are beneficial to its members&#8221; to show that political involvement is crucial in creating visibility within society. Additionally, the writer includes that because of immigration laws and such, several Asian-American communities are in fear of deportation etc., so there is this conflict where there is a need to be visible but if they are perhaps <em>too </em>visible, they could be arrested or something similar.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9tqpEF9-_lw">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9tqpEF9-_lw</a></p>
<p>In this music video, the newer generation of Asian-Americans rap about the histories and impact of inequality on Asians in the U.S. I think this song reflects on the disconnect between the current generation and their ancestors. For example, the title of the song is &#8220;Where&#8217;d you go?&#8221; which probably means that some of the newer generation are unaware of what their grandparents, for example, had to endure in order to provide for their families, especially with the high amount of inequality and lack of many civil rights. Furthermore, the newer generation have this disconnect with the older generation because they are not confronted with the same lack of equality in society and politics.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">564</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher: Transnational Labor and Capital</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-transnational-labor-and-capital/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-transnational-labor-and-capital/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 17:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=561</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Rachel Salazar Parrenas &#8220;Migrant Filipina Domestic Workers and the International Division of Reproductive Labor,&#8221; she writes &#8220;the hierarchy of womanhood &#8211; based on race, class, and nation &#8211; establishes a work transfer system of reproductive labor among women &#8211; the international transfer of caretaking.&#8221; I looked up reproductive labor as child-rearing and house keeping duties [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Rachel Salazar Parrenas &#8220;Migrant Filipina Domestic Workers and the International Division of Reproductive Labor,&#8221; she writes &#8220;the hierarchy of womanhood &#8211; based on race, class, and nation &#8211; establishes a work transfer system of reproductive labor among women &#8211; the international transfer of caretaking.&#8221; I looked up reproductive labor as child-rearing and house keeping duties and I realized that it was indeed the stereotype of Latin American women to take on the roles of maids or janitorial duties. Even though this stereotype may not be entirely accurate, I think that it is unfortunate that this labor is also hard but often not credited with a full set of employment rights. In addition, I recently saw a trailer for this show about housekeeping maids that were all of Hispanic ethnicity: <a href="http://www.mylifetime.com/shows/devious-maids">http://www.mylifetime.com/shows/devious-maids</a>.</p>
<p>I think the point of a lot of entertainment is to make fun of stereotypes and this is a perfect way to depict some of the stereotypes in society that has had lasting impressions. Even if the stereotype is not true, it is a depiction of what we see and think in modern society.</p>
<p>In Junaid Rana&#8217;s &#8220;Labor Diaspora and the Global Racial System,&#8221; she talks about &#8220;the consolidation of the South Asian labor diaspora in the global racial system that began during the period of colonial indenture continues into the contemporary period via an economic and political strategy of neoliberalism now practiced across the planet.&#8221; Rana critiques neoliberalism and argues that the idea of free trade only benefits an imperialistic power like the United States instead of giving everyone equal opportunity. She critiques that it is only people at the top that get to benefit from neoliberalism or &#8220;free trade&#8221; practices. This article talks about the recent alliance to empower South Asian immigrants in terms of fulfilling goals they have when in comes to work: <a href="http://www.dc37.net/news/PEP/2_2012/south_asian_power.html">http://www.dc37.net/news/PEP/2_2012/south_asian_power.html</a>.</p>
<p>I think that it is a good article because it shows how immigrants are increasingly rallying for support just as we saw the Vietnamese in the New Orleans documentary. Though the Vietnamese were fighting for a political awareness in terms of community, the South Asian immigrants are fighting for employment benefits. In either case, both sought greater visibility and presence in either the communities they were in or in the country they were in. Rana mostly critiques the imperialism of the country but the documentary reminds us to start of small is still a staring place, within their community.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-transnational-labor-and-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">561</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
