<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Primary Reader &#124; Racial Formation, the State, Capital</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/2013/06/08/primary-reader-racial-formation-the-state-capital/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210/2013/06/08/primary-reader-racial-formation-the-state-capital/</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: Christie Ng</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/08/primary-reader-racial-formation-the-state-capital/#comment-10</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christie Ng]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 02:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=242#comment-10</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Concerning Omi and Co.&#039;s writing, I was surprised to learn exactly how much thought is put on race in politics. The Phipps&#039; case is surprising since the decision was handed down about 30 years ago from an obscure law that had never been contested before. It seems time has yet to change many ways of thinking.
For Molina&#039;s work, her structure of writing was easy to follow as she demonstrated the amount of prejudice 3 ethnic groups had to face under the scrutiny of the health department. &quot;American-ness&quot; may have been associated with cleanliness, but people shouldn&#039;t have assumed anyone really wanted to live that way. Bad decisions and unflattering opinions was all that had kept them down.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Concerning Omi and Co.&#8217;s writing, I was surprised to learn exactly how much thought is put on race in politics. The Phipps&#8217; case is surprising since the decision was handed down about 30 years ago from an obscure law that had never been contested before. It seems time has yet to change many ways of thinking.<br />
For Molina&#8217;s work, her structure of writing was easy to follow as she demonstrated the amount of prejudice 3 ethnic groups had to face under the scrutiny of the health department. &#8220;American-ness&#8221; may have been associated with cleanliness, but people shouldn&#8217;t have assumed anyone really wanted to live that way. Bad decisions and unflattering opinions was all that had kept them down.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ryan McNeil</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/08/primary-reader-racial-formation-the-state-capital/#comment-8</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 04:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=242#comment-8</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I agree along with Atitaya that race is &quot;an element of social structure rather than an irregularity within it,&quot;  I feel that Molina&#039;s article handled the treatment of race in the US without discriminating enough between race and culture, as did Americans at the time she writes about.  I think it&#039;s worth pointing out that the quote used from Charles Murray ties in with Tomas Almageur&#039;s point (from Molina&#039;s article) that groups were racialized in relation to one another and the concept of intersectionality.  So, the underlying conflict for immigrants like those in Los Angeles was between their home culture and American culture, but their American-ness was similarly diminished due to the frailty in human nature that lead to their being grouped by race--a convenient but unfair and unreliable heuristic.  

The latter half of this post points out what I believe to be the result of this kind of racialization, the mistreatment of certain peoples because of the belief that they are intrinsically inferior.

The dramatic decrease of the Chinese population in the county coincides with an even larger increase in the Chinese population in the city, this could have something to do with that shift taking place between 1930 and 1940, a time of frequent migration within the United States as people searched for jobs in the midst of the Great Depression.

Historically immigrants to America have been pushed by mainstream American culture to Assimilate, but usually ultimately integrate.  Immigrants conform in some ways and in others retain their culture and instead change American culture.  While I might be biased to say so as a New Yorker, in my opinion the give-and-take of integration is superior to purging immigrants&#039; native culture and keeping American culture steady and sterile.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I agree along with Atitaya that race is &#8220;an element of social structure rather than an irregularity within it,&#8221;  I feel that Molina&#8217;s article handled the treatment of race in the US without discriminating enough between race and culture, as did Americans at the time she writes about.  I think it&#8217;s worth pointing out that the quote used from Charles Murray ties in with Tomas Almageur&#8217;s point (from Molina&#8217;s article) that groups were racialized in relation to one another and the concept of intersectionality.  So, the underlying conflict for immigrants like those in Los Angeles was between their home culture and American culture, but their American-ness was similarly diminished due to the frailty in human nature that lead to their being grouped by race&#8211;a convenient but unfair and unreliable heuristic.  </p>
<p>The latter half of this post points out what I believe to be the result of this kind of racialization, the mistreatment of certain peoples because of the belief that they are intrinsically inferior.</p>
<p>The dramatic decrease of the Chinese population in the county coincides with an even larger increase in the Chinese population in the city, this could have something to do with that shift taking place between 1930 and 1940, a time of frequent migration within the United States as people searched for jobs in the midst of the Great Depression.</p>
<p>Historically immigrants to America have been pushed by mainstream American culture to Assimilate, but usually ultimately integrate.  Immigrants conform in some ways and in others retain their culture and instead change American culture.  While I might be biased to say so as a New Yorker, in my opinion the give-and-take of integration is superior to purging immigrants&#8217; native culture and keeping American culture steady and sterile.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
