<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"

  >
<channel>
  <title>Comments on: Migrant Filipina Domestic Workers and the International  Divisioin of Reproductive labor</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/2013/07/03/migrant-filipina-domestic-workers-and-the-international-divisioin-of-reproductive-labor/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210/2013/07/03/migrant-filipina-domestic-workers-and-the-international-divisioin-of-reproductive-labor/</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

  <item>
    <title>By: Kevin Han</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/03/migrant-filipina-domestic-workers-and-the-international-divisioin-of-reproductive-labor/#comment-40</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Han]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 03:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=551#comment-40</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Like Mallika has said, there are lots of immigrant worker in NYC and Filipino people are not the only ones who provide for their families. There are many people from many different countries provide for their families by doing reproductive labor in the US just as the Filipino women that Parrenas mentioned on her article. On the contrary, there are &quot;Goose Fathers&quot; in Korea, who work in Korea while his wife and children stay in a foreign country which is the opposite case of the Filipino family. However, the goose father feel the same emotional complication as the Filipino family because of the same reason and different places.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like Mallika has said, there are lots of immigrant worker in NYC and Filipino people are not the only ones who provide for their families. There are many people from many different countries provide for their families by doing reproductive labor in the US just as the Filipino women that Parrenas mentioned on her article. On the contrary, there are &#8220;Goose Fathers&#8221; in Korea, who work in Korea while his wife and children stay in a foreign country which is the opposite case of the Filipino family. However, the goose father feel the same emotional complication as the Filipino family because of the same reason and different places.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>By: Atitaya</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/03/migrant-filipina-domestic-workers-and-the-international-divisioin-of-reproductive-labor/#comment-35</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 02:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=551#comment-35</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I agree with what Mallika has said, especially about the extreme gap between gender equality. The role of economy is clearly very important for the Filipino families, and therefore, it was necessary for the women to find sustainable employment to provide for the well-being of the family. To add on to what Mallika wrote, the contradiction the Filipino workers encounter often leads to emotional complication because of the lack of their actual family. But as the reading says, the Filipino women use the family they take of as a way of finding comfort and need. But I think the author prompts the difficult situation of whether family/relaxing time or finances matter more because it really does make it hard for the workers to give up their life in the Philippines in order to work strenuously in another country. Also as stated, the Filipino women are challenged by gender, class, and racial issues that, in my opinion, make them persevere more because they know it is worth it because it will provide for their families.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I agree with what Mallika has said, especially about the extreme gap between gender equality. The role of economy is clearly very important for the Filipino families, and therefore, it was necessary for the women to find sustainable employment to provide for the well-being of the family. To add on to what Mallika wrote, the contradiction the Filipino workers encounter often leads to emotional complication because of the lack of their actual family. But as the reading says, the Filipino women use the family they take of as a way of finding comfort and need. But I think the author prompts the difficult situation of whether family/relaxing time or finances matter more because it really does make it hard for the workers to give up their life in the Philippines in order to work strenuously in another country. Also as stated, the Filipino women are challenged by gender, class, and racial issues that, in my opinion, make them persevere more because they know it is worth it because it will provide for their families.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
