<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Primary Reader &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
	<atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/category/primary-reader/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>	<item>
		<title>Primary Reader on June 26th</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 04:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=660</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Asian American Displacements” by Wanni Anderson and Robert Lee focus on a few frame works including what Asian Americanists study about, the relationship between Asian settlement and the patterns of American history and society, Asian immigrant workers’ role in shaping both the land and social terrain, the connection between American imperialism and the trajectories of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Asian American Displacements” by Wanni Anderson and Robert Lee focus on a few frame works including what Asian Americanists study about, the relationship between Asian settlement and the patterns of American history and society, Asian immigrant workers’ role in shaping both the land and social terrain, the connection between American imperialism and the trajectories of class, race and gender in the U.S. What I found interesting is their idea of four forms of displacement which is including the refugee, the exile, the expatriate, and the migrant.  These four forms have to deal with physical, cultural, psychological, and the intellectual displacement.  The structure of this piece is interesting because it contains a collection of scholar’s references to support their central idea.</p>
<p>In the other piece “Deporting Cambodian Refugees: Youth Activism, State Reform, and Imperial Statecraft” by Soo Ah Kwon is a case study and it includes author’s experience with the AYPAL youth and their campaign to put an end to deportations.  First she chronicles young people’s direct engagement with the state and the political process, and second, “I critically examine how, in confronting the limits of their relationship to the state, AYPAL youth uncovered that the neoliberal state is an imperial state” (Kwon 739).  I think Kwon’s piece is so different from the other pieces we have read because it actually based on author’s own experience in a case study.  Her topic of deportation of Asians got caught my attention because I did not know how these South Asians are living unfairly before I read her article.  She includes documentations in her piece.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">660</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>July 1 – The War on Terror Primary Reader</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader-2/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 16:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle Folvar]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=654</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The three texts read for the class discussion this week were based on the South Asian population, also often referred to as the Near East or Middle East in scholarly text, and their racial formation in the United States post 9/11. We have one piece by Sunaina Maira that is written about the Muslim youth [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The three texts read for the class discussion this week were based on the South Asian population, also often referred to as the Near East or Middle East in scholarly text, and their racial formation in the United States post 9/11. We have one piece by Sunaina Maira that is written about the Muslim youth of America in a narrative and interviewed format, an article by Nadine Naber written with heavy historical and referential context, and finally a piece by Junaid Rana concerning the moral panic and Muslim peril that engulfed the U.S. Post 9/11. All three articles juxtapose the ideas that after the attacked on the United States by terrorists on September 11<sup>th</sup>, a particular rise in racism and racial formation of the Asian populations that could be visible labeled as “Muslim terrorists” arose. They also heavily discuss the reason for the development of such practices historically as well as give ample examples of situations of how the State uses it&#8217;s authoritative power to instill fear and methods of control against the target population through news discourses, legal actions (i.e. Patriot Act), and selective exclusion of populations as we&#8217;ve seen repeated through history towards minorities. Even Naber makes such a correlation with the reference to the Japanese during World War II and their internments and prosecutions for similar circumstances and events as suffered by the Muslim people in our current era.</p>
<p>We also have new concepts introduced in these pieces, including the ideas of Flexible/Cultural/Multicultural Citizenship in relation to Muslim youth and their perspective, racial and moral peril that Muslims pose to America through the association of terrorism as a social, psychological and pathological entity of their ethnicity and culture, and the promotion of racial justice under the pretense of circumstance. All of these new ideas together promote the collective rationalization of dehumanizing and stereotyping the Muslim population in order to create a sense of rightness in regards to the wrong that had been dealt to the United States from the events of 9/11. Naber, Rana, and Maira agree that though this is how the nation and American people have developed, it is nonetheless immoral and criminal to behave this way and treat citizens in a manner that violated their basic human rights. Maira citizenship topics reflective of the documentary “Village Called Versailles” mentions of citizenship for Vietnamese Asians in America and their freedoms being diminished or outright ignored. These issues brought up an image of America that is, no matter how technologically advanced and innovative, backwards we can still be in terms of racial mentality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">654</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>June 24 – Pacific Wars Primary Reader</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 16:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle Folvar]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=648</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The two articles assigned for this week discuss in great detail the Asian American as a dichotomy of the Asian American model minority and the Asian American unassimilable immigrant. The model minority is a representation of a good immigrant living in a first world nation. For example, Palumbo-Liu and Lee both reference how this identity [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The two articles assigned for this week discuss in great detail the Asian American as a dichotomy of the Asian American model minority and the Asian American unassimilable immigrant. The model minority is a representation of a good immigrant living in a first world nation. For example, Palumbo-Liu and Lee both reference how this identity was given because the North Eastern Asian population living in the U.S. had these traits: Self reliance, family cohesion, good work ethic and emphasis on higher education, politically silent and emotionally calm. They also demonstrate the opposite side of the coin with the image of the unassimilable Asian as unwanted refugees and political scapegoats which varied depending on the years. We have this dynamic where the authors describe the Asian populations as both beloved and hated.</p>
<p>Many times, Lee describes the Asian in America “a<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif"><span style="font-size: medium">s the model of successful &#8220;ethnic assimilation&#8221; [that] was created in the crisis of racial policy that had surfaced at the highest levels of the federal government” (150) while Palumbo-Liu says “America&#8217;s &#8220;super minority&#8221;: They are smarter and better educated and make more money than everyone else. Now they are vaulting the last obstacles that stand between them and this country&#8217;s corner offices&#8221; (236). Then we have Lee describing their identity historical as “imperative to place all Asian migration, forced or not, under the same processes of assimilation and social subjectivity, despite tremendous historical differences” (235) or face racial discrimination and possible deportation, and Palumbo-Liu similarly “the historical reality of race in America as compelling logic for limiting civil rights into the economic sphere” (150) that developed the perspective with which Asian were often times viewed based on past events.</span></span></p>
<p>The two texts equally used various examples to support their works. Everything from news correspondences and political campaigning to movies and television was utilized. Both Palumbo and Lee referenced films and broke them down in summary with commentary on what scenes and character interactions represented the &#8216;Asian American&#8217; as well as delving into the topics of American perspectives of Asians and Asian Americans during relevant time periods. We had, particularly in Lee&#8217;s writings, the association of not only the Asian American and its duality, but also the mentions of many other fears that his movies examples highlighted. There were correlations the films had with anti-communist believes as well as the prevalence of homophobia and its developing social context. These two pieces were both linked with the ideas of discussing the Asian American image and the integration within the U.S. in the context of socially relevant circumstances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">648</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader 7/10 readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 13:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=602</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Aoyagi Storm&#8217;s article, the CRAASH movement is described in great details and truly exposed the emotions of the students involved in the movement. Prior to this course I had no idea in such action taken to revitalize the AASP program here at Hunter. After reading this article I admire Olivia Lin for speaking out [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Aoyagi Storm&#8217;s article, the CRAASH movement is described in great details and truly exposed the emotions of the students involved in the movement. Prior to this course I had no idea in such action taken to revitalize the AASP program here at Hunter. After reading this article I admire Olivia Lin for speaking out passionately, at the same time representing the rest who felt the same way about gaining justice and more attention for the program. I like how this article transitions, and in the conclusion it brings a Californian student to provide her take and comparison of the AASP program here to the one in CSUN. I like the quote of, &#8220;This is New York City, this is not Middle America, and we are fighting for Asian American studies. We are fighting for the education we were promised.&#8221; As one of the most diverse and popular city in the world, and one of the only CUNY that offers AASP courses, the students have the right to fight for the best of their education especially if they take great interest in the field.</p>
<p>In Karen Umemoto&#8217;s article, &#8220;the San Francisco State College strike was a microcosm of this struggle over cultural hegemony.&#8221;  The main focus of the strike was to redefine education in links to American society. (25). She analyzes the strike in four stages; from 1964 to Summer of 1969.  She also talks about the concept of &#8220;internal colonialism&#8221; which &#8220;became popular to depict the oppressed status of minorities in America. (30). Also self determination was stressed to be an important term. For PACE members, the term helped people to understand what they were trying to express. The Asian American Political Alliance saw the importance to build alliances based on race and common oppression, and &#8220;political organization should not only effect change but build new non-hierarchical social relationships.&#8221; (36- 37). However they were only to create ideas to effect social, economical and political changes. In Third World Liberation Front, &#8220;the demands of the coalition set a foundation for unity and defined the political issues and struggles which occurred through the course of the strike.&#8221;  (38).  In their goals, the themes of freedom and self- determination are evident. The TWLF people saw self-determination to give &#8220;each nationality the right to determine its own curriculum and hire its own faculty&#8221; for ethnic studies courses. (40). I found it interesting when they said their students found those who lived the ethnic experiences could best teach about it.</p>
<p>In Yamashita&#8217;s I-hotel, which is a 600 pages novel and we were assigned about 76 pages of it, I found the style to be very interesting. It is almost written in a play form sometimes, or overview for an actor or director&#8217;s scripts. I found it interesting when some of the names mentioned were hidden in black highlight, and the voice over&#8217;s job to provide us the settings. On page 136, I found the policeman 1 very violent to punch the student in the stomach with his club and ignorant with the policeman 2 when they thought all the students looked alike because they &#8220;all got black hair and brown eyes&#8221;, while they continued to beat the student up. Then they booked the student for assaulting them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader #03</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-03/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-03/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 03:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Han]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=594</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Spaces of Mobilization&#8221; is the article about the struggle for social justice in the US by Asian and Pacific Islands. There are several cases about the struggle by them according to the article such as feminists, queers, and labor movement. Aguirre and Lio, the authors, provide readers those struggle for showing Asian and Pacific Islanders&#8217; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Spaces of Mobilization&#8221; is the article about the struggle for social justice in the US by Asian and Pacific Islands. There are several cases about the struggle by them according to the article such as feminists, queers, and labor movement. Aguirre and Lio, the authors, provide readers those struggle for showing Asian and Pacific Islanders&#8217; resistance for social justice and moreover fight against racism, hate crimes, and affirmative action. There are not much of their ideas for the issues but just providing the facts and cases. The authors say that the issues they provide will contribute the literature on  Asian and Pacific Islanders so that this article is more like an informatic article.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Four Prisons and The Movements of Liberation&#8221; is the article about the history of  the Asian American activists. The author, Omatsu, explains their activism in chronological order from 1960s to 1990s. According to the article, many Asian American activists were the parts of the US history and related to political powers like neo-conservatives or Marxists.  I had no idea that Asian Americans were being part of the US history and political powers a long time ago.</p>
<p>&#8220;Kung Fusion&#8221; is the article about Bruce Lee and his cultural influence among the world and in the history. The author says that Bruce&#8217;s movie being intellectual resources for Communism and Marxism and his movies were like a symbol of the hero fights to the US imperialism and struggle against racial discrimination even in the third world. I didn&#8217;t realized that the Bruce Lee movies were treated like anti-Americanism stuff in the past.I never heard that Bruce Lee intended to make an anti-Americanism movie or he was a anti-american person.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-03/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">594</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#124; Asian American Studies</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 16:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=581</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The general messages and meaning I understood from the reading were that Asian American, or ethnic studies, are relatively recent and that there is a continuous struggle to be seen and heard and because of this struggle, AsAm studies are not given enough funding, permanency, and voice. For example, on the CRAASH article, the students [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The general messages and meaning I understood from the reading were that Asian American, or ethnic studies, are relatively recent and that there is a continuous struggle to be seen and heard and because of this struggle, AsAm studies are not given enough funding, permanency, and voice. For example, on the <em>CRAASH</em> article, the students wanted to organize an AsAm program at Hunter College but the lack of funding prevented it from getting its resources and needed attention. Also the writer states that because the program was so horrible before, there was very little student interest and since not many students cared, the program worsened. Then in <em>I Spy Hotel, </em>Mr. Takabayashi goes and begins the class about the AsAm experience which is like an ethnic course but what seems to be like a reoccuring theme is the banning and closing down of his position in the university. In Unemoto&#8217;s piece, I see the ideas of empowerment and activism because the student leaders are striking for education that includes easily accessible material for minorites, in addition to their role in politics and how aware they are of their role.</p>
<p> I don&#8217;t think the Smith reading really related to AsAm studies but I saw it as a way to highlight how &#8220;people of color&#8221;/&#8221;women of color&#8221; are framed from a shared oppression by white supremacy. Even though they all seem to have this &#8220;shared victimhood&#8221; they <em>still</em> victimize each other. I thought it was interesting how Smith included the idea of the heteropatriarchal society and the threats against it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>7/8 Primary Reader</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 06:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=573</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the three readings we have to do before class, they are focused on the civil rights movements toward Asians in American and how they tried to achieve their goal and gained their rights along with the movements.  In Aguirre’s piece “Spaces of Mobilization: The Asian American/Pacific Islander Struggle for Social Justice” started with a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the three readings we have to do before class, they are focused on the civil rights movements toward Asians in American and how they tried to achieve their goal and gained their rights along with the movements.  In Aguirre’s piece “Spaces of Mobilization: The Asian American/Pacific Islander Struggle for Social Justice” started with a brief summary of what Asians American went through, like how the society changed their attitudes and point of view toward them changed over time and incidents.  The frame work of this piece is “Space of Mobilization” and the definition is “Space constitutes and structures the processes that produce race, class, and gender identities”.  This piece mainly focuses on how Asians Americans tried to expand their “space” with movements.  In the other article “The ‘Four Prisons’ and the Movements of Liberation” by Glenn Omatsu stated that Asian American movement coincided not with Martin Luther King Jr’s initial campaign for civil rights but with Malcom X’s black liberation.  .Omatsu discussed how Asian American identity changed from the inspiration of activists from 1960s to 1990s.  Prashad’s “Kung Fusion – Organize the ‘Hood Under I-Ching Banners’” is different compares to Omatsu and Aguirre’s piece because Prashad talks about Bruce Lee as an Chinese American to bring out the theme of “orientalism”. “Imperalism”, “Liberation”, etc…Bruce Lee was born in the U.S. but raised in Hong Kong and starred in over twenty movies before he went back to the U.S. for college.  He refused to be an idol for Caucasians because of his strong identity of &#8220;yellow-faced Chinese&#8221;.   But what make these three pieces together is these authors tried to tell us the readers how Asian American movements were under the influence of Marxism, &#8220;Black Maoism&#8221;, and Malcolm X’s black liberation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Migrant Filipina Domestic Workers and the International  Divisioin of Reproductive labor</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/03/migrant-filipina-domestic-workers-and-the-international-divisioin-of-reproductive-labor/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/03/migrant-filipina-domestic-workers-and-the-international-divisioin-of-reproductive-labor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 13:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mallika Basnet]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=551</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This article by Parrenas  Rhacel Salazar didn&#8217;t  come as surprise to me after living in NYC. We see lots of immigrant worker here who have to struggle and their life style has changed tremendously over time. Salazar is maily focusing on the examination of reproductive labor in the process of globalization. In order to clarify [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This article by Parrenas  Rhacel Salazar didn&#8217;t  come as surprise to me after living in NYC. We see lots of immigrant worker here who have to struggle and their life style has changed tremendously over time. Salazar is maily focusing on the examination of reproductive labor in the process of globalization. In order to clarify her statement she uses the ideologies of many scholars and feminist as she is talking mostly about the Filipino women in labor in the globalist society. She also talks about class and inequality and how economy play a major role in the life of these women. It is sad how the women&#8217;s work ethic, love and dedication for her family is not praised in their highly patriarchal society.</p>
<p>These international reproductive Filipino worker go through various contradiction. They feel disconnected and lonely for not being able to spend more time with their own family and having to be taking care of others children. Though life is easier in Philippines there is no money and they have to live a hard working life in order to make more money and make a better living for her family.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/03/migrant-filipina-domestic-workers-and-the-international-divisioin-of-reproductive-labor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">551</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader: Transnational Labor &#038; Capital</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/03/primary-reader-transnational-labor-capital/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/03/primary-reader-transnational-labor-capital/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 05:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Trevor O'Mara]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=539</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s readings deal with transnational laborers and relevant qualities of the world and its globalized economy that have facilitated their being so. The piece on the migrant Filipinas could hardly have painted a bleaker picture. My fellow primary reader below was able to find a &#8220;silver lining&#8221; in the piece. I found none: this is [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s readings deal with transnational laborers and relevant qualities of the world and its globalized economy that have facilitated their being so.</p>
<p>The piece on the migrant Filipinas could hardly have painted a bleaker picture. My fellow primary reader below was able to find a &#8220;silver lining&#8221; in the piece. I found none: this is horrible and it made me cry. The part that most fed my despondency was where the &#8220;middle-tier&#8221; migrant worker relished the thought of essentially exploiting the poorer women back home, just as she had been, and that that was what she was struggling for. What a damning indictment of the world order this is &#8212; heart breaking stuff.</p>
<p>But there&#8217;s still more misery to discuss. Among the repercussions of this way things are, families are torn apart: mothers half a world away from their children &#8212; all causing untold emotional damage. It is so in the other piece as well about the Pakistani male migrant workers. There the men are torn away from their families. So, this globalization is tearing people apart &#8212; from themselves, their families, their home &#8212; the world over, causing massive social distortion. It&#8217;s pretty messy stuff.</p>
<p>The Junaid piece is much more of a historical expose&#8217;, detailing how colonial practices are still informing the present, providing some nifty historical context. And there is much contemporary context, too. He talks about how the Pakistani government suppresses labor unions, which contributes to this male working class being in constant flux. The motives and context of the Pakistani government&#8217;s actions is something I&#8217;d like to know more about. There are many more sordid details of which to speak, of course; we&#8217;ll get to them in class.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/03/primary-reader-transnational-labor-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">539</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader 7/3</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/02/primary-reader-73/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/02/primary-reader-73/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 03:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=532</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Parrenas article discusses female Filipino-American immigrants in domestic labor (as the name implies) and examines their place in American society based mostly on interviews that the Author had with female Filipino domestic workers.  The paper spends a bit examining their common place in domestic labor, and how their handling of reproductive labor for richer [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Parrenas article discusses female Filipino-American immigrants in domestic labor (as the name implies) and examines their place in American society based mostly on interviews that the Author had with female Filipino domestic workers.  The paper spends a bit examining their common place in domestic labor, and how their handling of reproductive labor for richer families (specifically for richer mothers) has been under-credited by society.  She mentions that this issue has had a long history in America and in doing so brings up an interesting point that when reproductive labor is performed by a mother, the labor is seen as noble, proper and respectable, while when the same work is done by these immigrant workers, it is simply &#8220;unskilled labor;&#8221; a lowly job.  The Author also states that &#8220;globalization has sparked the feminization of migrant labor.&#8221;  That is to say that the global industrial system has called for plenty of labor from female immigrants and females in their home countries, though it&#8217;s worth mentioning that this has kept them from escaping strenuous low-paying jobs in many places and has allowed the devaluing of reproductive labor in society.  The silver lining to this decrease in social standing in America is an increase of social and material status in their home country (The Philippines).</p>
<p>In &#8220;So Our History Doesn&#8217;t Become Your Future,&#8221; Naber discusses changes in American public policy following 9/11.  She states her opinion that despite fears or reservations, US foreign policy is progressing and cultural unity is growing.  I found this to be a refreshing perspective given all the pessimism that naturally comes along with investigating the inequalities in society to begin with.  She did mention that post-9/11 US policy did see an increase in the government&#8217;s (specifically the executive branch) ability to label an entire group as a threat to national security, a label that those of us living here now can vouch is easily recognizable in American society.  She  also makes reference to the post 9/11 world order, linked to the idea that the US essentially controlled global politics after 9/11 and attempted to make its interest the ways of the world as in Israel-Palestine conflict.  After reading this article, I&#8217;d pose the simple question of where the author may see the US in 10 and 50 years given these shifts in policy, and I&#8217;m curious to see how our actions effect our global standing in the very long run.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/02/primary-reader-73/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">532</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
