<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
  >

<channel>
  <title>Lisa Lowe &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/tag/lisa-lowe/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <language>en-US</language>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>  <item>
    <title>Primary Reader &#8211; Empire, Globalization, Diasporas, and Transnationalism</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/26/primary-reader-empire-globalization-diasporas-and-transnationalism/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/26/primary-reader-empire-globalization-diasporas-and-transnationalism/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 04:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Diaspora]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Empire]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Globalization]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Lisa Lowe]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Robert G Lee]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Transnationalism]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Wanni Anderson]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=570</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In Lisa Lowe’s “Heterogeneity, Hybridity, and Multiciplicy: Asian American Differences,” she talks about the problems that come with the idea of a homogeneous Asian American population. Instead of looking at Asian American populations as homogeneous, she wants to talk about the heterogeneity and hybridity of the population. In addition she wants to make it a [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">In Lisa Lowe’s “Heterogeneity, Hybridity, and Multiciplicy: Asian American Differences,” she talks about the problems that come with the idea of a homogeneous Asian American population. Instead of looking at Asian American populations as homogeneous, she wants to talk about the heterogeneity and hybridity of the population. In addition she wants to make it a point that Asian Americans should be viewed with multiplicity, or in different lights. She writes, describing Asian American homogeneity, “The articulation of an ‘Asian American identity’ as an organizing tool has provided a concept of political unity to understand unequal circumstances and histories as being related” (71). I think she is acknowledging that the unity of only one” Asian American identity” has perhaps have had some political benefits but goes on to critique this standpoint as wrong because it “implies Asians are ‘all alike’ and conform to ‘types’” (71). In addition, she writes “Rather, the assertion of ‘integral autonomy’ by ‘not unified’ classes suggests a coordination of distinct, yet allied, positions, practices, and movements – class-identified and not class-identified, in parties and not, race-based and gender-based – each on its own, not necessarily equivalent manner transforming, disrupting, and destructuring the apparatuses of a specific hegemony” (70). In other words, a one unified view of Asian Americans is erroneous because it ignores many of the differences between Asian Americans as well as reinforces the idea that there is one, specific, dominant hegemon, or in this case the White population.</span></p>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">In Anderson, Wanni W. and Robert G. Lee’s “Asian American Displacements,” they write about four types of displacement. They write “at beginning of the twenty-first century, we identify four existing forms of displacement as the lived experienced of the immigrant, the refugee, the exile, the expatriate, and the migrant: physical/spatial displacement, cultural displacement, psychological/affective displacement, and intellectual displacement” (11). I think of physical/spatial as the first type of displacement but with time, this type of displacement can lead to “cultural,” “psychological,” and “intellectual” displacement. I think that the latter of the three types of displacement are the most straining and the most offensive to new immigrants who are struggling to conform to new cultures, new ideas, and new ambiances. The term hypochondria comes to mind when I think of people who have trouble fitting in to the present place they are in because they are suffering from being away from home, from adjusting to the new time as voiced in many Asian American texts. In the end, they conclude “they (volumes) lead us through the Asian experience in the Americas across space and time and provide us a conceptual map with which we can engage the changing economic, cultural, and political landscapes” (17). The writers end on a hopeful path as they acknowledged earlier in the text that Asian American studies were conceived in the 1970’s after being empowered by the Civil Rights Movement in the 1960’s to fight the oppression that inhibited a racially divided America.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">Discussion Questions</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">1) Is Lisa Lowe’s writing accurate of what is happening in today’s United Stated States? If so, what can we do to empower Asian Americans to fight for better representation?</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">2) Are Asian Americans being subjected to great “cultural,” “psychological” and “intellectual” strain because they are a minority and because they have been displaced from their home country? What can we do to alleviate some of the pressure?</span></div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/26/primary-reader-empire-globalization-diasporas-and-transnationalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">570</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Primary Reader 6/24</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 02:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Cold War]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Lisa Lowe]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Robert G Lee]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Robert Lee]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=452</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the Robert G. Lee piece, Lee tackles the stereotype that Asians embodied a &#8220;model minority;&#8221; a group that assimilated well and fell in line well with established societal norms.  He spends a good portion of the paper on the history of this stereotype.  In my opinion, it was somewhat surprising to read about the [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the Robert G. Lee piece, Lee tackles the stereotype that Asians embodied a &#8220;model minority;&#8221; a group that assimilated well and fell in line well with established societal norms.  He spends a good portion of the paper on the history of this stereotype.  In my opinion, it was somewhat surprising to read about the excerpt from <i>Life </i>magazine.  Though racism was still so socially acceptable in America at the time, I was a little surprised to see a respected magazine publish such a pseudoscientific piece on racial anthropology as late as 1941.  The main idea I got from this paper was that straight, working-class Asians were seen as an acceptable out-group in relation to other minorities (racial minorities and homosexuals), despite the very negative light cast on Asians in America by the prevalence of communism in a few asian nations.  I believe that the model minority myth must have been incredibly well entrenched in American culture, given that it had to overcome even the extreme anti-communist sentiment central to Cold War America.</p>
<p>The David Palumbo-Liu paper delves more technically into the politics of being Asian in America, and relative stereotypes.  The paper talks about some differences in the treatment of Asian Americans by location (particularly California). It goes on to examine a few films, in my opinion, illustrating popular perception of Asians in the US and the contradictory nature of some Asian stereotypes.  The paper works its way from these perceptions themselves to their implications, like the mistreatment of Asian Americans like that of the banking system.  One interesting point that this paper brings up is that Asians were forced to integrate (page 241), evidencing that the model minority myth was not just created in white Americans&#8217; minds, but in their actions.  For further research, I would be curious how racist perceptions of Asian Americans, and their treatment because of those perceptions may have fed back and forth in a circular fashion. ie. Asians being perceived as unsanitary or unhealthy, thus not being afforded the same health care as white Americans causing them to actually have poorer health than white Americans.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">452</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Researcher for 6/19</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/19/409/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/19/409/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 04:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Citizenship]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Leti Volpp]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Lisa Lowe]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=409</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[http://www.cis.org/1965ImmigrationAct-MassImmigration Like many of the analyses I could find online, the above defends the Immigration Act of 1965, discussed extensively in the Lowe piece.  I thought this one was worth posting because it contains several quotes from American politicians, illustrating the controversy that surrounded the bill.  While the Lowe piece gives the opinion of one [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.cis.org/1965ImmigrationAct-MassImmigration">http://www.cis.org/1965ImmigrationAct-MassImmigration</a><br />
Like many of the analyses I could find online, the above defends the Immigration Act of 1965, discussed extensively in the Lowe piece.  I thought this one was worth posting because it contains several quotes from American politicians, illustrating the controversy that surrounded the bill.  While the Lowe piece gives the opinion of one (very informed) writer, the above link allows us to see how many people within the setting of the bill&#8217;s passing reacted to it, and gives us some statistics to back up Lowe&#8217;s information. It&#8217;s worth pointing out that this bill was considered the result of immigration policy related to the general liberalization of American politics during the 60s.</p>
<p><a href="http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/citizenship/#1.1">http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/citizenship/#1.1</a><br />
The above is a little lengthy, I only mean use section 1.1. I searched around for an interesting definition of citizenship and managed to find one that did so in more than terms of birthplace and naturalization.  This excerpt seemed relevant to the Volpp paper because it offers (to some extent) a scholarly and philosophical answer to the question of citizenship discussed in &#8220;&#8216;Obnoxious To Their Very Nature&#8217;: Asian Americans and Constitutional Citizenship.&#8221; This section is honest about the debate over how to define citizenship,  is straight forward in doing so, and doesn&#8217;t try to offer its own definition as absolute.  The psychological aspect of citizenship mentioned in the section reminds the reader that immigrants are not homogenous in their perceived &#8220;foreignness&#8221; and that citizenship does not necessarily have to involve complete identification with a new culture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/19/409/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">409</post-id> </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
