<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
  >

<channel>
  <title>Edward Said &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/tag/edward-said/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <language>en-US</language>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>  <item>
    <title>Primary Reading, 6/5/13 (Said &#038; Shah)</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 03:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Christie Ng]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=185</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The texts of &#8220;Introduction&#8221; by Edawrd Said and &#8220;Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown&#8221; by Nyan Shah bring forth the volatile relationship seen between the Asian and Western cultures. Both texts present the Western culture as having an overbearing ideology that rejects and steps on anything that it does not support while exaggerating on [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The texts of &#8220;Introduction&#8221; by Edawrd Said and &#8220;Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown&#8221; by Nyan Shah bring forth the volatile relationship seen between the Asian and Western cultures. Both texts present the Western culture as having an overbearing ideology that rejects and steps on anything that it does not support while exaggerating on the desirable aspects. The author Said writes about exotic locations and sexual longings that the European men capitalize on. The Asian culture receives many hard blows for being different and has many slanderous remarks to fight against. Shah mentions the reporters of 19th century San Francisco wrote of Chinese immigrants living in cramped, disease-filled tenements as if it was something the immigrants had wanted to live in.</p>
<p>Edward Said&#8217;s piece is about &#8220;Orientalism&#8221;, which is the Western ideals of European countries defining the aspects that make up the Asian countries. Said paints an image of European men who measure every aspect of the lives of Asians by the yardstick of their own Western ideas. It is irritating to know that other cultures were being measured to the standards of another culture as if it was superior in any way. The only comfort that can come of this realisation is that in the future people do learn to make the effort to see the beliefs of many on their own terms and ways. I would like to question about the section in the text of politics influencing academic knowledge and its writers. Since many researchers would have wanted support for their work from whatever government group had money to bring out, could the words in these studies be fully trusted if there is a possibility of flattery? </p>
<p>Nyan Shah engages the reader with the loud arguements of San Francisco&#8217;s white population protesting against the Chinatowns and the dangers these places could have. Shah points out that &#8220;escalating anti-Chinese politics and the spector of epidemic disease&#8221; (171) had a hand in driving the public to hurt the immigrants living there. The implication of racism in these reasons show how American history keeps repeating itself many times over on who could be trusted. The Irish and African-Americans had been two other groups who faced persecution based on what others thought of their cultures and physical features. The image of being a group of dirty, diseased people is nothing new for all persecuted groups, but how can it end? Would education in all necessary areas be the only defense against the ignorance and hate that continues throughout the ages?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">185</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Primary Reader &#8211; Said and Shah&#8217;s Orientalism and Politics of Knowledge</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 03:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=186</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The readings we have to read before class is the introduction from Orientalism by Edward Said and “Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown” by Nyan Shah.  These two readings shared the ideas of how Asians or Chinese were viewed by the Europeans and White Caucasians during the 19th century.  Medias and literature were being [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The readings we have to read before class is the introduction from <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Orientalism</span> by Edward Said and “Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown” by Nyan Shah.  These two readings shared the ideas of how Asians or Chinese were viewed by the Europeans and White Caucasians during the 19<sup>th</sup> century.  Medias and literature were being used to portray negative image of Asians in the western world, and that created discriminations and against the east side.</p>
<p>Said stated his point of view of how the Europeans declare themselves as orientalism and separated themselves from the East.  They think the West which represents them is more civilized and exotic than the East, and also see the East as a lower class compares to them.  They described the East as orientals because their culture is different from them, which makes the Europeans see them as a cruel, uncivilized, uneducated group of people.  Said also mentioned that the Europeans have the idea to educate this group of uncivilized people (orientals) into a civilized group (orientalisms) like them.  Different countries have different culture and the cultural difference made the Europeans to classify themselves as the higher class just because the east side has a different way of living.  The other point Said mentioned in the introduction is the westerners started to portray Asians as uncivilized group into Medias, literatures, etc… That created a wide spread negative image of the east in the western society.</p>
<p>Shah is trying to tell us the same idea, but the difference between him and Said is he used references to support his idea.  This is including the investigations done by Logan, Anti- Coolie (group against Chinese immigrants in San Francisco) and the acts by government were used against the Chinese immigrants.  During the late 1800, the rapid growth of Chinese immigrants brought the Caucasians’ attention.  White workers started to lose their job because of the Chinese workers and the cholera and smallpox epidemic in San Francisco built discriminations toward the Chinese immigrants.  The Caucasians started to blame Chinese immigrants for making them unemployed and the crowded living spaces in Chinatown created the spread of cholera and smallpox.  Groups like Anti- Coolie were formed to against the Chinese immigrants and wanted to kick them out of the state, investigations on the real side of Chinatown also portrayed negative image of Chinese immigrants to the public.  One of the example is being used by Shah is Logan’s investigation, Shah stated Logan’s ignorance of the good side of Chinatown like the merchant’s homes, drug goods stores, temples, meeting rooms, and Chinese opera theatre.  Logan only focused on gambling house, opium dens, and brothel which brought more attentions from the public on the Chinese immigrants and made the public wanted to explore more negative facts from Chinatown, San Francisco.  This is just like Said’s point of view from the Europeans, because of the cultural differences between the east and west, Chinese/ Asians have an extreme negative image in the Caucasians world during the 19<sup>th</sup> century.  Although there were assumptions on the dirty and crowded environment created by the Chinese immigrants cause harms to others’ health issues, but Shah stated that there were no legal or extralegal action on the Board of Health’s condemnation of Chinatown ever occurred.  The other interesting fact Shah used to support the research is the U.S. congress actually passed the Chinese Exclusion Act in 1882 to disallow the Chinese workers to immigrate, so this will decrease the white workers’ unemployment rate and also a discrimination act made by the congress.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">186</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Researcher#01</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/researcher01/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/researcher01/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 02:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Han]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=172</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[&#160; Claude Monet &#8211; &#8220;La Japonaise&#8221; &#160; Edward Said&#8217;s &#8216;Orientalism&#8217; is the article that explains how the west(Europe, North America) understand the east(Asia) and analyzes the stereotypes about Asian people. According to the article, the west have many stereotypes about the east such as &#8216;All asian people have black hair and slit eyes&#8217;. and those [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/mimg0001.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-173 alignleft" alt="mimg0001" src="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/mimg0001.jpg?resize=610%2C1000" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/mimg0001.jpg?w=610 610w, https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/mimg0001.jpg?resize=183%2C300 183w" sizes="(max-width: 610px) 100vw, 610px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Claude Monet &#8211; &#8220;La Japonaise&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Edward Said&#8217;s &#8216;Orientalism&#8217; is the article that explains how the west(Europe, North America) understand the east(Asia) and analyzes the stereotypes about Asian people.</p>
<p>According to the article, the west have many stereotypes about the east such as &#8216;All asian people have black hair and slit eyes&#8217;.</p>
<p>and those stereotypes sometimes lead to racism toward Asian people or fantasy about Asia like &#8216;Japonesque&#8217; which are arts based on Japanese drawings.</p>
<p>However, those based on the stereotypes are mostly exaggerated and give wrong concepts of Asia.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://arabstereotypes.org/why-stereotypes/what-orientalism">http://arabstereotypes.org/why-stereotypes/what-orientalism</a></p>
<p>the link above goes to the article that defines Orientalism with the Arab stereotypes.</p>
<p>It points out that the west defines the east as different and inferior and shows several examples of Orientalism with the European history.</p>
<p>I chose this article because it explains well about the wrong perception of Arab culture and includes videos about the wrong perception of the Middle East.</p>
<p>In other words, it shows the examples of &#8216;the bad side of Orientalism&#8217;.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.marcmaison.com/architectural-antiques-resources/japonism">http://www.marcmaison.com/architectural-antiques-resources/japonism</a></p>
<p>The link above goes to the article that explains Japonism which is the Japanese cultural influence among the European culture.</p>
<p>On the contrary, This shows &#8216;the good side of Orientalism&#8217; which is more like a fantasy about Asian people and/or culture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/researcher01/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">172</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Researcher (Said and Shah)</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/researcher-said-and-shah/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/researcher-said-and-shah/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 01:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Akash Sharma]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=138</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Edward Said on Orientalism (YouTube Video)]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/xwCOSkXR_Cw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe><br />
Edward Said on Orientalism (YouTube Video)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/researcher-said-and-shah/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">138</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>First Reading &#8211; Shah and Said&#8217;s Asian/Oriental &#8220;Other&#8221;</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/first-reading-shah-and-saids-asianoriental-other/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/first-reading-shah-and-saids-asianoriental-other/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle Folvar]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=171</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The two readings done for today&#8217;s class involve the concepts of “the other” in the eyes of the class-ruling population of Caucasians during the 1800s and modern era. During both time periods, there is a distinct reference to the social and economical events in relation to the concept of “the other”; for the Shah reading, [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The two readings done for today&#8217;s class involve the concepts of “the other” in the eyes of the class-ruling population of Caucasians during the 1800s and modern era. During both time periods, there is a distinct reference to the social and economical events in relation to the concept of “the other”; for the Shah reading, the weight falls on the shoulders of the Chinese community of San Francisco and its Chinatown during the nineteenth century while Said&#8217;s general focus is the Orient itself, collectively bundling the Asian and Eurasian communities into a whole representing foreignness, exoticism, and often times barbarism to the White and European realm.</p>
<p>Shah&#8217;s publication is written as a critical review, taking investigations, textual references (both medical and historic), and other captious materials in creating a world of the past for those of us in the modern day. Though it seems unclear who his exact audience is, the piece is appropriate for those interested in the public health sphere in general, as well as students, social science professionals and researchers intrigued with the issues of Asian communities as a target for racism, political scapegoating and oppression in the nineteenth century. The author chooses to present his arguments in a analytic manner seen in research papers, giving basis around the idea of dirty, diseased and inhuman Chinese immigrants and how they were victimized to direct problems of corruption and economic hardships unto them. We see government and elective roles using and abusing the Chinese population to fund their own ends and to create greater disparity between the average middle class whites and the immigrant lower class Asians, and the author asks us why they were able to get away with such clearly biased and discriminatory behavior during this time period. Comparative to today&#8217;s San Francisco, though I myself have never been there to be sure, it can be assumed that the communities of Asian Americans have been able to evolve passed the repression and disparities that once plagued the areas of Chinatown.</p>
<p>By the same token, we have Said who takes the concept of Orientalism, or the difference of everything cultural and historical from that of the Western world, and molds it into a view of the same foreignness as Shah, but with reference to its almost subsidiary nature in the eyes Westerners through its romanticism and standing as colonial properties to European oppressors. It should be noted that the author states this is not a state of total imposed oppression however because such concepts cannot stand for long periods of time without reinforcement from both institutions of higher learning, government policy and understanding, and a lack of rebuttal or ambivalence from the locations deemed the Orient itself. Said&#8217;s focus is on providing a guide of sorts for the scholar or student interested in the concept of the Orient, or that which is opposite to the Occidental’s perspective, as well as detailing a history and knowledge about what makes the construct of Orientalism real and functioning for the time he is writing about, the past into the late 1980s. He questions of why we have this abstract creation of the Orient to begin with and explains how he as an attempted “individual” tries to view the argument despite carrying political and slanted views that typically color an objective argument. He also poses many questions concerning the dynamic which drives the Orient into a setting of historic, lexicographic, biological, economical and political context, again in reference to the omnipresent Western perspective.  Overall, these two works written are focused on the same idea of otherness to a reader and show inequalities that often times occurred within studies involving the communities of Asian and Asian Americans.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/first-reading-shah-and-saids-asianoriental-other/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">171</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Primary reading response for &#8220;Introduction&#8221; In Orientalism</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-response-for-introduction-in-orientalism/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-response-for-introduction-in-orientalism/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 21:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Mallika Basnet]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=165</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Orientalism a very interesting reading by Edward W said was written in 1978 and published only in 1994 by the vintage. The book seem to have been written during the time of colonization. I believe that Said wrote this for the post colonial studies, European studies or the study of Orientals themselves. This reading by [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Orientalism a very interesting reading by Edward W said was written in 1978 and published only in 1994 by the vintage. The book seem to have been written during the time of colonization. I believe that Said wrote this for the post colonial studies, European studies or the study of Orientals themselves. This reading by Said portrays the ideology of the Orients ( Mostly East Asian and middle Eastern) in the European world mostly French and the British. Said starts by defining the Orient and Orientalism in different context.</p>
<p>Orientals is the name used for the east Asian or the people from the middle east. The people studying the orient is known as the Orientalism in the European context. The European found the orients culture, civilization and nature very exotic and they were very interested in learning the livelihood of this innocent human decent who were far from the advancement and development from the rest of the western world. According to Said the world was divided into East and West based on civilization by the Europeans during this time. Said mostly talks about the Orientalism if the late 19th and the 20th century. This division based on civilization seems mostly imaginary and artificial. European colonization basically started from the least developing counties of the orients. The Westerners ( Europeans) considered themselves more superior and the orientals as the inferior group of people. They also thought that it was somehow their duty to colonize the East and teach them more about the western world. Orientals were considered to be lazy, crude, irrational and uncivilized as they had a simple living. Henceforth, European marked their superiority by colonizing and using their authoritative rule by living with the Orientals. East and the West mostly hold accounts on Social and Political affiliation in relation to costume, culture and lifestyle of the orients. And Said finds it very crucial to use Michel Foucault&#8217;s notion of a discourse, which states &#8220;The Archaeology of Knowledge and in Discipline and Punish&#8221;, to explain in order to identify Orientalism.</p>
<p>The Orientals seemed too be constantly judged based on their culture, religion and way of living by the European . This conceptualization somehow seem has created a false image on the orientals. As we see how the world sees the Muslim as the terrorist till today. This kind of discrimination as the oriental and occident has created biases among human kind throughout history and it continues to prevail.</p>
<p>Said states that European gained power and self image through the orientals. Orient which was vastly ruled and dominated by the British and in the french was ruled by the American after the world war II. The main purpose of this reading is to state that the the Orient world or group was not created by anyone in particular. Orient according to Said based on my understanding is the land with its own geographical boundaries, culture and history which the Western world found amusing to learn and rule on to gain power!!!!</p>
<p>Well let me know if you guys think that i had made a good point on understanding the reading by Said and if you guys agree or disagree on any points that i have made..</p>
<p>Mallika Basnet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-response-for-introduction-in-orientalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">165</post-id> </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
