<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Primary Reader 6/24</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: Kristina Szeto</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/#comment-48</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 04:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=452#comment-48</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think that the idea of Asians being a model minority really affects the way that other minorities - not just Asians - are treated and it&#039;s still relevant today. One example of such is the controversial Stop-and-Frisk program by the NYPD. This procedure involves police officers stopping people they believe are acting suspicious (relating to criminal activity or property). The program is gender and race-neutral, but the implementation of the program appears to have been skewed by racial profiling.

     A majority of the people stopped by police officers are of African-American or Latino descent, with a markedly smaller percentage of white or other minorities being stopped. This plays into the model minority myth by unofficially reinforcing the idea of a &#039;model minority&#039;, particularly Asians. People believe in the model minority myth and as a result Asians aren&#039;t subject to the same racial treatment as other minorities.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think that the idea of Asians being a model minority really affects the way that other minorities &#8211; not just Asians &#8211; are treated and it&#8217;s still relevant today. One example of such is the controversial Stop-and-Frisk program by the NYPD. This procedure involves police officers stopping people they believe are acting suspicious (relating to criminal activity or property). The program is gender and race-neutral, but the implementation of the program appears to have been skewed by racial profiling.</p>
<p>     A majority of the people stopped by police officers are of African-American or Latino descent, with a markedly smaller percentage of white or other minorities being stopped. This plays into the model minority myth by unofficially reinforcing the idea of a &#8216;model minority&#8217;, particularly Asians. People believe in the model minority myth and as a result Asians aren&#8217;t subject to the same racial treatment as other minorities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Akash Sharma</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/#comment-26</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akash Sharma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 02:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=452#comment-26</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I agree with both Ryan and Atitaya and was very much interested and impressed with the article by Robert Lee. Out of the two articles we had to read Lee&#039;s article on the Cold War and the Origins of Model Minority Myth was my favourite. Populations of Asians Americans were initially looked as bad and disease carrying, but they soon became a &#039;model&#039; for the other minority groups residing in the United States. To be a part of the model minority, one has to have certain characteristics as we discussed in past readings and discussions. Asian Americans because of their docile and apolitical nature were quickly added to the category of &quot;assimilated&quot; migrants. 

As I was reading the article and thinking about the read through an historic and anthropological perspective, I had a question on the establishment of  the model minority and the rise of Communism in the Americas. It may be because of this &#039;Red Scare&#039; the State implimented such notions of model minority so that Asian populations could adhere to and pursue their capitalistic or American dreams.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I agree with both Ryan and Atitaya and was very much interested and impressed with the article by Robert Lee. Out of the two articles we had to read Lee&#8217;s article on the Cold War and the Origins of Model Minority Myth was my favourite. Populations of Asians Americans were initially looked as bad and disease carrying, but they soon became a &#8216;model&#8217; for the other minority groups residing in the United States. To be a part of the model minority, one has to have certain characteristics as we discussed in past readings and discussions. Asian Americans because of their docile and apolitical nature were quickly added to the category of &#8220;assimilated&#8221; migrants. </p>
<p>As I was reading the article and thinking about the read through an historic and anthropological perspective, I had a question on the establishment of  the model minority and the rise of Communism in the Americas. It may be because of this &#8216;Red Scare&#8217; the State implimented such notions of model minority so that Asian populations could adhere to and pursue their capitalistic or American dreams.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Atitaya</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/#comment-24</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 23:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=452#comment-24</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I also thought the section about Life magazine was provoking. To add on to what Ryan wrote, the idea of the yellow peril was challenged by the model minority myth but Asian-Americans were still categorized based on sexuality and gender and socio-economic status. It seems that Asian-Americans as well as other minority groups will continue to be labeled as something similar to foreign and within that foreign label, they will be labeled with a certain social class, for example, thus creating something like a minority within the Asian-American minority. 
I agree with what Ryan said about the model minority myth and how it wasn&#039;t just a concept or theory, and that it was carried out. To add on, I think the discussion in class about a claim to space and how rural space was a significant factor for Asian-Americans, especially for economic reasons. I think further research on what Ryan wrote about would be interesting! Particularly because it appears in a lot of readings of minorities because excluded from certain benefits and because of the lack of health or housing they become ill or something and it creates or strengthens stereotypes. It&#039;s not their fault people are excluding them or creating ridiculous stereotypes because of inequality.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I also thought the section about Life magazine was provoking. To add on to what Ryan wrote, the idea of the yellow peril was challenged by the model minority myth but Asian-Americans were still categorized based on sexuality and gender and socio-economic status. It seems that Asian-Americans as well as other minority groups will continue to be labeled as something similar to foreign and within that foreign label, they will be labeled with a certain social class, for example, thus creating something like a minority within the Asian-American minority.<br />
I agree with what Ryan said about the model minority myth and how it wasn&#8217;t just a concept or theory, and that it was carried out. To add on, I think the discussion in class about a claim to space and how rural space was a significant factor for Asian-Americans, especially for economic reasons. I think further research on what Ryan wrote about would be interesting! Particularly because it appears in a lot of readings of minorities because excluded from certain benefits and because of the lack of health or housing they become ill or something and it creates or strengthens stereotypes. It&#8217;s not their fault people are excluding them or creating ridiculous stereotypes because of inequality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
