<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"

  >
<channel>
  <title>Comments on: Primary Reading, 6/5/13 (Said &#038; Shah)</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

  <item>
    <title>By: Trevor O'Mara</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/#comment-4</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Trevor O'Mara]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 04:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=185#comment-4</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[You seem quite angry in your writing -- perhaps rightfully so. Indeed, it seems humans have found some difficulty in coexistence, a difficulty that looks like it will persist through the foreseeable future. There are many factors contributing to hatred, prejudice, xenophobia, and the like, and we should be careful not to conflate them. Education can help to mitigate these things, but obviously it cannot eliminate conflict between people and peoples. There are many problems in the world (duh), and as long as they persist (forever) someone will seek someone else upon whom to cast the blame, whether rightly so or not.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You seem quite angry in your writing &#8212; perhaps rightfully so. Indeed, it seems humans have found some difficulty in coexistence, a difficulty that looks like it will persist through the foreseeable future. There are many factors contributing to hatred, prejudice, xenophobia, and the like, and we should be careful not to conflate them. Education can help to mitigate these things, but obviously it cannot eliminate conflict between people and peoples. There are many problems in the world (duh), and as long as they persist (forever) someone will seek someone else upon whom to cast the blame, whether rightly so or not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
