<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Primary Reader on Lisa Lowe and Leti Volpp</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: Kevin Han</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/#comment-31</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Han]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 02:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=410#comment-31</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think that US is being too rigid in laws and policies about citizenship and immigrants and of course I understand that laws must be followed but US is the country of diversity and I believed that US needs more flexibility in interpretation in racial and cultural boundaries as much as its diversity of people. 

Also, I think that citizenship is not a tool for politics. It is more like having rights and freedom and being eligible to participate politics without compulsion.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think that US is being too rigid in laws and policies about citizenship and immigrants and of course I understand that laws must be followed but US is the country of diversity and I believed that US needs more flexibility in interpretation in racial and cultural boundaries as much as its diversity of people. </p>
<p>Also, I think that citizenship is not a tool for politics. It is more like having rights and freedom and being eligible to participate politics without compulsion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ryan McNeil</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/#comment-28</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 07:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=410#comment-28</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[continued] I also understand how the construction of a Vietnam War memorial designed by an Asian American could raise unease (which is not to say that I agree with that unease, but that I understand that some people would think that way), and I think that that unease exposes a lot about the nature of racism--that a conflict with a single nation in Asia could translate into racism against all Asians shows how thoughtless yet impactful it can really be.
In the second paragraph I realized an interesting conundrum. If true citizenship is considered to include being active in politics, then while Asian Americans were held above other minorities to some degree by the model minority myth, they would have to choose to defy the myth by not being politically quiet if they want to be true citizens.  So in a sense, Asian Americans would have to choose between being unaccepted in one way or another.  Lastly, I&#039;d be interested to read more about the shift from Yellow Peril to Model Minority that is mentioned at the end of the original post, and how the fluid shift could have resulted in a mixing of the two.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[continued] I also understand how the construction of a Vietnam War memorial designed by an Asian American could raise unease (which is not to say that I agree with that unease, but that I understand that some people would think that way), and I think that that unease exposes a lot about the nature of racism&#8211;that a conflict with a single nation in Asia could translate into racism against all Asians shows how thoughtless yet impactful it can really be.<br />
In the second paragraph I realized an interesting conundrum. If true citizenship is considered to include being active in politics, then while Asian Americans were held above other minorities to some degree by the model minority myth, they would have to choose to defy the myth by not being politically quiet if they want to be true citizens.  So in a sense, Asian Americans would have to choose between being unaccepted in one way or another.  Lastly, I&#8217;d be interested to read more about the shift from Yellow Peril to Model Minority that is mentioned at the end of the original post, and how the fluid shift could have resulted in a mixing of the two.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ryan McNeil</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/#comment-27</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 06:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=410#comment-27</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I enjoyed reading this particular Primary Reader because it brought up a few points that I overlooked in reading the two papers.  I&#039;m curious how feminism may have influenced the issue of marrying into or out of citizenship by gender over the years.  I also understand]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I enjoyed reading this particular Primary Reader because it brought up a few points that I overlooked in reading the two papers.  I&#8217;m curious how feminism may have influenced the issue of marrying into or out of citizenship by gender over the years.  I also understand</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Gloria Cho</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/#comment-22</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 05:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=410#comment-22</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In comparison to Leti Volpp’s articale, I think Lowe’s “Immigration Acts” is more complex and she explores deeply about how Asian immigrants are just same as the while European immigrants but they were denied for citizenship.  Lowe includes her thoughts and view with the legislations passed by the U.S. government toward Asian immigrants in this piece, and how the states’ laws were unfair to the Asians. They were always seen as “alien”, cheap labors, immigrants in the states.  Asian immigrants had to protest and defense themselves in order to gain their rights for citizenship status.  I am agreed that gender roles mentioned by Lowe caught my attention too because I am also surprise that back in the days, if a female citizen married with a non- citizen male, she will lose her citizenship because of her marriage.  I also like how Lowe adopts Karl Marx’s theory to abstract her idea of racial capitalism, how U.S. has to maximize it profits through labors and that is including female immigrant labor.  I think Volpp’s piece is short and easier to understand compares to Lowe’s and I am agreed with your points on how she explains different types of citizenship. Her article is organized in a time- line format, so readers are easier to follow compares to Lowe’s.  I am agreed with you that Asian Americans were changed from “Yellow Peril” to “Model Minority” because Asian Americans were questioned to be donors and fundraisers for President Clinton’s re-election in 1996 and they called it the “Asian connection”.  Compares to the “yellow peril” period, Asians were seen as foreigners, and now they are more involve into U.S. politics.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In comparison to Leti Volpp’s articale, I think Lowe’s “Immigration Acts” is more complex and she explores deeply about how Asian immigrants are just same as the while European immigrants but they were denied for citizenship.  Lowe includes her thoughts and view with the legislations passed by the U.S. government toward Asian immigrants in this piece, and how the states’ laws were unfair to the Asians. They were always seen as “alien”, cheap labors, immigrants in the states.  Asian immigrants had to protest and defense themselves in order to gain their rights for citizenship status.  I am agreed that gender roles mentioned by Lowe caught my attention too because I am also surprise that back in the days, if a female citizen married with a non- citizen male, she will lose her citizenship because of her marriage.  I also like how Lowe adopts Karl Marx’s theory to abstract her idea of racial capitalism, how U.S. has to maximize it profits through labors and that is including female immigrant labor.  I think Volpp’s piece is short and easier to understand compares to Lowe’s and I am agreed with your points on how she explains different types of citizenship. Her article is organized in a time- line format, so readers are easier to follow compares to Lowe’s.  I am agreed with you that Asian Americans were changed from “Yellow Peril” to “Model Minority” because Asian Americans were questioned to be donors and fundraisers for President Clinton’s re-election in 1996 and they called it the “Asian connection”.  Compares to the “yellow peril” period, Asians were seen as foreigners, and now they are more involve into U.S. politics.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
