<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
  >

<channel>
  <title>internship &#8211; Intro to Geography</title>
  <atom:link href="{{ site.baseurl }}/geh101/tag/internship/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/geh101</link>
  <description>Lehman College</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 17:03:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <language>en-US</language>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">52642319</site>  <item>
    <title>Summer Opportunity: Western Apache Ethnography and GIS Research Experience</title>
    <link>{{ site.baseurl }}/geh101/2011/02/28/summer-opportunity-western-apache-ethnography-and-gis-research-experience/</link>
    <comments>{{ site.baseurl }}/geh101/2011/02/28/summer-opportunity-western-apache-ethnography-and-gis-research-experience/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 18:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Keith Miyake]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Resources]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[cultural geography]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[GIS]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[internship]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[summer opportunity]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://geh101.wordpress.com/?p=320</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Western Apache Ethnography and GIS Research Experience for Undergraduates The White Mountain Apache Tribe Heritage Program and the University of Arizona announce opportunities for student participation in the second season of the Western Apache Ethnography and GIS Research Experience for Undergraduates field school, a National Science Foundation-supported program, June 6-July 15, 2011. Students participating in this REU will [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Western Apache Ethnography and GIS Research Experience for Undergraduates</p>
<p>The White Mountain Apache Tribe Heritage Program and the University of Arizona announce opportunities for student participation in the second season of the Western Apache Ethnography and GIS Research Experience for Undergraduates field school, a National Science Foundation-supported program, June 6-July 15, 2011.</p>
<p>Students participating in this REU will contribute to the creation of a Western Apache cultural and historical Atlas. Participants will learn field research techniques that will include:<br />
• Creating research plans and documenting research efforts;<br />
• Conducting archival, interview, survey, and participant-observation research;<br />
• Identifying the locations of historical sites and land modification areas from archival maps, photographs, and land inspections;<br />
• Collecting and conducting initial analysis of qualitative and quantitative data relating to historical and cultural use of landscapes and natural resources;<br />
• Applying Geographic Information Science (GIS) and Global Positioning Systems (GPS) tools and technologies to mapping and field data collection.</p>
<p>These tools will provide a firm analytical foundation for the systematic evaluation of cultural data. Students will design research projects, and will work collaboratively with fellow students, cultural advisors, and Tribal personnel to complete research projects that will result in draft entries for inclusion in the Atlas.</p>
<p>Participants will receive room and board at the Fort Apache/Theodore Roosevelt School campus, and a weekly stipend of $500 ($3,000 total for 6 weeks). Non-local students will be responsible for transportation to and from Tucson at the beginning and end of the program and will be expected to arrive in Tucson by Sunday, June 5, and to depart no earlier than Saturday, July 16.</p>
<p>6 hours of course credit from the University of Arizona will be available to participants who successfully complete the program (ANTH 395B Special Topics in Cultural Anthropology: Application of Geographic Information Systems to Cultural Anthropology and ANTH 495B Special Topics in Cultural Anthropology: Ethnographic Field Methods).  2011 U.A. Summer School tuition and fees are anticipated to be approximately $3,200 for 6 hours of coursework; tuition scholarships may be available. Successful applicants will be required to enroll in the University of Arizona summer school in order to receive course credit for the program.  This will require an admission fee (anticipated to be $50 for Arizona residents/$65 for non-residents) and submission of proof of current MMR vaccination.  Program staff will provide additional information and guidance.</p>
<p>All participants in the National Science Foundation Research Experience for Undergraduates must be enrolled in an undergraduate degree program at an accredited college or university (i.e., have completed courses in an AA/AS or BA/BS program during the spring 2011 term and/or be enrolled for courses for the fall 2011 term).</p>
<p>A total of 8 students will be admitted to this program annually, 2010-2012.  Members of the Western Apache Nations (White Mountain Apache Tribe, San Carlos Apache Tribe, Tonto Apache Tribe, Camp Verde Yavapai-Apache Nation) will be given first consideration for this program, but other Native and non-Native students are encouraged to apply.  Applications received before March 18, 2011 will be given first consideration.  Applications will continue to be accepted until the program is full.</p>
<p>For more information please contact REU Director Dr. Karl Hoerig at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;il&#x74;&#x6f;&#58;kh&#x6f;&#x65;&#114;ig&#x40;&#x66;&#111;rt&#x61;&#x70;ac&#x68;&#x65;&#97;ri&#x7a;&#x6f;&#110;a.&#x6f;&#x72;&#103;">&#107;h&#x6f;e&#x72;i&#x67;&#64;&#x66;&#111;&#x72;&#116;a&#x70;a&#x63;h&#x65;a&#x72;i&#x7a;&#111;&#x6e;&#97;.&#x6f;r&#x67;</a>.  This announcement and application form also available online at <a href="http://anthropology.arizona.edu/content/summer_research_experience_undergraduates_ethnography_and_gis">http://anthropology.arizona.edu/content/summer_research_experience_undergraduates_ethnography_and_gis</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>{{ site.baseurl }}/geh101/2011/02/28/summer-opportunity-western-apache-ethnography-and-gis-research-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">320</post-id> </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
