<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Atitaya &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/author/atauthon/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>	<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#124; Asian American Studies</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 16:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=581</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The general messages and meaning I understood from the reading were that Asian American, or ethnic studies, are relatively recent and that there is a continuous struggle to be seen and heard and because of this struggle, AsAm studies are not given enough funding, permanency, and voice. For example, on the CRAASH article, the students [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The general messages and meaning I understood from the reading were that Asian American, or ethnic studies, are relatively recent and that there is a continuous struggle to be seen and heard and because of this struggle, AsAm studies are not given enough funding, permanency, and voice. For example, on the <em>CRAASH</em> article, the students wanted to organize an AsAm program at Hunter College but the lack of funding prevented it from getting its resources and needed attention. Also the writer states that because the program was so horrible before, there was very little student interest and since not many students cared, the program worsened. Then in <em>I Spy Hotel, </em>Mr. Takabayashi goes and begins the class about the AsAm experience which is like an ethnic course but what seems to be like a reoccuring theme is the banning and closing down of his position in the university. In Unemoto&#8217;s piece, I see the ideas of empowerment and activism because the student leaders are striking for education that includes easily accessible material for minorites, in addition to their role in politics and how aware they are of their role.</p>
<p> I don&#8217;t think the Smith reading really related to AsAm studies but I saw it as a way to highlight how &#8220;people of color&#8221;/&#8221;women of color&#8221; are framed from a shared oppression by white supremacy. Even though they all seem to have this &#8220;shared victimhood&#8221; they <em>still</em> victimize each other. I thought it was interesting how Smith included the idea of the heteropatriarchal society and the threats against it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#124; Civil Rights and Militant Radicalism</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 02:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=564</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.asianfortunenews.com/2013/07/race-talk-asian-american-as-a-political-identity-blog/ In this brief article, a half-Japanese American college student reflects on what being Asian American is. In particular, she speaks about the model minority myth and the expectations others have on her in school. She states that she would be labeled with &#8220;foreign-ness and high grades.&#8221; Therefore, the model minority myth has continues to exist [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.asianfortunenews.com/2013/07/race-talk-asian-american-as-a-political-identity-blog/">http://www.asianfortunenews.com/2013/07/race-talk-asian-american-as-a-political-identity-blog/</a></p>
<p>In this brief article, a half-Japanese American college student reflects on what being Asian American is. In particular, she speaks about the model minority myth and the expectations others have on her in school. She states that she would be labeled with &#8220;foreign-ness and high grades.&#8221; Therefore, the model minority myth has continues to exist in the current generation. To add on to the stereotype of Asian-Americans being foreign, the writer says she felt isolated from the customs of her grade-school mates because she would be enjoying a brown rice ball among a lunch table of peanut butter and jelly sandwiches. Somehow she felt different in the sense of identity because for her, she was the one who had to conceal what she was &#8211; she says she ate her brown rice ball as quickly as possible so no one would notice it&#8217;s <em>uncleanliness </em>or <em>odor</em>. For this reason, I see that the writer notices these myths/stereotypes but does not see them as an obstacle but more of a step towards understanding and empowerment. Furthermore, the writer speaks about the role Asian Americans have in the political system. She writes that Asian-Americans are seen as &#8221; apolitical and, as a consequence, suffers from not having much of a say in changing or adopting new laws that are beneficial to its members&#8221; to show that political involvement is crucial in creating visibility within society. Additionally, the writer includes that because of immigration laws and such, several Asian-American communities are in fear of deportation etc., so there is this conflict where there is a need to be visible but if they are perhaps <em>too </em>visible, they could be arrested or something similar.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9tqpEF9-_lw">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9tqpEF9-_lw</a></p>
<p>In this music video, the newer generation of Asian-Americans rap about the histories and impact of inequality on Asians in the U.S. I think this song reflects on the disconnect between the current generation and their ancestors. For example, the title of the song is &#8220;Where&#8217;d you go?&#8221; which probably means that some of the newer generation are unaware of what their grandparents, for example, had to endure in order to provide for their families, especially with the high amount of inequality and lack of many civil rights. Furthermore, the newer generation have this disconnect with the older generation because they are not confronted with the same lack of equality in society and politics.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-civil-rights-and-militant-radicalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">564</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#124; The War on Terror</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/29/primary-reader-the-war-on-terror/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/29/primary-reader-the-war-on-terror/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 01:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=505</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I thought the ideas discussed in this week&#8217;s readings were overall very interesting and thought-provoking. The racial formation of Muslims from the discourses of terror, racial panic, and Islamic peril is clear even to this day, particularly in New York City because there continues to be incidents of Muslim citizens being attacked or discriminated against [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I thought the ideas discussed in this week&#8217;s readings were overall very interesting and thought-provoking. The racial formation of Muslims from the discourses of terror, racial panic, and Islamic peril is clear even to this day, particularly in New York City because there continues to be incidents of Muslim citizens being attacked or discriminated against because of the preconceived notion of them being &#8220;threats&#8221;. Also I thought it was a little ridiculous how in the readings, they said the U.S. uses terror as a substantial excuse to use violence or deport people. What really caught my attention was in the Rana reading when it states something along the lines of terror being the manufacturing of fear. It seems that most of the controversy around the topic of the war on terror surrounds the thought of another attack happening so people are naturally fearful but I do not think that should allow for unjust decisions made by the government. In the Maira reading, the idea of the U.S. being an empire or imperial power was interesting, too. I think that the U.S. has enough global visibility to influence the minds of other nations, particularly developing ones.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/29/primary-reader-the-war-on-terror/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">505</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#124; Empire, Globalization, Diasporas, Transnationalism</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/26/researcher-empire-globalization-diasporas-transnationalism/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/26/researcher-empire-globalization-diasporas-transnationalism/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 02:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=489</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Generational Gaps/Stereotypes In this video, an assumed first generation Asian American boy talks about the stereotypes he has noticed about Asians in the US. This video relates to the Lisa Lowe piece because in her reading, she says it is important to be united as Asian-Americans in order to fight towards equality but at the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYpA0d9UXyw">Generational Gaps/Stereotypes</a></p>
<p>In this video, an assumed first generation Asian American boy talks about the stereotypes he has noticed about Asians in the US. This video relates to the Lisa Lowe piece because in her reading, she says it is important to be united as Asian-Americans in order to fight towards equality but at the same time unity can also lead to generalizations such as stereotypes and racism. Another aspect of her piece is about the parent-child conflict because of a difference in childhood environments. As shown in the video, the boy has conflicting views and a different mindset from his mother about culture. Although he practices the customs of his Asian-American mother, he also has incorporated &#8220;American&#8221; customs which may not go along with what his mother is used to. But I think he does not lose his mother&#8217;s &#8220;Asian identity&#8221; but rather integrates it with the practices he has learned from growing up in America.</p>
<p><a href="http://informahealthcare.com/doi/abs/10.1080/09540269874763">http://informahealthcare.com/doi/abs/10.1080/09540269874763</a></p>
<p>This research paper is about the intense effects of war and displacement on children from Croatia. As we can see, adults are not the only ones who are affected emotionally and I believe children are more vulnerable to adverse effects of war displacement because they are usually more sensitive and naïve. For this reason it is important to give more attention to the children who experience any sort of war displacement because the post-traumatic stress can have a lasting, permanent effect. Children too can feel isolated and distant from the children in the new country, not just adults.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/26/researcher-empire-globalization-diasporas-transnationalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">489</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#124; Law and Citizenship</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/18/primary-reader-law-and-citizenship/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/18/primary-reader-law-and-citizenship/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=405</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Lisa Lowe&#8217;s piece, I thought her ideas on culture equating to citizenship were interesting because it is not necessarily what it is today. Citizenship in the early twentieth century seemed to be based on how well someone was integrated or assimilated into American culture, so it was affected by societal norms and pressures. I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Lisa Lowe&#8217;s piece, I thought her ideas on culture equating to citizenship were interesting because it is not necessarily what it is today. Citizenship in the early twentieth century seemed to be based on how well someone was integrated or assimilated into American culture, so it was affected by societal norms and pressures. I liked the anecdote in the beginning about the Chinese American woman designing the memorial for U.S. Vietnam veterans. I thought it was surprising how the veterans did not feel &#8220;represented&#8221; by her design, and how this incident led to inevitable greater racial tension. I liked how Lowe pointed out that Asian Americans have been &#8220;subject to&#8221; and &#8220;subjects of&#8221; the immigration debacle; they&#8217;ve been a crucial center piece of controversy while having to live through the struggle of inequality. Also Lowe&#8217;s points about the role of the state and its lack of carrying out the &#8220;organization and interpretation of race&#8221; (10) was provoking.</p>
<p>Personally, I preferred Leti Volpp&#8217;s piece because it was better organized and easier to read. Her central idea of it being necessary to be able to access all four forms of citizenship was interesting. The section on citizenship as legal status reinforced the thought of Asian Americans as being inferior to other racial group and lacking political power. Also, I thought it was ridiculous how the ownership of property was part of someone being a good citizen but Asian American were ineligible of owning property so they weren&#8217;t even given a chance to become good citizens. In this reading, media was important because it provided the public with an image of Asian America; however, the image portrayed hurt the positive image that was being strived. But as Volpp later states, the idea of Asian Americans changed from &#8220;yellow peril&#8221; to &#8220;model minority&#8221;, and I thought that was interesting too.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/18/primary-reader-law-and-citizenship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">405</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#124; Racial Capital, Racial Hierarchy</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/17/researcher-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/17/researcher-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 22:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=395</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;What kind of Asian are you?&#8221; In this video, a European-American man begins to talk to an Asian-American woman and asks her where she&#8217;s from. There is a misunderstanding on both sides of the question. He wants to know what her ethnicity is, whereas she thinks he&#8217;s asking her what town she&#8217;s from. I think [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='560' height='315' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/DWynJkN5HbQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe>
<p>&#8220;What kind of Asian are you?&#8221;</p>
<p>In this video, a European-American man begins to talk to an Asian-American woman and asks her where she&#8217;s from. There is a misunderstanding on both sides of the question. He wants to know what her ethnicity is, whereas she thinks he&#8217;s asking her what town she&#8217;s from. I think this video relates to Claire Jean Kim&#8217;s piece because similarly to the reading, there was an idea of all Asian sub-groups being the same, like one homogenous blob. Also the reading touched upon the idea of Asians being the same in the U.S. as in Asia. Almost like they could not become Americanized, and as Kim said, &#8220;aliens ineligible of citizenship.&#8221; This video points out that Asians have been integrated into American culture much like their European counterparts.</p>
<p>academiccommons.columbia.edu/item/ac:124615</p>
<p>(a link to open a PDF is on the website)</p>
<p>This paper addresses the hardships and racism Latino and Asian Americans had to endure immediately after immigrating to the U.S., particularly in the mining of gold. Similarly to Moon-Ho Jung&#8217;s piece, Asian Americans were not treated well and kind of had a place below the White population but were unsure of their status&#8230;almost like racial triangulation. In addition, the Latino and Asian American immigrants did not fit into social or cultural categories. We see the constant theme of struggle in both pieces in order for a better life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/17/researcher-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">395</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#124; Racial Formation, the State, Capital</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/08/primary-reader-racial-formation-the-state-capital/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/08/primary-reader-racial-formation-the-state-capital/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 18:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=242</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Omi &#38; Winant&#8217;s piece, I thought the idea introduced about how race is a key component to political leaders and political state was intriguing. I particularly enjoyed how chapter five began with an anecdote about the irony of racial politics. Additionally, I thought chapter four really provoked the idea of how involved government is [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Omi &amp; Winant&#8217;s piece, I thought the idea introduced about how race is a key component to political leaders and political state was intriguing. I particularly enjoyed how chapter five began with an anecdote about the irony of racial politics. Additionally, I thought chapter four really provoked the idea of how involved government is in racial formation. It also shows how race is seen differently for the individual as opposed to the state, as shown in Phipps&#8217; case. I agree with their idea that race is &#8220;an element of social structure rather than an irregularity within it&#8221; (55) because race is clearly an important factor in human interaction, perhaps unconsciously, as well as in the state (government, public health, etc.). However, I thought what Charles Murray (56) said about race not being a good enough reason to treat others differently was interesting because it contradicts what was said earlier about race being used to unevenly distributing rights but then again, it may be impossible for institutions to be &#8220;color-blind&#8221;.</p>
<p>How does racial formation tie in with the concept of intersectionality?</p>
<p>In Molina&#8217;s piece, I thought the focus on public health and how it caused racial formation was interesting. A concept that was intriguing was the idea that &#8220;American-ness&#8221; was associated with cleanliness. I think that since Chinese, Mexican, and Japanese citizens did not receive adequate health care, their unhygienic lifestyle was exacerbated. Molina further explains that these minorities were ostracized and officials of institutions treated them as if they were toxic to one&#8217;s health and to American culture, and as Molina states, &#8221; institutional policies affected a sense of social membership.&#8221; Particularly, I though Molina&#8217;s evidence that public health discourses used unclean conditions as a way to prove Chinese would not last in the economy.</p>
<p>What resulted in the dramatic decrease of the Chinese population in the county (see Table 1). Was it more necessary for minority groups to be integrated or assimilated?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/08/primary-reader-racial-formation-the-state-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">242</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#124; Orientalism &#038; Politics of Knowledge</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/05/researcher-orientalism-politics-of-knowledge/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/05/researcher-orientalism-politics-of-knowledge/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 02:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=223</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The first photo is a cartoon that depicts the unhygienic, crowded conditions Chinese immigrants had to endure, contrary to other ethnic groups. The caption for the half of the cartoon says  &#8220;Why they can live on 40 cents a day&#8221; and on the right, the caption is &#8220;and they can&#8217;t&#8221;. I think these captions further elaborate on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/ASAM1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-224" title="Tight Apartment" alt="http://thesocietypages.org/socimages/2008/07/08/old-yellow-peril-anti-chinese-posters/" src="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/ASAM1.jpg?resize=300%2C298" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/ASAM1.jpg?resize=150%2C150 150w, https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/ASAM1.jpg?resize=125%2C125 125w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><a href="https://i0.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/ASAM2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-225" alt="http://www.care2.com/news/member/140535861/1179426" src="https://i0.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/ASAM2.jpg?fit=300%2C300" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/ASAM2.jpg?resize=289%2C300 289w, https://i0.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/ASAM2.jpg?w=357 357w" sizes="(max-width: 289px) 100vw, 289px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a>
<p>The first photo is a cartoon that depicts the unhygienic, crowded conditions Chinese immigrants had to endure, contrary to other ethnic groups. The caption for the half of the cartoon says  &#8220;Why they can live on 40 cents a day&#8221; and on the right, the caption is &#8220;and they can&#8217;t&#8221;. I think these captions further elaborate on the fact that Chinese workers were paid very little, and perhaps did not need as much because they were sharing small apartments with several other families. Additionally, due to the cramped living spaces, the opportunities for diseases to spread increased because people came in close contact with those infected with diseases. Furthermore, with more Chinese immigrants contracting diseases, the perception of them by society became more negative, as explained by Shah. I think this source effectively portrays the problems during the mid 1800&#8217;s in San Francisco because of the inequality of living conditions between races.</p>
<p>The second photo is also a cartoon that depicts the British as controlling and readily colonizing countries. This cartoon highlights the ideas in Saïd&#8217;s <em>Orientalism</em> about the relationship of power between European countries and other countries. The imperialistic empires of Europe enforce power onto the Orient countries almost as a means of mirroring their capabilities. For example, Saïd states, &#8220;European culture gained in strength and identity by setting itself off against the Orient as a sort of surrogate and even underground self&#8221; (3). Therefore, in my opinion, the British and the French gained and exerted power by manipulating Asian countries.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/05/researcher-orientalism-politics-of-knowledge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">223</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
