<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Linda He &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/author/lindahe/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>	<item>
		<title>Primary Reader: Asian American Studies</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-2/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 01:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=595</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I really liked the article “A Full-on CRAASH at Hunter College” because I have met members who were part of the organization in the spring of 2011. They seemed very committed to the cause so I did not find it a surprise that this article showcased the passionate leaders of the organization. I took several Asian [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I really liked the article “A Full-on CRAASH at Hunter College” because I have met members who were part of the organization in the spring of 2011. They seemed very committed to the cause so I did not find it a surprise that this article showcased the passionate leaders of the organization. I took several Asian American courses and I found them really helpful in understanding the discourse of various liberation movements. I thought it was really helpful for future students of that rally to continue to be able to take courses because it offers insight into Asian American history and sentiment. It is a different telling of history in the eyes of several Asian American scholars as well as an education in how we can fight for Asian American rights.</p>
<p>It is difficult to maintain a Hunter College Asian American Studies Program without enough funding as well as the constant change of faculty but otherwise looking at the courses that Hunter College offers, I actually think it is plenty. It did not surprise me that Hunter College had more Asian American Studies Courses than most schools in New York and the only CUNY to offer the program but I do think it is necessary to continue to fight for more funding and better resources to teach the material better. The more courses I took, the more I could relate the material to other discourses in political science and the more I understood how the world worked under systems of oppression, marginalization, and empire.</p>
<p>That being said, I was not surprised to read that within the CUNY system, administration gave apathetic responses when students fought for greater funding for Asian American Studies Program and more resources. I think it is a predictable response by the Hunter College administration to students who want to break the status quo for a program that promotes awareness. It is a predictable response in terms of understanding neo-liberalism why the administration would want to push off the interests of the Asian American Studies Program. I think it is easier for the administration to push off the interests of the students in comparison to the response by the college administration during the San Francisco protests.</p>
<p>In “’On Strike!’: San Francisco College Strike, 1968-1969’” by Karen Umemoto, while a School of Ethnic Studies was created at San Francisco State due to many days of protest, I would not be surprised if students have to continue to fight a dreary and long-drawn fight. I think it is hard for students to have to fight for greater awareness at Hunter College because it always seems like there is a barrier between the many offices of Hunter College, the administration, and the attitude to students. It is particularly hard to students who want to break the status quo to be heard or even be recognized as a group because the CUNY system in itself is a system that was segregated with no real glue in terms of student action and collective action.</p>
<p>The administration seems to not want to be involved in movements led by Asian American students but perhaps this is due to the way the CUNY system is set up. There are no real dorms for the entire student population or general housing, and so it is particularly hard for students to really gain a sense of community and fight for a common cause.</p>
<p>Discussion Questions:</p>
<p>How can we promote a greater understanding of the Asian American Studies Program and how is it fought for in other colleges around the state?</p>
<p>How can we rally more funding for the Asian American Studies Program and how is it done in other colleges around the state?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">595</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher: Transnational Labor and Capital</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-transnational-labor-and-capital/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-transnational-labor-and-capital/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 17:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=561</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Rachel Salazar Parrenas &#8220;Migrant Filipina Domestic Workers and the International Division of Reproductive Labor,&#8221; she writes &#8220;the hierarchy of womanhood &#8211; based on race, class, and nation &#8211; establishes a work transfer system of reproductive labor among women &#8211; the international transfer of caretaking.&#8221; I looked up reproductive labor as child-rearing and house keeping duties [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Rachel Salazar Parrenas &#8220;Migrant Filipina Domestic Workers and the International Division of Reproductive Labor,&#8221; she writes &#8220;the hierarchy of womanhood &#8211; based on race, class, and nation &#8211; establishes a work transfer system of reproductive labor among women &#8211; the international transfer of caretaking.&#8221; I looked up reproductive labor as child-rearing and house keeping duties and I realized that it was indeed the stereotype of Latin American women to take on the roles of maids or janitorial duties. Even though this stereotype may not be entirely accurate, I think that it is unfortunate that this labor is also hard but often not credited with a full set of employment rights. In addition, I recently saw a trailer for this show about housekeeping maids that were all of Hispanic ethnicity: <a href="http://www.mylifetime.com/shows/devious-maids">http://www.mylifetime.com/shows/devious-maids</a>.</p>
<p>I think the point of a lot of entertainment is to make fun of stereotypes and this is a perfect way to depict some of the stereotypes in society that has had lasting impressions. Even if the stereotype is not true, it is a depiction of what we see and think in modern society.</p>
<p>In Junaid Rana&#8217;s &#8220;Labor Diaspora and the Global Racial System,&#8221; she talks about &#8220;the consolidation of the South Asian labor diaspora in the global racial system that began during the period of colonial indenture continues into the contemporary period via an economic and political strategy of neoliberalism now practiced across the planet.&#8221; Rana critiques neoliberalism and argues that the idea of free trade only benefits an imperialistic power like the United States instead of giving everyone equal opportunity. She critiques that it is only people at the top that get to benefit from neoliberalism or &#8220;free trade&#8221; practices. This article talks about the recent alliance to empower South Asian immigrants in terms of fulfilling goals they have when in comes to work: <a href="http://www.dc37.net/news/PEP/2_2012/south_asian_power.html">http://www.dc37.net/news/PEP/2_2012/south_asian_power.html</a>.</p>
<p>I think that it is a good article because it shows how immigrants are increasingly rallying for support just as we saw the Vietnamese in the New Orleans documentary. Though the Vietnamese were fighting for a political awareness in terms of community, the South Asian immigrants are fighting for employment benefits. In either case, both sought greater visibility and presence in either the communities they were in or in the country they were in. Rana mostly critiques the imperialism of the country but the documentary reminds us to start of small is still a staring place, within their community.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/05/researcher-transnational-labor-and-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">561</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; Empire, Globalization, Diasporas, and Transnationalism</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/26/primary-reader-empire-globalization-diasporas-and-transnationalism/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/26/primary-reader-empire-globalization-diasporas-and-transnationalism/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 04:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diaspora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Empire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Globalization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lisa Lowe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert G Lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transnationalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wanni Anderson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=570</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Lisa Lowe’s “Heterogeneity, Hybridity, and Multiciplicy: Asian American Differences,” she talks about the problems that come with the idea of a homogeneous Asian American population. Instead of looking at Asian American populations as homogeneous, she wants to talk about the heterogeneity and hybridity of the population. In addition she wants to make it a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">In Lisa Lowe’s “Heterogeneity, Hybridity, and Multiciplicy: Asian American Differences,” she talks about the problems that come with the idea of a homogeneous Asian American population. Instead of looking at Asian American populations as homogeneous, she wants to talk about the heterogeneity and hybridity of the population. In addition she wants to make it a point that Asian Americans should be viewed with multiplicity, or in different lights. She writes, describing Asian American homogeneity, “The articulation of an ‘Asian American identity’ as an organizing tool has provided a concept of political unity to understand unequal circumstances and histories as being related” (71). I think she is acknowledging that the unity of only one” Asian American identity” has perhaps have had some political benefits but goes on to critique this standpoint as wrong because it “implies Asians are ‘all alike’ and conform to ‘types’” (71). In addition, she writes “Rather, the assertion of ‘integral autonomy’ by ‘not unified’ classes suggests a coordination of distinct, yet allied, positions, practices, and movements – class-identified and not class-identified, in parties and not, race-based and gender-based – each on its own, not necessarily equivalent manner transforming, disrupting, and destructuring the apparatuses of a specific hegemony” (70). In other words, a one unified view of Asian Americans is erroneous because it ignores many of the differences between Asian Americans as well as reinforces the idea that there is one, specific, dominant hegemon, or in this case the White population.</span></p>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">In Anderson, Wanni W. and Robert G. Lee’s “Asian American Displacements,” they write about four types of displacement. They write “at beginning of the twenty-first century, we identify four existing forms of displacement as the lived experienced of the immigrant, the refugee, the exile, the expatriate, and the migrant: physical/spatial displacement, cultural displacement, psychological/affective displacement, and intellectual displacement” (11). I think of physical/spatial as the first type of displacement but with time, this type of displacement can lead to “cultural,” “psychological,” and “intellectual” displacement. I think that the latter of the three types of displacement are the most straining and the most offensive to new immigrants who are struggling to conform to new cultures, new ideas, and new ambiances. The term hypochondria comes to mind when I think of people who have trouble fitting in to the present place they are in because they are suffering from being away from home, from adjusting to the new time as voiced in many Asian American texts. In the end, they conclude “they (volumes) lead us through the Asian experience in the Americas across space and time and provide us a conceptual map with which we can engage the changing economic, cultural, and political landscapes” (17). The writers end on a hopeful path as they acknowledged earlier in the text that Asian American studies were conceived in the 1970’s after being empowered by the Civil Rights Movement in the 1960’s to fight the oppression that inhibited a racially divided America.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">Discussion Questions</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">1) Is Lisa Lowe’s writing accurate of what is happening in today’s United Stated States? If so, what can we do to empower Asian Americans to fight for better representation?</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">2) Are Asian Americans being subjected to great “cultural,” “psychological” and “intellectual” strain because they are a minority and because they have been displaced from their home country? What can we do to alleviate some of the pressure?</span></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/26/primary-reader-empire-globalization-diasporas-and-transnationalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">570</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher: June 24th &#8211; Pacific Wars</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/23/researcher-june-24th-pacific-wars/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/23/researcher-june-24th-pacific-wars/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 18:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=440</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Robert Lee&#8217;s &#8220;Cold War Construction of the Model Minority Myth,&#8221; he writes that Asian Americans were more likely to fit in a white-dominant society because Asian Americans were not Blacks. He writes &#8220;Asian Americans were &#8216;not black&#8217; in 2 significant ways: they were politically silent and ethnically assimilable&#8221; (145). I never thought about the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Robert Lee&#8217;s &#8220;Cold War Construction of the Model Minority Myth,&#8221; he writes that Asian Americans were more likely to fit in a white-dominant society because Asian Americans were not Blacks. He writes &#8220;Asian Americans were &#8216;not black&#8217; in 2 significant ways: they were politically silent and ethnically assimilable&#8221; (145). I never thought about the Model Minority Myth as a product of the Cold War and the ideologies that &#8220;Whites&#8221; tries to counter. I had always assumed that Asians were the model minority based strictly on their academic performance but Lee makes an interesting and pithy argument. The story of the model minority,&#8221; he argues, was to counter the &#8220;red menace of communism,&#8221; &#8220;the black menace of race mixing,&#8221; and the &#8220;white menace of homosexuality&#8221; (146). I looked up some articles to go with these arguments and I found this article: http://diverseeducation.com/article/52979/#.</p>
<p>This article is titled &#8220;The Model Minority Myth: What 50 Years of Research Does and Does Not Tell Us&#8221; by Dr. Nicholas D. Hartlep. He critiques the idea that Asian Americans were recognized solely by their academic achievements such as stereotypically high SAT&#8217;s, subservience, and high GPA&#8217;s. Because Asian Americans possessed these quintessential qualities, Hartlep argues that Asian Americans were branded as the model minority because the United States were &#8220;trying to shift&#8221; negative attention away from itself. In other words, Asian Americans were the intentional brand of model minority and constructed during the Cold War because they did not see African Americans as assimilable. This aligns with Lee&#8217;s argument who wrote Asian Americans were the intentional brand of a model minority and constructed during the Cold War because they did not see African Americans as assimilable. As Hartlep puts it &#8220;it was not their (African Americans) fate.&#8221; Lee also mentioned certain ideologies such as &#8220;communism&#8221; and other social stigmas such as &#8220;race mixing&#8221; and &#8220;homosexuality.&#8221; Therefore, I think this article is a good resource to help us understand Lee&#8217;s &#8220;Cold War Construction of the Model Minority Myth.&#8221;</p>
<p>In David Palumbo-Liu&#8217;s &#8220;War, the Homeland, and the Traces of Memory,&#8221; he writes &#8220;America&#8217;s interest in the Sino-Japanese War, it&#8217;s war in the Pacific (and it&#8217;s postwar relations in that area), it&#8217;s concern with China&#8217;s and Taiwan&#8217;s position in the Cold War, its wars in Korea and Indochina, have all affected Asian Americans profoundly, both in terms of Asians already in America and Asians who migrated to the United States&#8221; (218). He links war to how Asian Americans may have remembered their feelings tied to either their homeland, their identity, or the question of citizenship. In all these instances, Liu writes that perhaps Asian Americans had to remember differently as a result of the wars the United States wages. Because of how the United States acted in either their mother country or &#8220;ethnic&#8221; country, perhaps some Asians had to purposefully forget what they once had close and perhaps that sentiment really was important to the Asian Americans who may have felt displaced from their identity, their homes, and their idea of belonging or &#8220;citizenship&#8221; &#8211; something that had always been contested by United States&#8217; legislation.</p>
<p>These videos/trailers highlight some of the sentiment Asian Americans want to remember or had to forget: <a href="http://caamfest.com/2013/films/memories-to-light/">http://caamfest.com/2013/films/memories-to-light/</a> and <a href="http://caamfest.com/2013/films/memory-of-forgotten-war/">http://caamfest.com/2013/films/memory-of-forgotten-war/</a>. These videos talk about keeping the memories alive in a racially torn decision to remember being American or remember their home or &#8220;ethnic&#8221; country. I think it&#8217;s interesting to see the compilations.</p>
<p>Discussion Questions:</p>
<p>1. What other forms of media can we use to keep the memory alive?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/23/researcher-june-24th-pacific-wars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">440</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; Racial Capital, Racial Hierarchy</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/17/primary-reader-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/17/primary-reader-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 04:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Moon-Ho Jung&#8217;s &#8220;Introduction&#8221; and &#8220;Domesticating Labor,&#8221; he writes &#8220;Coolies confused the boundary between slavery and freedom, between black and white, causing the mass demand for Asian migrant laborers as well as appeals for their exclusion in the postbellum United States&#8221; (6). Coolies as I understand, is &#8220;cheap labor&#8221; or those with jobs that do not [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Moon-Ho Jung&#8217;s &#8220;Introduction&#8221; and &#8220;Domesticating Labor,&#8221; he writes &#8220;Coolies confused the boundary between slavery and freedom, between black and white, causing the mass demand for Asian migrant laborers as well as appeals for their exclusion in the postbellum United States&#8221; (6). Coolies as I understand, is &#8220;cheap labor&#8221; or those with jobs that do not have employment benefits such as health care, or representation of a union. Coolies did not have unions to protect their job at the workplace, and most are temporary and hired for a brief moment of time, usually in instances where the regular workers are on protest or if the employers want to employ cheap labor to increase their profit margin. I think Coolies would have had a hard time in the United States with no protections for their jobs, nor insurances for their job in case of an accident which is probably the worse drawback. I would imagine Asians would not have been treated as well as the Whites or paid as much which is similar to how women are not paid as much even in the present United States. I believe Women only earn about $0.68 to every dollar. In Leti Volpp&#8217;s &#8216;&#8221;Obnoxious To Their Very Nature&#8221;: Asian Americans and Constitutional Citizenship,&#8217; she questions Asian American citizenship and writes &#8220;For more than a century and a half, Asian Americans were barred from naturalization; and they continue to be viewed as a group whose loyalty to American remains in doubt&#8221; (71). I think that this is the reason these two readings were put together because they focus on the question mark of Asian American identity. Asian Americans in United States history did not enjoy the same benefits or protections as other White Americans with European Americans, though not citizens, receiving better treatment because of their race and color of their skin. Many Asian American writers point out how Asian Americans are constantly being interrogated or short-handed their rights in the case of Japanese Internment and the Exclusionary Acts. Japanese Internment was a disaster for Asian American rights because the United States decided to displace many Japanese people of their homes in fear of espionage or treason in response to the December attacks on Pearl Harbor. Although Exclusionary Acts barred new immigration, current citizens of that time period were still discriminated and denied a full set of constitutional rights which every American citizen could enjoy because they were either a member of the White race or because they were not Asian or categorized as inferior.</p>
<p>Discussion Questions</p>
<p>1. Do we still see Asian Americans being questioned of their identity as American due to their race?</p>
<p>2. In what instances can we improve Asian American presence and recognition as full citizens with a full set of rights?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/17/primary-reader-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">387</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#8211; Discourse of Exclusion (June 12th)</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/14/researcher-discourse-of-exclusion-june-12th/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/14/researcher-discourse-of-exclusion-june-12th/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 23:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=333</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1st Source: http://ocw.mit.edu/ans7870/21f/21f.027/yellow_promise_yellow_peril/perils.html, Reading 1: Lee, Erika. 2007. &#8220;The &#8216;Yellow Peril&#8217; and Asian Exclusion in the Americas.&#8221; Pacific Historical 76 (4): 537-562.   For &#8220;The Yellow Peril&#8217; and Asian Exclusion in the Americas&#8221; by Erika Lee, I chose this picture because it makes alot of her argument come to life. I chose this picture because it depicts an Asian [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1st Source: <a href="http://ocw.mit.edu/ans7870/21f/21f.027/yellow_promise_yellow_peril/perils.html">http://ocw.mit.edu/ans7870/21f/21f.027/yellow_promise_yellow_peril/perils.html</a>, Reading 1: Lee, Erika. 2007. &#8220;The &#8216;Yellow Peril&#8217; and Asian Exclusion in the Americas.&#8221; Pacific Historical 76 (4): 537-562.</p>
<div><img title="" alt="MIT Visualizing Cultures" src="https://i2.wp.com/ocw.mit.edu/ans7870/21f/21f.027/yellow_promise_yellow_peril/image/2002_3727.jpg?resize=289%2C409" data-recalc-dims="1" /></div>
<div> </div>
<div>For &#8220;The Yellow Peril&#8217; and Asian Exclusion in the Americas&#8221; by Erika Lee, I chose this picture because it makes alot of her argument come to life. I chose this picture because it depicts an Asian American who destroys the world after invading the world, now collectively the Asian Empire, but at the same time, the Asian American in the picture ultimately destroys what it tried to set out to do. This shows that Asian Americans are dangerous, and a threat to the Western World, the White Population, and above all, the human population. This picture tries to depict how Asian Americans are dangerous, and will eventually destroy itself from the &#8220;excess&#8221; stereotype. The picture is almost what most White Populations prophecize, that Asian Americans are not worth bringing into the United States as evidenced in American Legislation. This picture describes the &#8220;hemispheric Orientalism&#8221; Lee describes. Lee wrote &#8221; &#8220;I argue that these national (exclusionary) policies were not separate phenomena but rather resulted from a transnational anti-Asian racism &#8211; what I have called &#8216;hemispheric Orientalism&#8217; &#8211; that flourished and moved across national bondaries&#8221; (538). The picture shows that it was not the United States that discriminated Asian Americans but Latin America, Canada, the Carribean, Hawaii, and Mexico. This picture tries to show peoples&#8217; fear of an &#8220;Asian Invasion.&#8221; Lee continues to write about the transnational networks that homeland citizens around the world seemed to discriminate against: &#8220;Retaining ties to thier homelands and forming networks across national borders, these Asians were like many migrants who practiced transnational migration adn formed diasporic communities&#8221; (538). Asian Americans were virtually not welcome anywhere in these networks, even when the United States would be the final destination.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2nd Source:<a href="http://www.vintagefineartprints.com/print-18502-1869353/japanese-yellow-peril-paranoid-comment-japans-expansionism-giclee-print/">http://www.vintagefineartprints.com/print-18502-1869353/japanese-yellow-peril-paranoid-comment-japans-expansionism-giclee-print/</a> , Reading 2: Ono, Kent A. and Vincent N. Pham. 2009. &#8220;The Persistence of Yellow Peril Discourse.&#8221; In Asian Americans and the Media. Cambridge, UK and Malden, MA: Polity Press, 25-44.</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.vintagefineartprints.com/print-18502-1869353/japanese-yellow-peril-paranoid-comment-japans-expansionism-giclee-print/buy/1869353/" target="allposters"><img alt="Buy The Japanese " src="https://i1.wp.com/imagecache6.allposters.com/LRG//17/1741/H6X3D00Z.jpg?resize=336%2C404" border="0" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></td>
<td valign="top"><img alt="" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.vintagefineartprints.com/print-18502-1869353/japanese-yellow-peril-paranoid-comment-japans-expansionism-giclee-print/themes/standard/images/poster_bg_r_top.jpg?resize=11%2C13" border="0" data-recalc-dims="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" valign="top"> </td>
<td align="left" valign="top"> </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>In this picture, this shows what the White Populations thought of Japanese immigration. This  pictures shows the fear of White Populations and populations around the world about the expansion Japanese and other Asian populations have evoked. Though the stereotypes are contested, the picture shows how frightening the expansion could be in the eyes of who believe their legitimacy is established i.e., non-immigrants, those that are native. This pictures shows the threat that non-immigrants may have faced, the picture is frightening enough but the author wants to show that these fears may be a misperception and ends by writing: &#8220;Our approach to studying yellow peril discourse in this chapter has been to take an Asian American studies perspective on the subject; to draw attention to the historical, social, political, and legal conditions that relate to its existence: to emphasize the multimedia dimension of the emergence of yellow peril: and to suggest the ability ultimately to change media representations through knowledge, study, and critical examinations of such representations&#8221; (44). I think this is the best approach, although this is an approach that will take time as Asian Americans have yet to gain a presence in the media. Even then, Asian Americans are not hired for the roles that would exactly be considered socially acceptable, instead these roles exacerbate Asian American or Asian immigrants in a light that is not favorable, just as their presence has been in much of United States history during the late 1800s, and early 1900&#8217;s. In connection to the first text by Lee, Ono and Pham also agree on the same tangent that: &#8220;Furthermore, these examples illustrate that yellow peril is a media discourse that refers abstractly to the threat of Asian takeover and therefore does not allow for distinctions among groups&#8221; (44). Lee, Ono, and Pham all argue for a reconstruction of Asian identity in media, and that may be possible in the near future with growing acceptance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/14/researcher-discourse-of-exclusion-june-12th/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; June 5th Readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/05/primary-reader-june-5th-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/05/primary-reader-june-5th-readings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 02:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=227</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Nayan Shah’s “Public Health and The Mapping of Chinatown,” he comes to the conclusion that “The Chinese were characterized repeatedly in terms of ‘excess’ – of their number, of their living densities, of the diseases they spawned, and of the waste they produced” (173). I do not find this conclusion during the start of the Chinatown [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Nayan Shah’s “Public Health and The Mapping of Chinatown,” he comes to the conclusion that “The Chinese were characterized repeatedly in terms of ‘excess’ – of their number, of their living densities, of the diseases they spawned, and of the waste they produced” (173). I do not find this conclusion during the start of the Chinatown in San Francisco and different from peoples’ descriptions of today’s Chinatowns including those in Manhattan and Sunset Park. It is a shame that because the Chinese are considered “foreign” or “alien,” they are judged with the full weight of biases and discrimination which is evident in United States history with the Exclusion Act of 1882.</p>
<p>In Edward Said’s “Orientalism,” he comes to the conclusion that “If this (better understanding) stimulates a new kind of dealing with the Orient, indeed if it eliminates the ‘Orient’ and ‘Occident’ altogether, then we shall have advanced a little in the process of what Raymond Williams has called the ‘unlearning’ of the ‘inherent dominative mode’” (28). I think that Said is correct in that “unlearning” and perhaps a color blind approach or close alternatives to seeing other people of different races or origins may help us learn more effectively about different people and their cultures. It is interesting the paradox of learning in different ways would mean unlearning ways he have already been conditioned, to think in dominant terms, in terms of superior and inferior.</p>
<p>In Martin F. Manalansan IV’s “Searching for Community: Filipino Gay Men in New York City,” he comes to the conclusion “Filipino gay men, as I have shown, respond to various historical instances, such as the AIDS pandemic, anchored to shared cultural traditions that are continually renewed and reassembled” (403). I think that Manahlansan IV’s has a positive tone and outlook to the future of Filipino Gay Men. I think that this is in part because New York City is a diverse, “melting pot” which enables different groups and culture to assimilate easier that a rural or suburban area where cultures may not have the greater chance to intermingle. I think it is interesting in part of other Asian American texts I have read, that he ends on a positive note but political movements are gaining an edge in further acceptance of the gay community which Manahlansan states is not static, but changes with time.   </p>
<p>I think all three texts are interesting because they provide some insight into Asian American literature and works. In Shah’s “Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown,” he is adamant about pointing out the discrimination Chinese people which many Asian literature points to, which makes Manalansan IV’s “Searching for Community: Filipino Gay Men in New York City” interesting because it is a change of pace in most literature I have come across. Many Asian American literature points to discrimination, and unfair practices in the United States such as internment camps, and Exclusion Acts but I think Edward Said’s “Orientalism” is the best way to focus on learning about different cultures, which is ironically to “unlearn” dominant habits and ways of thinking, to be more accepting of different cultures.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/05/primary-reader-june-5th-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">227</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
