<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kristina Szeto &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/author/kristinaszeto/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>	<item>
		<title>Researcher &#8211; July 8th Readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-july-8th-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-july-8th-readings/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 09:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=636</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think this TED talk shows how space and mobilization have helped her not only escape and reach freedom but shaped her struggle. She has found &#8216;safe spaces&#8217; in her quest for freedom in China and South Korea, but they are not completely without danger. Her movement between these safe spaces define a refugee network [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/lang/en/hyeonseo_lee_my_escape_from_north_korea.html" width="500" height="750" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
<p>I think this TED talk shows how space and mobilization have helped her not only escape and reach freedom but shaped her struggle. She has found &#8216;safe spaces&#8217; in her quest for freedom in China and South Korea, but they are not completely without danger. Her movement between these safe spaces define a refugee network for North Koreans.</p>
<p>These &#8216;safe&#8217; spaces she found with their own inherent dangers present a new perspective. In China, she <em>knew</em> she was North Korean, but had to pretend she was Chinese, or risk repatriation. But in South Korea, she began to question her own identity because of the division between North and South Korea even though they were one country. The implication that <em>one</em> country and space (Korea) is divided into <em>two</em> spaces (North and South Korea) with <em>two</em> racial identities (North and South Korean) rather than <em>one</em> racial identity (Korean, which is more normal in America) makes me wonder what nuances exist between them that can cause an identity crisis (is it another difference due to culture or more due to loyalty?).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-july-8th-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">636</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; July 1st Readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/15/primary-reader-july-1st-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/15/primary-reader-july-1st-readings/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 07:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=634</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Something I found interesting in Junaid Rana&#8217;s piece Racial Panic, Islamic Peril, and Terror was how the &#8216;moral panic&#8217; that spread through America in the aftermath of Sept. 11th was warped and transformed into a &#8216;racial panic&#8217; even though Muslim isn&#8217;t a race, it&#8217;s a religion. Something else I also found odd was how it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Something I found interesting in Junaid Rana&#8217;s piece <em>Racial Panic, Islamic Peril, and Terror</em> was how the &#8216;moral panic&#8217; that spread through America in the aftermath of Sept. 11th was warped and transformed into a &#8216;racial panic&#8217; even though Muslim isn&#8217;t a race, it&#8217;s a religion. Something else I also found odd was how it appeared that anybody perceived to be &#8216;Muslim&#8217; was subjected to the same racial profiling and treatment even though there were few documented cases of other Asians being mistaken for Japanese during World War 2. This is especially odd since it is easier to distinguish who is Muslim and who is not by their religious dress compared to being able to distinguish between the different Asian populations which could easily cause confusion.</p>
<p>In the case that Rana mentions of Homeland Security and the FBI attempting to locate five individuals who&#8217;s names and birth dates were possibly fictitious and were not likely to have terrorist affiliations according to the information they have so far, the vagueness of the situation allowed for the case to easily become a mass panic. This case I think especially highlights how easily and closely linked racialization and illegality is to terror and panic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/15/primary-reader-july-1st-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">634</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#8211; June 26th Readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-june-26th-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-june-26th-readings/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 05:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=631</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the Lisa Lowe&#8217;s Heterogeneity, Hybridity, and Multiplicity: Asian American Differences and Wanni Anderson and Robert G. Lee&#8217;s Asian American Displacements readings, it brought to mind an episode of Cold Case which embodied several of the elements we spoke about in class (online stream here: Cold Case Season 02 Episode 05). In this episode, there are brief references to what Lisa [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the Lisa Lowe&#8217;s <em>Heterogeneity, Hybridity, and Multiplicity: Asian American Differences</em> and Wanni Anderson and Robert G. Lee&#8217;s <em>Asian American Displacements</em> readings, it brought to mind an episode of Cold Case which embodied several of the elements we spoke about in class (online stream here: <a href="http://www.tubeplus.me/player/796073/Cold_Case/season_2/episode_5/Who's_Your_Daddy/">Cold Case Season 02 Episode 05</a>).</p>
<p>In this episode, there are brief references to what Lisa Lowe refers to as the idea of a homogeneous Asian American population and the different kinds of displacements experienced by Asians. For the first example, Brad Atwater (the victim&#8217;s boss) incorrectly refers to Channary Dhiet (the murdered wife) as &#8216;Miss Saigon&#8217; when in fact, the Dhiets are Cambodian. This plays into the misconception that Asians are all one population. For the second example, we look at Sen and Channary Dhiet (the murdered couple) who are physically, culturally, and psychologically displaced as a result of being Cambodian refugees. They are also socio-economically displaced rather than intellectually displaced as they were members of the royal family in Cambodia and in America they were illegal immigrants who ended up taking the identities of fellow immigrants to stay alive.</p>
<p>These brief references to several elements that have been mentioned in class display how vulnerable (Asian) immigrant populations are after they come to America. This episode reveals the darker possibilities of displacement and the susceptibility that displaced immigrants encounter.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/15/researcher-june-26th-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">631</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; June 19th Readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/25/primary-reader-june-19th-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/25/primary-reader-june-19th-readings/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 19:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=470</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Lisa Lowe&#8217;s Immigration, Citizenship, Racialization I thought it was interesting what Atitaya pointed out, that Lowe was equating culture to citizenship. It seemed like though that was what Lowe was intending, it wasn&#8217;t what was happening in America. Now matter how much of American culture an immigrant learns or absorbs, they are still defined [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Lisa Lowe&#8217;s <em>Immigration, Citizenship, Racialization</em> I thought it was interesting what Atitaya pointed out, that Lowe was equating culture to citizenship. It seemed like though that was what Lowe was intending, it wasn&#8217;t what was happening in America. Now matter how much of American culture an immigrant learns or absorbs, they are still defined by their race as &#8216;not American&#8217;. Culture can make one seem like an American, but politically, they were not.</p>
<p>In Leti Volpp&#8217;s <em>Obnoxious to Their Very Nature: Asian Americans and Constitutional Citizenship</em>, she pointed out how America seemed to always doubt the loyalty of an Asian (American) immigrant. No matter how long they&#8217;ve been in America, how small or distant their relation to anything considered anti-American, an Asian had a &#8216;connection&#8217; to their homeland. This phenomenon appeared to rise again in the wake of Sept. 11, when Muslims were targeted for their religion and race, wondering whether they were terrorist or sleeper cells. While &#8216;innocent citizens&#8217; enjoyed the freedoms and rights afforded by the Constitution, those who were governmental targets appeared to have &#8216;reduced&#8217; citizenship status because of their (non-existent) affiliation with an enemy. This happened not only after Sept. 11, but after Pearl Harbor, and the case of Wen Ho Lee.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/25/primary-reader-june-19th-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">470</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#8211; June 17th Readings &#8211; Coolies</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/25/researcher-june-17th-readings-coolies/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/25/researcher-june-17th-readings-coolies/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 18:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=467</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I thought it was interesting to find a coolie contract. We understand coolie labor as similar to slave labor, with the exception that they are paid (much less than a regular worker) and looking at a contract like this, I wonder how many workers actually understood what they were signing and whether they had any [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="alignnone" alt="" src="https://i0.wp.com/24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lvdx8rb5zG1r1rgjfo1_1280.jpg?resize=768%2C1159" data-recalc-dims="1" />
<p>I thought it was interesting to find a coolie contract. We understand coolie labor as similar to slave labor, with the exception that they are paid (much less than a regular worker) and looking at a contract like this, I wonder how many workers actually understood what they were signing and whether they had any legal recourse should their contracts be violated or broken.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/25/researcher-june-17th-readings-coolies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">467</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; Week 2 readings</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/10/primary-reader-week-2-readings/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/10/primary-reader-week-2-readings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 04:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Natalia Molina&#8217;s Fit to be Citizens? we see how racialization plays a role in public health and policies, immigration and public perception. In Los Angeles, officials used public health to further racial divides and perpetuate racial stereotypes; this racialization was also have been exacerbated by the conditions of a growing city. In Omi and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Natalia Molina&#8217;s <i>Fit to be Citizens?</i> we see how racialization plays a role in public health and policies, immigration and public perception. In Los Angeles, officials used public health to further racial divides and perpetuate racial stereotypes; this racialization was also have been exacerbated by the conditions of a growing city.</p>
<p>In Omi and Winant&#8217;s <i>Racial Formation</i> they propose that race is neither an &#8216;essence&#8217; nor a &#8216;mere illusion&#8217; but &#8216;a concept which signifies and symbolizes social conflicts and interests by referring to different types of human bodies.&#8217; It goes on to cover how race has affected policies.</p>
<p>These two articles discuss how race has affected public policy, perception, and politics. How does race affect them? By giving the public the concept of &#8216;outsiders&#8217;, people who don&#8217;t belong or can justifiably be excluded, we can create restrictions on immigration policies, limit public health programs, and create racial hierarchies without a public outcry because public perception is determined by government programs.</p>
<p>A lot of these stereotypes still haunt us today; even if we wish to remove all traces of racial categorization, the damage is done. When we think of the word &#8216;immigrant&#8217; a certain type of image comes to mind, when we look at certain people, certain stereotypes immediately come to the forefront.</p>
<p>Looking through the course of history, we can trace when any sort of conflict has targeted a specific race. Why then, can we not stop this cycle, even after hundreds of years of civilization?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/10/primary-reader-week-2-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">255</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#8211; Orientalism in Disney</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/05/researcher-orientalism-in-disney/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/05/researcher-orientalism-in-disney/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 03:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=230</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; I think this video helps clarify some of the concepts of Orientalism by using examples from Disney movies. These movies were made much later than the concept of Orientalism so a lot of the discrimination is downplayed but we still maintain these stereotypes adapted from Orientalism and discrimination.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='560' height='315' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/dLdzx9-H8Wg?version=3&#038;rel=0&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I think this video helps clarify some of the concepts of Orientalism by using examples from Disney movies. These movies were made much later than the concept of Orientalism so a lot of the discrimination is downplayed but we still maintain these stereotypes adapted from Orientalism and discrimination.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/05/researcher-orientalism-in-disney/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">230</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
