<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"

  >
<channel>
  <title>Comments on: Primary Reader 7/10 readings</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

  <item>
    <title>By: Gloria Cho</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/#comment-51</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 05:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=602#comment-51</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I feel like Yamashita’s I-Hotel is one of the hardest pieces we have to read in this course because it is just confusing.  Although it is a tough piece, the new format of writing that Yamashita uses is interesting because this is my first time reading a piece that is a combination of fictions, play, conversations, etc… I am agreed with Lucy that in Umemoto’s piece, when they said their students found those who lived the ethnic experience could best teach about it because they teach what they went through is the best.  Umemoto analyze the growth of political consciousness among Asian American students during the San Francisco State strike, and she analysis them separately in four different stages.  I think her piece is in an organize format and it is much easier to read compares to I-Hotel.  One thing that caught my attention is she talks about Freedom Riders of 1962 because I watched that movie in my other class, and the Freedom Riders tended to go on the road trip with mixed raced to protest about segregations betweens blacks and the whites.  I found it related to San Francisco Strike because these two groups both fighting for the equal rights and these two events helped us to shape into today’s America.  For the Aoyagi-Storm’s piece, it is interesting because this is my first time to hear about the Vincent Chin case just like Olivia Lin, and I am glad to hear about the CRAASH.  I have been in Hunter College for Five years and it is my first time to hear about the CRAASH and the author described the movement in details.  I found it interesting to read because it is related to us in Hunter College.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like Yamashita’s I-Hotel is one of the hardest pieces we have to read in this course because it is just confusing.  Although it is a tough piece, the new format of writing that Yamashita uses is interesting because this is my first time reading a piece that is a combination of fictions, play, conversations, etc… I am agreed with Lucy that in Umemoto’s piece, when they said their students found those who lived the ethnic experience could best teach about it because they teach what they went through is the best.  Umemoto analyze the growth of political consciousness among Asian American students during the San Francisco State strike, and she analysis them separately in four different stages.  I think her piece is in an organize format and it is much easier to read compares to I-Hotel.  One thing that caught my attention is she talks about Freedom Riders of 1962 because I watched that movie in my other class, and the Freedom Riders tended to go on the road trip with mixed raced to protest about segregations betweens blacks and the whites.  I found it related to San Francisco Strike because these two groups both fighting for the equal rights and these two events helped us to shape into today’s America.  For the Aoyagi-Storm’s piece, it is interesting because this is my first time to hear about the Vincent Chin case just like Olivia Lin, and I am glad to hear about the CRAASH.  I have been in Hunter College for Five years and it is my first time to hear about the CRAASH and the author described the movement in details.  I found it interesting to read because it is related to us in Hunter College.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>By: Linda He</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/#comment-44</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 04:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=602#comment-44</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I liked Storm&#039;s article because it helps with the discourse of the Asian American Studies Movement, and it was a report about a club within Hunter College. I did not know much about the club but knew it existing as flyers were handed out. I think it is interesting that the Asian American Studies Program was founded in 1993 but still has had trouble funding it. It was formed a lot earlier than I had thought but I think the program will help students see the multiplicity of Asian Americans. I think that the heterogeneity of the Asian population as well as the rejection that all Asian American populations are not the same are compelling ideas and could use more awareness. I took some Asian American Courses and it was really enlightening and so I think the Asian American Studies Program is really useful. I also think as the article reported, the fact that students are disinterested in the subject is invalid. I see the Asian American Studies Program as interesting and did not think that is was separate from any other academic departments. I like &quot;I-Hotel&quot; by Karen Tei Yamashita because it was creative in terms of recreating the atmosphere and the chaos but I thought that &quot;On Strike!San Francisco State College Strike, 1968-1969&quot; by Karen Umemoto was much more informative and easier to read in terms of understanding the beginnings of such an influential movement. I think it is great that a movement could have such a lasting impact and created a separate school - the School of Ethnic Studies.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I liked Storm&#8217;s article because it helps with the discourse of the Asian American Studies Movement, and it was a report about a club within Hunter College. I did not know much about the club but knew it existing as flyers were handed out. I think it is interesting that the Asian American Studies Program was founded in 1993 but still has had trouble funding it. It was formed a lot earlier than I had thought but I think the program will help students see the multiplicity of Asian Americans. I think that the heterogeneity of the Asian population as well as the rejection that all Asian American populations are not the same are compelling ideas and could use more awareness. I took some Asian American Courses and it was really enlightening and so I think the Asian American Studies Program is really useful. I also think as the article reported, the fact that students are disinterested in the subject is invalid. I see the Asian American Studies Program as interesting and did not think that is was separate from any other academic departments. I like &#8220;I-Hotel&#8221; by Karen Tei Yamashita because it was creative in terms of recreating the atmosphere and the chaos but I thought that &#8220;On Strike!San Francisco State College Strike, 1968-1969&#8221; by Karen Umemoto was much more informative and easier to read in terms of understanding the beginnings of such an influential movement. I think it is great that a movement could have such a lasting impact and created a separate school &#8211; the School of Ethnic Studies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
