<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"

  >
<channel>
  <title>Comments on: Primary Reader &#8211; Ono &#038; Pham, Lee, Jun</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/2013/06/12/primary-reader-ono-pham-lee-jun/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210/2013/06/12/primary-reader-ono-pham-lee-jun/</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

  <item>
    <title>By: Ryan McNeil</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/12/primary-reader-ono-pham-lee-jun/#comment-16</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 02:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=286#comment-16</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I found it interesting to see that many of the stereotypes of Asians that this post took from &quot;The Persistence of Yellow Peril Discourse&quot; are the same as stereotypes of other minority groups in America.  To me, this implies that many of the fears of growing minority groups spring simply from their being viewed as a threat to the established culture, and not from any specific cultural differences.  This understanding could help us predict how the same scenarios will play out in the future.

The point from &quot;The ‘Yellow Peril’ and Asian Exclusion in the Americas&quot; about the US interning Japanese living in other countries somewhat brings to mind the modern controversy over places like the Guantanamo Bay detention camp.  While the US could not get away with shoveling away masses based on ancestry, it does continue to detain individuals  from anywhere in the world without proper charges and without due process in the name of national security.

My last point is to ask whether similar action has ever been taken by other partially-assimilated races against more &quot;foreign&quot; races in America, and whether there is a pattern of this use of one racism to fight racism in American history.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I found it interesting to see that many of the stereotypes of Asians that this post took from &#8220;The Persistence of Yellow Peril Discourse&#8221; are the same as stereotypes of other minority groups in America.  To me, this implies that many of the fears of growing minority groups spring simply from their being viewed as a threat to the established culture, and not from any specific cultural differences.  This understanding could help us predict how the same scenarios will play out in the future.</p>
<p>The point from &#8220;The ‘Yellow Peril’ and Asian Exclusion in the Americas&#8221; about the US interning Japanese living in other countries somewhat brings to mind the modern controversy over places like the Guantanamo Bay detention camp.  While the US could not get away with shoveling away masses based on ancestry, it does continue to detain individuals  from anywhere in the world without proper charges and without due process in the name of national security.</p>
<p>My last point is to ask whether similar action has ever been taken by other partially-assimilated races against more &#8220;foreign&#8221; races in America, and whether there is a pattern of this use of one racism to fight racism in American history.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
