<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
  >

<channel>
  <title>Christie Ng &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/author/christieng/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <language>en-US</language>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>  <item>
    <title>Researcher- Week 3 (Lee,Ono, Jun)</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/15/researcher-week-3-leeono-jun/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/15/researcher-week-3-leeono-jun/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 01:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Christie Ng]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=339</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Ono and Pham&#8217;s article &#8220;The Persistence of Yellow Peril Discourse&#8221; included studying the media to show examples of how the concept of yellow peril has continued to this day. While looking for a more recent example of yellow peril, I found this article here. It saddens me to realize this article was made in May [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ono and Pham&#8217;s article &#8220;The Persistence of Yellow Peril Discourse&#8221; included studying the media to show examples of how the concept of yellow peril has continued to this day. While looking for a more recent example of yellow peril, I found this article <a href="http://blog.angryasianman.com/2013/05/what-does-this-racist-video-have-to-do.html" target="_blank">here</a>. It saddens me to realize this article was made in May 2013, only a month ago! Educating the public on what is and is not socially correct seems to be taking a very long time indeed. It makes one wonder why people know black face is not acceptable, but not yellow face.</p>
<p>While checking the news for news on campaigns, this video from last year (September 2012) came to mind for this topic <a href="http://abclocal.go.com/wabc/video?id=8665886" target="_blank">here</a>. It reveals that the Census Bureau&#8217;s data shows an increase in the number of babies being born to non-white ethnicities. That is a definite bit of information which should be celebrated, for there is concrete proof that all of the propaganda about white supremacy has no standing in the USA.</p>
<p>PS: Since I&#8217;m not sure of how to put a video on my blog post, it&#8217;s going to be an out-going link until I can figure WordPress out.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/15/researcher-week-3-leeono-jun/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">339</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Primary Reading, 6/5/13 (Said &#038; Shah)</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 03:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Christie Ng]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=185</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The texts of &#8220;Introduction&#8221; by Edawrd Said and &#8220;Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown&#8221; by Nyan Shah bring forth the volatile relationship seen between the Asian and Western cultures. Both texts present the Western culture as having an overbearing ideology that rejects and steps on anything that it does not support while exaggerating on [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The texts of &#8220;Introduction&#8221; by Edawrd Said and &#8220;Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown&#8221; by Nyan Shah bring forth the volatile relationship seen between the Asian and Western cultures. Both texts present the Western culture as having an overbearing ideology that rejects and steps on anything that it does not support while exaggerating on the desirable aspects. The author Said writes about exotic locations and sexual longings that the European men capitalize on. The Asian culture receives many hard blows for being different and has many slanderous remarks to fight against. Shah mentions the reporters of 19th century San Francisco wrote of Chinese immigrants living in cramped, disease-filled tenements as if it was something the immigrants had wanted to live in.</p>
<p>Edward Said&#8217;s piece is about &#8220;Orientalism&#8221;, which is the Western ideals of European countries defining the aspects that make up the Asian countries. Said paints an image of European men who measure every aspect of the lives of Asians by the yardstick of their own Western ideas. It is irritating to know that other cultures were being measured to the standards of another culture as if it was superior in any way. The only comfort that can come of this realisation is that in the future people do learn to make the effort to see the beliefs of many on their own terms and ways. I would like to question about the section in the text of politics influencing academic knowledge and its writers. Since many researchers would have wanted support for their work from whatever government group had money to bring out, could the words in these studies be fully trusted if there is a possibility of flattery? </p>
<p>Nyan Shah engages the reader with the loud arguements of San Francisco&#8217;s white population protesting against the Chinatowns and the dangers these places could have. Shah points out that &#8220;escalating anti-Chinese politics and the spector of epidemic disease&#8221; (171) had a hand in driving the public to hurt the immigrants living there. The implication of racism in these reasons show how American history keeps repeating itself many times over on who could be trusted. The Irish and African-Americans had been two other groups who faced persecution based on what others thought of their cultures and physical features. The image of being a group of dirty, diseased people is nothing new for all persecuted groups, but how can it end? Would education in all necessary areas be the only defense against the ignorance and hate that continues throughout the ages?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reading-6513-said-shah/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">185</post-id> </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
