<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"

  >
<channel>
  <title>Comments on: Primary Reader on 7/1 readings</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/2013/07/01/primary-reader-on-71-readings/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210/2013/07/01/primary-reader-on-71-readings/</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

  <item>
    <title>By: Gloria Cho</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/01/primary-reader-on-71-readings/#comment-34</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 05:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=517#comment-34</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The three readings we have to do on July 1st all focused on the racial problems brought up from the 9/11 and how do U.S. immigration policies changed to target on Muslim immigrants afterward.  For Rana’s piece, she basically talks about the racism towards Muslims after the 9/11 and how they were seen as “terrorist”.  She clearly states her meaning of moral panic in her piece and she tried to connect it to the orientalism placed on Asian immigrants, and how they were being stereotype by the western countries.  I am agreed that the connection of “yellow peril” of China and Japan in relation to the “Islam Peril” is interesting.  Western countries placed typical negative image to them and how they were treated differently under the law and government.  Besides moral panic, Rana mentioned a few theoretical theories connect to her thesis like racial formation, orientalism, transnational family structure, etc… I think Maira’s “Youth Culture Citizenship” focus on U.S. immigration acts after 9/11, which is different from Rana’s focus on moral panic.  She stated her meaning of “Flexible citizenship” and I found that interesting also.  Because it shows that there is less concern of citizenship toward the Asian groups after the 9/11 which caught my attention.  In Naber’s piece, there is one thing that I found interesting is the Japanese American community organizations expose the similar ties between the racist backlash against Japanese and Muslims in the U.S., how they were treated the same way after the attack of Pearl Harbor and World Trade Center.  The purpose of expose the connections is because JACL did not want the same thing happen on the Muslims again  and they did not want them to be seen as “ dangerous” just like how they were isolated in the concentration camps after the Pearl Harbor attack.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The three readings we have to do on July 1st all focused on the racial problems brought up from the 9/11 and how do U.S. immigration policies changed to target on Muslim immigrants afterward.  For Rana’s piece, she basically talks about the racism towards Muslims after the 9/11 and how they were seen as “terrorist”.  She clearly states her meaning of moral panic in her piece and she tried to connect it to the orientalism placed on Asian immigrants, and how they were being stereotype by the western countries.  I am agreed that the connection of “yellow peril” of China and Japan in relation to the “Islam Peril” is interesting.  Western countries placed typical negative image to them and how they were treated differently under the law and government.  Besides moral panic, Rana mentioned a few theoretical theories connect to her thesis like racial formation, orientalism, transnational family structure, etc… I think Maira’s “Youth Culture Citizenship” focus on U.S. immigration acts after 9/11, which is different from Rana’s focus on moral panic.  She stated her meaning of “Flexible citizenship” and I found that interesting also.  Because it shows that there is less concern of citizenship toward the Asian groups after the 9/11 which caught my attention.  In Naber’s piece, there is one thing that I found interesting is the Japanese American community organizations expose the similar ties between the racist backlash against Japanese and Muslims in the U.S., how they were treated the same way after the attack of Pearl Harbor and World Trade Center.  The purpose of expose the connections is because JACL did not want the same thing happen on the Muslims again  and they did not want them to be seen as “ dangerous” just like how they were isolated in the concentration camps after the Pearl Harbor attack.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>By: Linda He</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/01/primary-reader-on-71-readings/#comment-33</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 21:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=517#comment-33</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I think the last quote is interesting: &quot;the U.S. state and media have reproduced the historical contradictions of U.S. racial formations that fuel hate violence, while at the same time promoting tolerance and diversity&quot; (222). I think it is true that minorities have been discriminated such as East Asian and South Asian populations. Arab Americans and Muslim Americans have endured discrimination, especially the youth that Maira has mentioned. They grow up with a really prejudiced sense of citizenship because the wider population does not accept or think that they are worthy for a full set of rights or are not &quot;American&quot; enough. Even though the youth in America are not responsible for the crimes brought on by other populations of their homeland, they are still being treated like criminals and terrorists. They are racially slurred at as well as treated with hostility with chants that fuel racism. In this sense, the U.S. state and media have reproduced these contradictions of a free world because they do not seem to be taking big steps to stopping this kind of treatment or prejudice to these people. This type of treatment to even small minorities do not stop violence or promote values that should be &quot;American.&quot; Maira writes that they may never experience the same type of citizenship the law guarantees and for this reason, Arab-speaking populations are harshly marginalized in United States society. I think that U.S. racial formations in terms of categories may promote tolerance and diversity but they are essentially a euphemism toward a multiculturalistic way of thinking compared to the more realistic polyculturalism where not everyone benefits the same way. This highlights the unequal treatment and the unfair prejudice youth had to face post 9/11. Even after many years, the treatment does not stop for Muslim Americans or citizens of Middle Eastern descent.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think the last quote is interesting: &#8220;the U.S. state and media have reproduced the historical contradictions of U.S. racial formations that fuel hate violence, while at the same time promoting tolerance and diversity&#8221; (222). I think it is true that minorities have been discriminated such as East Asian and South Asian populations. Arab Americans and Muslim Americans have endured discrimination, especially the youth that Maira has mentioned. They grow up with a really prejudiced sense of citizenship because the wider population does not accept or think that they are worthy for a full set of rights or are not &#8220;American&#8221; enough. Even though the youth in America are not responsible for the crimes brought on by other populations of their homeland, they are still being treated like criminals and terrorists. They are racially slurred at as well as treated with hostility with chants that fuel racism. In this sense, the U.S. state and media have reproduced these contradictions of a free world because they do not seem to be taking big steps to stopping this kind of treatment or prejudice to these people. This type of treatment to even small minorities do not stop violence or promote values that should be &#8220;American.&#8221; Maira writes that they may never experience the same type of citizenship the law guarantees and for this reason, Arab-speaking populations are harshly marginalized in United States society. I think that U.S. racial formations in terms of categories may promote tolerance and diversity but they are essentially a euphemism toward a multiculturalistic way of thinking compared to the more realistic polyculturalism where not everyone benefits the same way. This highlights the unequal treatment and the unfair prejudice youth had to face post 9/11. Even after many years, the treatment does not stop for Muslim Americans or citizens of Middle Eastern descent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
