<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"

  >
<channel>
  <title>Comments on: primary reader &#8211; Omi, Winant &#038; Molina, Natalia&#8217;s articles</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/2013/06/09/primary-reader-omi-winant-molina-natalias-articles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210/2013/06/09/primary-reader-omi-winant-molina-natalias-articles/</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

  <item>
    <title>By: Linda He</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/09/primary-reader-omi-winant-molina-natalias-articles/#comment-9</link>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 15:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=250#comment-9</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[&quot;How does the racial formation theory evolve and draw less controversy?&quot; I think starting with the fierst few waves of immigration in the 1900&#039;s in search for better jobs or work cases some of the racial formations to take place. One racial for,action was who categorized as &quot;Mexican.&quot; In Molina&#039;s piece, she writes how white people saw potential in Mexicans to &quot;Americanize&quot; so they made &quot;Mexicans&quot; their own separate category. &quot;Mexican&quot; was categorized in that the population was considered everything that was &quot;non-white,&quot; &quot;non-Chinese,&quot; and &quot;non-Japanese.&quot; This racial formation was unique compared to other minorities where there was strictly &quot;Chinese&quot; and &quot;other.&quot; &quot;Chinese&quot; were looked at as foreign aliens, queer, and not assimilable in many depictions that were not just in media. White officials held some of their own sentiments and biases against these minorities after the &quot;Mexican&quot; population could not prosper as the White officials had hoped for. Instead, white officials, again, saw Mexcians as inassimilable, and economic burdens. Though the &quot;Mexican&quot; population was at first counted as subordinate, white officials saw only the &quot;Mexcian&quot; as able to &quot;Americanize&quot; when compared to &quot;Asian&quot; populations such as the &quot;Chinese&quot; and &quot;Japanese.&quot; In contrast, the &quot;Chinese&quot; racial formation came about to reinforce white hegemony as the definition of &quot;Chinese&quot; was alien. The only categories to defining &quot;Chinese-ness&quot; was &quot;Chinese&quot; and &quot;other.&quot; Molina writes &quot;Throughout the first half of the 1900&#039;s, city and country health officials tracked Mexcian communities more consistently than they did Chinese or Japanese populations.&quot; Although White officials thought Mexicans would be a &quot;fading&quot; race such as the Native Americans, they ultimately saw Mexcian populations as superior to Asian raves, but ultimately Whites and it&#039;s hegemony  ruled the racial hierarchy. This hegemony that is reinforced or helps with racial formation is evident in the laws that were based in legislation against Chinese and Japanese populations such as the &quot;Chinese Exclusion Act&quot; to slow down Chinese immigration, and &quot;Japanese&quot; internment after the bombing of Pearl Harbor. White hegemony was also referenced in health discourses, in addition to the legislation which Molina talks a lot about. Health discourses stereotype &quot;Mexican,&quot; &quot;Chinese,&quot; &quot;Japanese&quot; populations in San Francisco as &quot;dirty,&quot; &quot;disease-ridden,&quot; and &quot;disease-breeding.&quot;

&quot;How do we look beyond what races that cause sanitary issues and focus more on what can we do to fix the issues?&quot;
As Molina writes, there has to be a greater focus on helping with the structural changes of an unhealthy environment, but instead of white officials doing their duty, they reinforce their own biases to continue to perpetuate stereotypes and put down &quot;Asian&quot; as we&#039;ll as &quot;Mexican&quot; populations as inferior and subordinate. They are not doing their official duty to help get rid of disease and unhealthy conditions in apartments or living spaces, but instead target and examine more closely conditions that inevitablely would not change without an unbiased approach to solving the problem. I think Molina&#039;s conclusion was best when she writes using the negative &quot;descriptions&quot; and &quot;exclusions&quot; to make positive &quot;affirmations&quot; and &quot;empowerment.&quot;

I like how Molina&#039;s piece and Manalahassan IV&#039;s piece end on a positive note to fix unjust practices in the past.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;How does the racial formation theory evolve and draw less controversy?&#8221; I think starting with the fierst few waves of immigration in the 1900&#8217;s in search for better jobs or work cases some of the racial formations to take place. One racial for,action was who categorized as &#8220;Mexican.&#8221; In Molina&#8217;s piece, she writes how white people saw potential in Mexicans to &#8220;Americanize&#8221; so they made &#8220;Mexicans&#8221; their own separate category. &#8220;Mexican&#8221; was categorized in that the population was considered everything that was &#8220;non-white,&#8221; &#8220;non-Chinese,&#8221; and &#8220;non-Japanese.&#8221; This racial formation was unique compared to other minorities where there was strictly &#8220;Chinese&#8221; and &#8220;other.&#8221; &#8220;Chinese&#8221; were looked at as foreign aliens, queer, and not assimilable in many depictions that were not just in media. White officials held some of their own sentiments and biases against these minorities after the &#8220;Mexican&#8221; population could not prosper as the White officials had hoped for. Instead, white officials, again, saw Mexcians as inassimilable, and economic burdens. Though the &#8220;Mexican&#8221; population was at first counted as subordinate, white officials saw only the &#8220;Mexcian&#8221; as able to &#8220;Americanize&#8221; when compared to &#8220;Asian&#8221; populations such as the &#8220;Chinese&#8221; and &#8220;Japanese.&#8221; In contrast, the &#8220;Chinese&#8221; racial formation came about to reinforce white hegemony as the definition of &#8220;Chinese&#8221; was alien. The only categories to defining &#8220;Chinese-ness&#8221; was &#8220;Chinese&#8221; and &#8220;other.&#8221; Molina writes &#8220;Throughout the first half of the 1900&#8217;s, city and country health officials tracked Mexcian communities more consistently than they did Chinese or Japanese populations.&#8221; Although White officials thought Mexicans would be a &#8220;fading&#8221; race such as the Native Americans, they ultimately saw Mexcian populations as superior to Asian raves, but ultimately Whites and it&#8217;s hegemony  ruled the racial hierarchy. This hegemony that is reinforced or helps with racial formation is evident in the laws that were based in legislation against Chinese and Japanese populations such as the &#8220;Chinese Exclusion Act&#8221; to slow down Chinese immigration, and &#8220;Japanese&#8221; internment after the bombing of Pearl Harbor. White hegemony was also referenced in health discourses, in addition to the legislation which Molina talks a lot about. Health discourses stereotype &#8220;Mexican,&#8221; &#8220;Chinese,&#8221; &#8220;Japanese&#8221; populations in San Francisco as &#8220;dirty,&#8221; &#8220;disease-ridden,&#8221; and &#8220;disease-breeding.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;How do we look beyond what races that cause sanitary issues and focus more on what can we do to fix the issues?&#8221;<br />
As Molina writes, there has to be a greater focus on helping with the structural changes of an unhealthy environment, but instead of white officials doing their duty, they reinforce their own biases to continue to perpetuate stereotypes and put down &#8220;Asian&#8221; as we&#8217;ll as &#8220;Mexican&#8221; populations as inferior and subordinate. They are not doing their official duty to help get rid of disease and unhealthy conditions in apartments or living spaces, but instead target and examine more closely conditions that inevitablely would not change without an unbiased approach to solving the problem. I think Molina&#8217;s conclusion was best when she writes using the negative &#8220;descriptions&#8221; and &#8220;exclusions&#8221; to make positive &#8220;affirmations&#8221; and &#8220;empowerment.&#8221; </p>
<p>I like how Molina&#8217;s piece and Manalahassan IV&#8217;s piece end on a positive note to fix unjust practices in the past.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
