<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: 7/8 Primary Reader</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: Ryan McNeil</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/#comment-42</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 02:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=573#comment-42</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think Gloria covered the main point of today&#039;s readings and what ties them all together--the way Asian American movements were heavily influenced by these other movements at the time (1960s through the &#039;90s).  Like other non-African American minority movements at the time, Asian American movements were heavily influenced by the more popular black civil rights movement (1956-1968).  As covered by some of the readings from last week, Asian Americans had to deal with the stigma of &quot;communist&quot; even more so than other minority groups at the time due to the prevalence of communism in many parts of Asia.  Gloria also focused on a point I found to be particularly interesting too, the influence of Malcolm X on the Asian American side of the civil rights movement.  I think that the popularity of Malcolm X&#039;s teachings over those of MLK with the Asian American side of the civil rights movement crushes the model minority myth and the stereotype that Asian Americans would be more timid and politically quiet than other minorities.  The Omatsu article really outed all such stereotypes without having to attack them directly.  This unrecognized pride and strength is mirrored in Bruce Lee&#039;s decision (Prashad&#039;s article) and the adaptability and persistence of Asian communities (Aguirre&#039;s article), both brought up in Gloria&#039;s post.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think Gloria covered the main point of today&#8217;s readings and what ties them all together&#8211;the way Asian American movements were heavily influenced by these other movements at the time (1960s through the &#8217;90s).  Like other non-African American minority movements at the time, Asian American movements were heavily influenced by the more popular black civil rights movement (1956-1968).  As covered by some of the readings from last week, Asian Americans had to deal with the stigma of &#8220;communist&#8221; even more so than other minority groups at the time due to the prevalence of communism in many parts of Asia.  Gloria also focused on a point I found to be particularly interesting too, the influence of Malcolm X on the Asian American side of the civil rights movement.  I think that the popularity of Malcolm X&#8217;s teachings over those of MLK with the Asian American side of the civil rights movement crushes the model minority myth and the stereotype that Asian Americans would be more timid and politically quiet than other minorities.  The Omatsu article really outed all such stereotypes without having to attack them directly.  This unrecognized pride and strength is mirrored in Bruce Lee&#8217;s decision (Prashad&#8217;s article) and the adaptability and persistence of Asian communities (Aguirre&#8217;s article), both brought up in Gloria&#8217;s post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
