<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Primary Reader: Discourses of Exclusion</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/2013/06/12/primary-reader-discourses-of-exclusion/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210/2013/06/12/primary-reader-discourses-of-exclusion/</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: Akash Sharma</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/12/primary-reader-discourses-of-exclusion/#comment-15</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akash Sharma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 18:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=315#comment-15</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I also agree with Trevor&#039;s synthesis of the articles that we had to read for the week. I was very much interested in reading about the Asian in United States in Erika Lee&#039;s article titled &#039;Yellow Peril&#039;. Being an Anthro. undergrad, my main area of focus is also migration and specifically transnational migration and this article relates to it very well. 
   What Lee does in this article is examines the migration patterns of Asians to the United States and other countries in the same hemisphere. She also looks at the &quot;threat&quot; that this produces. Anyhow, I had the same reaction as Trevor&#039;s when Lee points out the hiring of Sikhs as police in Hong Kong. I think this is because Hong Kong as a Brtish territory during the time. India, at the same time was also occupied by the British and many Sikhs were part of their policing regiments. Because of this &#039;connectedness&#039; amongst two territories, we can observe  easier migration patterns; both by choice and by force.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I also agree with Trevor&#8217;s synthesis of the articles that we had to read for the week. I was very much interested in reading about the Asian in United States in Erika Lee&#8217;s article titled &#8216;Yellow Peril&#8217;. Being an Anthro. undergrad, my main area of focus is also migration and specifically transnational migration and this article relates to it very well.<br />
   What Lee does in this article is examines the migration patterns of Asians to the United States and other countries in the same hemisphere. She also looks at the &#8220;threat&#8221; that this produces. Anyhow, I had the same reaction as Trevor&#8217;s when Lee points out the hiring of Sikhs as police in Hong Kong. I think this is because Hong Kong as a Brtish territory during the time. India, at the same time was also occupied by the British and many Sikhs were part of their policing regiments. Because of this &#8216;connectedness&#8217; amongst two territories, we can observe  easier migration patterns; both by choice and by force.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Siyu (Lucy) Liu</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/12/primary-reader-discourses-of-exclusion/#comment-13</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 02:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=315#comment-13</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I agree with Trevor&#039;s comment about the Fast and Furious example in the Ono and Pham piece.  I haven&#039;t seen the first movie of the series but I rather enjoyed the 6th one that came out recently. I did not watch it because I had a sense of how Asian Americans are portrayed poorly in the film, but for the excitement and exceptional unrealistic racing skills. The character of Johnny Tran, sure, he might be part of the Asian American gang which isn&#039;t that popular after-all and has been depicted as a villain because of his actions in the sports compact scene and perhaps ill and egotistical attitude. But I don&#039;t think it portrays anything about the yellow peril discourse. The character of Tran could simply be anybody despite the race, since he is made up with the &quot;badass&quot; stereotype of any gang leader we see in movies. And I don&#039;t think it leaves any deceptive impressions because what else did we expect from gang leaders besides the acts of a villain? Also we see Asian American gang leaders in the Rush Hour series as well, etc.. Nothing stood out as illustrations of the yellow peril either.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I agree with Trevor&#8217;s comment about the Fast and Furious example in the Ono and Pham piece.  I haven&#8217;t seen the first movie of the series but I rather enjoyed the 6th one that came out recently. I did not watch it because I had a sense of how Asian Americans are portrayed poorly in the film, but for the excitement and exceptional unrealistic racing skills. The character of Johnny Tran, sure, he might be part of the Asian American gang which isn&#8217;t that popular after-all and has been depicted as a villain because of his actions in the sports compact scene and perhaps ill and egotistical attitude. But I don&#8217;t think it portrays anything about the yellow peril discourse. The character of Tran could simply be anybody despite the race, since he is made up with the &#8220;badass&#8221; stereotype of any gang leader we see in movies. And I don&#8217;t think it leaves any deceptive impressions because what else did we expect from gang leaders besides the acts of a villain? Also we see Asian American gang leaders in the Rush Hour series as well, etc.. Nothing stood out as illustrations of the yellow peril either.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Atitaya</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/12/primary-reader-discourses-of-exclusion/#comment-12</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Atitaya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 23:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=315#comment-12</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I agree with Trevor&#039;s analysis/conclusions about Lee&#039;s piece. To add on, I think Lee suggests that the anti-Asian movement was global, however, led by the U.S.. Additionally, I think Lee&#039;s key points centered around the key points of immigration, citizenship, and foreign policy. The instances of Asian exclusion were connected, and I believe the U.S. was the driving force behind the laws passed.
To add on to what Trevor wrote about the Ono &#038; Pham piece, the public&#039;s exposure to radical media certainly ignited negative feelings and attitudes towards Asian American that was possibly due to the lack of any actual interaction with an Asian American. Therefore, the general public was so easily influenced by media portrayals of Asian American rather than actual exposure to Asian American people. In addition, media influence is hard to remove from one&#039;s mind because it is made to make people remember. 
After the discussion in class of Jun&#039;s piece, I have a better understanding of her key ideas. Primarily, I think knowing that her argument was more about African American&#039;s demands of citizenship rather than being focused on Orientalism was important to know. Similarly to Trevor&#039;s response, I found this piece to be interesting because of the contradictions within the Black Orientalism relationship.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I agree with Trevor&#8217;s analysis/conclusions about Lee&#8217;s piece. To add on, I think Lee suggests that the anti-Asian movement was global, however, led by the U.S.. Additionally, I think Lee&#8217;s key points centered around the key points of immigration, citizenship, and foreign policy. The instances of Asian exclusion were connected, and I believe the U.S. was the driving force behind the laws passed.<br />
To add on to what Trevor wrote about the Ono &amp; Pham piece, the public&#8217;s exposure to radical media certainly ignited negative feelings and attitudes towards Asian American that was possibly due to the lack of any actual interaction with an Asian American. Therefore, the general public was so easily influenced by media portrayals of Asian American rather than actual exposure to Asian American people. In addition, media influence is hard to remove from one&#8217;s mind because it is made to make people remember.<br />
After the discussion in class of Jun&#8217;s piece, I have a better understanding of her key ideas. Primarily, I think knowing that her argument was more about African American&#8217;s demands of citizenship rather than being focused on Orientalism was important to know. Similarly to Trevor&#8217;s response, I found this piece to be interesting because of the contradictions within the Black Orientalism relationship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
