<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
  >

<channel>
  <title>Michelle Folvar &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/author/mfolvar/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <language>en-US</language>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>  <item>
    <title>July 1 – The War on Terror Primary Reader</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader-2/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader-2/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 16:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle Folvar]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=654</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The three texts read for the class discussion this week were based on the South Asian population, also often referred to as the Near East or Middle East in scholarly text, and their racial formation in the United States post 9/11. We have one piece by Sunaina Maira that is written about the Muslim youth [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The three texts read for the class discussion this week were based on the South Asian population, also often referred to as the Near East or Middle East in scholarly text, and their racial formation in the United States post 9/11. We have one piece by Sunaina Maira that is written about the Muslim youth of America in a narrative and interviewed format, an article by Nadine Naber written with heavy historical and referential context, and finally a piece by Junaid Rana concerning the moral panic and Muslim peril that engulfed the U.S. Post 9/11. All three articles juxtapose the ideas that after the attacked on the United States by terrorists on September 11<sup>th</sup>, a particular rise in racism and racial formation of the Asian populations that could be visible labeled as “Muslim terrorists” arose. They also heavily discuss the reason for the development of such practices historically as well as give ample examples of situations of how the State uses it&#8217;s authoritative power to instill fear and methods of control against the target population through news discourses, legal actions (i.e. Patriot Act), and selective exclusion of populations as we&#8217;ve seen repeated through history towards minorities. Even Naber makes such a correlation with the reference to the Japanese during World War II and their internments and prosecutions for similar circumstances and events as suffered by the Muslim people in our current era.</p>
<p>We also have new concepts introduced in these pieces, including the ideas of Flexible/Cultural/Multicultural Citizenship in relation to Muslim youth and their perspective, racial and moral peril that Muslims pose to America through the association of terrorism as a social, psychological and pathological entity of their ethnicity and culture, and the promotion of racial justice under the pretense of circumstance. All of these new ideas together promote the collective rationalization of dehumanizing and stereotyping the Muslim population in order to create a sense of rightness in regards to the wrong that had been dealt to the United States from the events of 9/11. Naber, Rana, and Maira agree that though this is how the nation and American people have developed, it is nonetheless immoral and criminal to behave this way and treat citizens in a manner that violated their basic human rights. Maira citizenship topics reflective of the documentary “Village Called Versailles” mentions of citizenship for Vietnamese Asians in America and their freedoms being diminished or outright ignored. These issues brought up an image of America that is, no matter how technologically advanced and innovative, backwards we can still be in terms of racial mentality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">654</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>June 24 – Pacific Wars Primary Reader</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 16:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle Folvar]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=648</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The two articles assigned for this week discuss in great detail the Asian American as a dichotomy of the Asian American model minority and the Asian American unassimilable immigrant. The model minority is a representation of a good immigrant living in a first world nation. For example, Palumbo-Liu and Lee both reference how this identity [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The two articles assigned for this week discuss in great detail the Asian American as a dichotomy of the Asian American model minority and the Asian American unassimilable immigrant. The model minority is a representation of a good immigrant living in a first world nation. For example, Palumbo-Liu and Lee both reference how this identity was given because the North Eastern Asian population living in the U.S. had these traits: Self reliance, family cohesion, good work ethic and emphasis on higher education, politically silent and emotionally calm. They also demonstrate the opposite side of the coin with the image of the unassimilable Asian as unwanted refugees and political scapegoats which varied depending on the years. We have this dynamic where the authors describe the Asian populations as both beloved and hated.</p>
<p>Many times, Lee describes the Asian in America “a<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif"><span style="font-size: medium">s the model of successful &#8220;ethnic assimilation&#8221; [that] was created in the crisis of racial policy that had surfaced at the highest levels of the federal government” (150) while Palumbo-Liu says “America&#8217;s &#8220;super minority&#8221;: They are smarter and better educated and make more money than everyone else. Now they are vaulting the last obstacles that stand between them and this country&#8217;s corner offices&#8221; (236). Then we have Lee describing their identity historical as “imperative to place all Asian migration, forced or not, under the same processes of assimilation and social subjectivity, despite tremendous historical differences” (235) or face racial discrimination and possible deportation, and Palumbo-Liu similarly “the historical reality of race in America as compelling logic for limiting civil rights into the economic sphere” (150) that developed the perspective with which Asian were often times viewed based on past events.</span></span></p>
<p>The two texts equally used various examples to support their works. Everything from news correspondences and political campaigning to movies and television was utilized. Both Palumbo and Lee referenced films and broke them down in summary with commentary on what scenes and character interactions represented the &#8216;Asian American&#8217; as well as delving into the topics of American perspectives of Asians and Asian Americans during relevant time periods. We had, particularly in Lee&#8217;s writings, the association of not only the Asian American and its duality, but also the mentions of many other fears that his movies examples highlighted. There were correlations the films had with anti-communist believes as well as the prevalence of homophobia and its developing social context. These two pieces were both linked with the ideas of discussing the Asian American image and the integration within the U.S. in the context of socially relevant circumstances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/22/july-1-the-war-on-terror-primary-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">648</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Research (Ono,Jun,Lee)</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/16/research-onojunlee/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/16/research-onojunlee/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 02:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle Folvar]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=374</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[http://colorblinding.tumblr.com/post/23593563622/afro-asian-history-black-orientalism A brief, but informative reading about Black Orientalism and Afro-Asian relations. In regards to last weeks conversation, I&#8217;ve been trying to find the video of the variety show I had mentioned, however, I believe it may have been taken down/or just disappeared. I did however, find an image still of the show&#8217;s performers in [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://colorblinding.tumblr.com/post/23593563622/afro-asian-history-black-orientalism">http://colorblinding.tumblr.com/post/23593563622/afro-asian-history-black-orientalism</a></p>
<p>A brief, but informative reading about Black Orientalism and Afro-Asian relations.</p>
<p>In regards to last weeks conversation, I&#8217;ve been trying to find the video of the variety show I had mentioned, however, I believe it may have been taken down/or just disappeared. I did however, find an image still of the show&#8217;s performers in their &#8220;black makeup&#8221; &#8211;</p>
<p><a href="http://imagesearch.naver.com/search.naver?sm=ext&amp;viewloc=1&amp;where=idetail&amp;rev=17&amp;query=%EC%8B%9C%EC%BB%A4%EB%A8%BC%EC%8A%A4&amp;section=image&amp;sort=0&amp;res_fr=0&amp;res_to=0&amp;start=2&amp;ie=utf8&amp;img_id=news0730002230947_1&amp;face=0&amp;color=0&amp;ccl=0&amp;viewtype=0&amp;aq=0&amp;spq=0&amp;nx_search_query=%EC%8B%9C%EC%BB%A4%EB%A8%BC%EC%8A%A4&amp;nx_and_query=&amp;nx_sub_query=&amp;nx_search_hlquery=&amp;nx_search_fasquery=">http://imagesearch.naver.com/search.naver?sm=ext&amp;viewloc=1&amp;where=idetail&amp;rev=17&amp;query=%EC%8B%9C%EC%BB%A4%EB%A8%BC%EC%8A%A4&amp;section=image&amp;sort=0&amp;res_fr=0&amp;res_to=0&amp;start=2&amp;ie=utf8&amp;img_id=news0730002230947_1&amp;face=0&amp;color=0&amp;ccl=0&amp;viewtype=0&amp;aq=0&amp;spq=0&amp;nx_search_query=%EC%8B%9C%EC%BB%A4%EB%A8%BC%EC%8A%A4&amp;nx_and_query=&amp;nx_sub_query=&amp;nx_search_hlquery=&amp;nx_search_fasquery=</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/16/research-onojunlee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">374</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Primary Reader &#8211; Racial Capital, Racial Hierarchy (Jung, Kim)</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/16/primary-reader-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy-jung-kim/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/16/primary-reader-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy-jung-kim/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 02:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle Folvar]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=370</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The two articles assigned to for this week&#8217;s reading has to do with the stance that Asian immigrants and Americans are a race of people that fall in between the two bipolar classifications of race, Black and White, and how their status has initially been viewed, altered and eventually challenged the viewpoints of racial hierarchy, [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The two articles assigned to for this week&#8217;s reading has to do with the stance that Asian immigrants and Americans are a race of people that fall in between the two bipolar classifications of race, Black and White, and how their status has initially been viewed, altered and eventually challenged the viewpoints of racial hierarchy, especially in reference to the labor force. There are also recurring themes such as Erika Lee&#8217;s ideas about the globalism of Asian immigrants, as well as references to Jun&#8217;s Black Orientalism and how Asians were compared to blacks, though these articles cover the white viewpoints on this particular issue.</p>
<p>In the Jung Moon Ho article, we have a piece written from a sort-of biographical, historic perspective about the spread of Asian Americans throughout the world, the global expansion of these people into the Caribbean and the US. The author states his article was originally meant to be a study of plantation workers in Louisiana, but expanding into the Asian American coolie historic transmutation and origins into the Americas. He talks about the different elements in the local, national, and transnational scope that created and continuously redefined the coolie culture in the Americas as well as how they embodied the hopes, fears and contradictions of emancipation (Jung 5). Jung goes to great lengths to demonstrate how the immigrating Asians, the “coolies”, were wanted for their promise of cheap labor in the South for work that was undesirable by European immigrants, while being fiercely chastised by the North because of their apathetic nature towards their own enslavement and the South who would use them as such. It was interesting to read, however, that in the attempts to present the “Chinaman” as a free willed, immigrating laborer, there were brief mentions of equality that would be afforded the Asian immigrant because he is “intelligent and who is not able to get along at first with us because he is a stranger;” but as soon as he acquaints himself with American customs and language, laws and courses of business, “he will ask for equal privileges and shall get them” (Jung 115). Even as we&#8217;ve seen through history and the many mentions in class of unequal treatment, the use of such promising lies by Southern Asian Labor proprietors in order to achieve their means is subtly reflective of the country&#8217;s belief in a free nation.</p>
<p>Claire Jean Kim&#8217;s article is theoretical research piece that discusses the methods by which Asian Americans have been delegated into an “in-between” class of people, especially in reference to the Black and White historical dynamic. There are familiar definitions in the article, such as how race as a culture is conceived and is intrinsically fluid, changing, unstable and dynamic (Kim 107) or Omi and Winant&#8217;s ideas concerning social constructs, but also new ideas about the racial triangulation that Asians and Asian Americans have had to endure. Like Jung&#8217;s article, we have a portion of this text presented in reference to the cheap labor that Asians provided, and how their status in terms of this dilemma that was facing the US further encompassed their position in this racial triangulation between the White/Black polarity. They were deemed intelligent and hard working, but calmer and more complacent than their black counterparts and inexpensive; their status as temporary, alien and unattainable in terms of citizenship along with all the yellow peril imagery left the Asian immigrant as a perfect pawn for the labor needy US society, particularly in the South. Further on in the article, we have various historic examples of media presentation and legal affirmation of Asian American racism in various situation, encompassing the theme of empowerment for racial minorities. Overall, these two articles sum up the historical use of Asian immigrants for cheap labor, but also as focus on them an alien race that is incapable of assimilation in a bipolar viewpoint in history&#8217;s longstanding racial battle of Black and White.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/16/primary-reader-racial-capital-racial-hierarchy-jung-kim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">370</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>First Reading &#8211; Shah and Said&#8217;s Asian/Oriental &#8220;Other&#8221;</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/04/first-reading-shah-and-saids-asianoriental-other/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/first-reading-shah-and-saids-asianoriental-other/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle Folvar]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=171</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The two readings done for today&#8217;s class involve the concepts of “the other” in the eyes of the class-ruling population of Caucasians during the 1800s and modern era. During both time periods, there is a distinct reference to the social and economical events in relation to the concept of “the other”; for the Shah reading, [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The two readings done for today&#8217;s class involve the concepts of “the other” in the eyes of the class-ruling population of Caucasians during the 1800s and modern era. During both time periods, there is a distinct reference to the social and economical events in relation to the concept of “the other”; for the Shah reading, the weight falls on the shoulders of the Chinese community of San Francisco and its Chinatown during the nineteenth century while Said&#8217;s general focus is the Orient itself, collectively bundling the Asian and Eurasian communities into a whole representing foreignness, exoticism, and often times barbarism to the White and European realm.</p>
<p>Shah&#8217;s publication is written as a critical review, taking investigations, textual references (both medical and historic), and other captious materials in creating a world of the past for those of us in the modern day. Though it seems unclear who his exact audience is, the piece is appropriate for those interested in the public health sphere in general, as well as students, social science professionals and researchers intrigued with the issues of Asian communities as a target for racism, political scapegoating and oppression in the nineteenth century. The author chooses to present his arguments in a analytic manner seen in research papers, giving basis around the idea of dirty, diseased and inhuman Chinese immigrants and how they were victimized to direct problems of corruption and economic hardships unto them. We see government and elective roles using and abusing the Chinese population to fund their own ends and to create greater disparity between the average middle class whites and the immigrant lower class Asians, and the author asks us why they were able to get away with such clearly biased and discriminatory behavior during this time period. Comparative to today&#8217;s San Francisco, though I myself have never been there to be sure, it can be assumed that the communities of Asian Americans have been able to evolve passed the repression and disparities that once plagued the areas of Chinatown.</p>
<p>By the same token, we have Said who takes the concept of Orientalism, or the difference of everything cultural and historical from that of the Western world, and molds it into a view of the same foreignness as Shah, but with reference to its almost subsidiary nature in the eyes Westerners through its romanticism and standing as colonial properties to European oppressors. It should be noted that the author states this is not a state of total imposed oppression however because such concepts cannot stand for long periods of time without reinforcement from both institutions of higher learning, government policy and understanding, and a lack of rebuttal or ambivalence from the locations deemed the Orient itself. Said&#8217;s focus is on providing a guide of sorts for the scholar or student interested in the concept of the Orient, or that which is opposite to the Occidental’s perspective, as well as detailing a history and knowledge about what makes the construct of Orientalism real and functioning for the time he is writing about, the past into the late 1980s. He questions of why we have this abstract creation of the Orient to begin with and explains how he as an attempted “individual” tries to view the argument despite carrying political and slanted views that typically color an objective argument. He also poses many questions concerning the dynamic which drives the Orient into a setting of historic, lexicographic, biological, economical and political context, again in reference to the omnipresent Western perspective.  Overall, these two works written are focused on the same idea of otherness to a reader and show inequalities that often times occurred within studies involving the communities of Asian and Asian Americans.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/first-reading-shah-and-saids-asianoriental-other/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">171</post-id> </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
