<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments for Asians in the U.S.</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/comments/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Researcher June 24th &#8211; &#8220;LIFE&#8221; Magazine and &#8220;Japanese War Bride&#8221; film by Shirley Yamaguchi (1920-2014) &#124; Bunnybun&#039;s Classic Movie Blog</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/23/httpwww-english-illinois-edumapspoetsa_ffosterlifemag-htmhttpwww-english-illinois-edumapspoetsa_ffosterlifemag-htm/#comment-87</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shirley Yamaguchi (1920-2014) &#124; Bunnybun&#039;s Classic Movie Blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=420#comment-87</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] I immediately recognized her name because I still remember parts of the King Vidor directed movie Japanese War Bride, a movie I saw on TV when I was about ten years [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] I immediately recognized her name because I still remember parts of the King Vidor directed movie Japanese War Bride, a movie I saw on TV when I was about ten years [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Primary Reader #01 by Katherine Sullivan</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/28/primary-reader-01/#comment-52</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Sullivan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 03:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=501#comment-52</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Not to mention that guy who served his sentence, got back to his life for a few years, started a family, then when he went to apply for citizenship they suddenly deported him. I felt bad for him.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not to mention that guy who served his sentence, got back to his life for a few years, started a family, then when he went to apply for citizenship they suddenly deported him. I felt bad for him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Primary Reader 7/10 readings by Gloria Cho</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/#comment-51</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 05:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=602#comment-51</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I feel like Yamashita’s I-Hotel is one of the hardest pieces we have to read in this course because it is just confusing.  Although it is a tough piece, the new format of writing that Yamashita uses is interesting because this is my first time reading a piece that is a combination of fictions, play, conversations, etc… I am agreed with Lucy that in Umemoto’s piece, when they said their students found those who lived the ethnic experience could best teach about it because they teach what they went through is the best.  Umemoto analyze the growth of political consciousness among Asian American students during the San Francisco State strike, and she analysis them separately in four different stages.  I think her piece is in an organize format and it is much easier to read compares to I-Hotel.  One thing that caught my attention is she talks about Freedom Riders of 1962 because I watched that movie in my other class, and the Freedom Riders tended to go on the road trip with mixed raced to protest about segregations betweens blacks and the whites.  I found it related to San Francisco Strike because these two groups both fighting for the equal rights and these two events helped us to shape into today’s America.  For the Aoyagi-Storm’s piece, it is interesting because this is my first time to hear about the Vincent Chin case just like Olivia Lin, and I am glad to hear about the CRAASH.  I have been in Hunter College for Five years and it is my first time to hear about the CRAASH and the author described the movement in details.  I found it interesting to read because it is related to us in Hunter College.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like Yamashita’s I-Hotel is one of the hardest pieces we have to read in this course because it is just confusing.  Although it is a tough piece, the new format of writing that Yamashita uses is interesting because this is my first time reading a piece that is a combination of fictions, play, conversations, etc… I am agreed with Lucy that in Umemoto’s piece, when they said their students found those who lived the ethnic experience could best teach about it because they teach what they went through is the best.  Umemoto analyze the growth of political consciousness among Asian American students during the San Francisco State strike, and she analysis them separately in four different stages.  I think her piece is in an organize format and it is much easier to read compares to I-Hotel.  One thing that caught my attention is she talks about Freedom Riders of 1962 because I watched that movie in my other class, and the Freedom Riders tended to go on the road trip with mixed raced to protest about segregations betweens blacks and the whites.  I found it related to San Francisco Strike because these two groups both fighting for the equal rights and these two events helped us to shape into today’s America.  For the Aoyagi-Storm’s piece, it is interesting because this is my first time to hear about the Vincent Chin case just like Olivia Lin, and I am glad to hear about the CRAASH.  I have been in Hunter College for Five years and it is my first time to hear about the CRAASH and the author described the movement in details.  I found it interesting to read because it is related to us in Hunter College.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Primary Reader: Asian American Studies by Trevor O'Mara</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-asian-american-studies-2/#comment-50</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Trevor O'Mara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 04:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=595#comment-50</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The CRAASH article and Umemoto piece really illustrate the potential effectiveness of large groups of loud people -- something we&#039;d all do well to remember once in a while.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The CRAASH article and Umemoto piece really illustrate the potential effectiveness of large groups of loud people &#8212; something we&#8217;d all do well to remember once in a while.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Primary Reader 7/3 by Kristina Szeto</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/02/primary-reader-73/#comment-49</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 08:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=532#comment-49</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Between Ryan and Trevor&#039;s summation of Parrenas&#039; article, there&#039;s a bit of a question I have coming up surrounding reproductive labor: Is it a consequence of socio-economic class stratification or is it more due to a cultural difference instead?

If it is a consequence of socio-economic class difference, then does race have an effect on whether reproductive labor is used in the household? If it is not due to socio-economic class differences and more due to cultural differences, then how does that affect the way we see reproductive labor?

I like to think that reproductive labor is a consequence of these various factors playing off each other, a push and pull interrelationship. The first factor being socio-economic status, we understand that wealthy people tend to take advantage of their wealth to foist the reproductive labor responsibility onto their hired help. But it isn&#039;t only the wealthy who do so. Babysitters can also be considered reproductive labor, if only a pale comparison of such, and even those in the lower-income brackets use a different type of reproductive labor: their support system. Lower income families may not pay for the reproductive labor they use because they tend to turn towards their support system for these needs: usually family or close friends who do not mind doing the service for free.

The second factor that affects reproductive labor is race. Reproductive labor tends to be minority women, but those who pay for reproductive labor tend to be rich white women/families. Going down the socio-economic ladder, the percentages shift with the type of reproductive labor: babysitters primarily used by middle-income white and American-assimilated minorities while support systems are used by those with low-income or those who value a support system as part of their culture, the third factor.

Culture appears similar but is markedly different from race: while one may be of a particular race, they may be of a completely different culture. Many cultures emphasize familial bonds - it appears American culture values familial bonds with certain lifestyles or certain financial statuses (bringing us back to the first factor). When a family is considered rich, the expectations for the kind of lifestyle the members lead and have are dictated by the money they have. Likewise, culture tends to dictate the kind of reproductive labor one uses. As the culture adopted by the individual approaches American culture more and more, we can see more and more how they also adopt the standards American culture has for reproductive labor.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Between Ryan and Trevor&#8217;s summation of Parrenas&#8217; article, there&#8217;s a bit of a question I have coming up surrounding reproductive labor: Is it a consequence of socio-economic class stratification or is it more due to a cultural difference instead?</p>
<p>If it is a consequence of socio-economic class difference, then does race have an effect on whether reproductive labor is used in the household? If it is not due to socio-economic class differences and more due to cultural differences, then how does that affect the way we see reproductive labor?</p>
<p>I like to think that reproductive labor is a consequence of these various factors playing off each other, a push and pull interrelationship. The first factor being socio-economic status, we understand that wealthy people tend to take advantage of their wealth to foist the reproductive labor responsibility onto their hired help. But it isn&#8217;t only the wealthy who do so. Babysitters can also be considered reproductive labor, if only a pale comparison of such, and even those in the lower-income brackets use a different type of reproductive labor: their support system. Lower income families may not pay for the reproductive labor they use because they tend to turn towards their support system for these needs: usually family or close friends who do not mind doing the service for free.</p>
<p>The second factor that affects reproductive labor is race. Reproductive labor tends to be minority women, but those who pay for reproductive labor tend to be rich white women/families. Going down the socio-economic ladder, the percentages shift with the type of reproductive labor: babysitters primarily used by middle-income white and American-assimilated minorities while support systems are used by those with low-income or those who value a support system as part of their culture, the third factor.</p>
<p>Culture appears similar but is markedly different from race: while one may be of a particular race, they may be of a completely different culture. Many cultures emphasize familial bonds &#8211; it appears American culture values familial bonds with certain lifestyles or certain financial statuses (bringing us back to the first factor). When a family is considered rich, the expectations for the kind of lifestyle the members lead and have are dictated by the money they have. Likewise, culture tends to dictate the kind of reproductive labor one uses. As the culture adopted by the individual approaches American culture more and more, we can see more and more how they also adopt the standards American culture has for reproductive labor.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Primary Reader 6/24 by Kristina Szeto</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/23/primary-reader-624/#comment-48</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristina Szeto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 04:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=452#comment-48</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think that the idea of Asians being a model minority really affects the way that other minorities - not just Asians - are treated and it&#039;s still relevant today. One example of such is the controversial Stop-and-Frisk program by the NYPD. This procedure involves police officers stopping people they believe are acting suspicious (relating to criminal activity or property). The program is gender and race-neutral, but the implementation of the program appears to have been skewed by racial profiling.

     A majority of the people stopped by police officers are of African-American or Latino descent, with a markedly smaller percentage of white or other minorities being stopped. This plays into the model minority myth by unofficially reinforcing the idea of a &#039;model minority&#039;, particularly Asians. People believe in the model minority myth and as a result Asians aren&#039;t subject to the same racial treatment as other minorities.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think that the idea of Asians being a model minority really affects the way that other minorities &#8211; not just Asians &#8211; are treated and it&#8217;s still relevant today. One example of such is the controversial Stop-and-Frisk program by the NYPD. This procedure involves police officers stopping people they believe are acting suspicious (relating to criminal activity or property). The program is gender and race-neutral, but the implementation of the program appears to have been skewed by racial profiling.</p>
<p>     A majority of the people stopped by police officers are of African-American or Latino descent, with a markedly smaller percentage of white or other minorities being stopped. This plays into the model minority myth by unofficially reinforcing the idea of a &#8216;model minority&#8217;, particularly Asians. People believe in the model minority myth and as a result Asians aren&#8217;t subject to the same racial treatment as other minorities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Researcher for 7/10 by Kevin Han</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/10/researcher-for-710/#comment-47</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Han]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 04:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=592#comment-47</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[(CONTINUED)
Also I think that the students activists are powerful and strong in some ways because they are all educated and have got specific ideas and motivation for their goals. Nothing is powerful than fully motivated ones.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(CONTINUED)<br />
Also I think that the students activists are powerful and strong in some ways because they are all educated and have got specific ideas and motivation for their goals. Nothing is powerful than fully motivated ones.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Researcher for 7/10 by Kevin Han</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/10/researcher-for-710/#comment-46</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Han]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 04:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=592#comment-46</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think that the most of the student activism is related to civil rights and it is very interesting that the students are being a huge part of fights for civil rights.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think that the most of the student activism is related to civil rights and it is very interesting that the students are being a huge part of fights for civil rights.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Primary Reader #03 by Katherine Sullivan</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/09/primary-reader-03/#comment-45</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Sullivan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 06:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=594#comment-45</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Spaces of Mobilizations” is an introductionary essay to a larger book on the same subject, so it makes sense that it would be mostly informative and summarizing. That said, with the way it’s structured, I felt like to some extent its argument is “here are some of the many ways Asian Americans have been involved in social justice in both the past and present, but today there are people who are convinced it never happened, doesn’t matter, and isn’t needed anymore.”

I found “The Four Prisons” to be very thought-provoking with regards to what the protests and movements of the 60s were about and how they’re interpreted. I can&#039;t remember if I already knew that Asian Americans were involved in politics, but if I did know I rarely heard about it, or them, at all, when I read about social movements.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Spaces of Mobilizations” is an introductionary essay to a larger book on the same subject, so it makes sense that it would be mostly informative and summarizing. That said, with the way it’s structured, I felt like to some extent its argument is “here are some of the many ways Asian Americans have been involved in social justice in both the past and present, but today there are people who are convinced it never happened, doesn’t matter, and isn’t needed anymore.”</p>
<p>I found “The Four Prisons” to be very thought-provoking with regards to what the protests and movements of the 60s were about and how they’re interpreted. I can&#8217;t remember if I already knew that Asian Americans were involved in politics, but if I did know I rarely heard about it, or them, at all, when I read about social movements.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Primary Reader 7/10 readings by Linda He</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/#comment-44</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda He]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 04:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=602#comment-44</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I liked Storm&#039;s article because it helps with the discourse of the Asian American Studies Movement, and it was a report about a club within Hunter College. I did not know much about the club but knew it existing as flyers were handed out. I think it is interesting that the Asian American Studies Program was founded in 1993 but still has had trouble funding it. It was formed a lot earlier than I had thought but I think the program will help students see the multiplicity of Asian Americans. I think that the heterogeneity of the Asian population as well as the rejection that all Asian American populations are not the same are compelling ideas and could use more awareness. I took some Asian American Courses and it was really enlightening and so I think the Asian American Studies Program is really useful. I also think as the article reported, the fact that students are disinterested in the subject is invalid. I see the Asian American Studies Program as interesting and did not think that is was separate from any other academic departments. I like &quot;I-Hotel&quot; by Karen Tei Yamashita because it was creative in terms of recreating the atmosphere and the chaos but I thought that &quot;On Strike!San Francisco State College Strike, 1968-1969&quot; by Karen Umemoto was much more informative and easier to read in terms of understanding the beginnings of such an influential movement. I think it is great that a movement could have such a lasting impact and created a separate school - the School of Ethnic Studies.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I liked Storm&#8217;s article because it helps with the discourse of the Asian American Studies Movement, and it was a report about a club within Hunter College. I did not know much about the club but knew it existing as flyers were handed out. I think it is interesting that the Asian American Studies Program was founded in 1993 but still has had trouble funding it. It was formed a lot earlier than I had thought but I think the program will help students see the multiplicity of Asian Americans. I think that the heterogeneity of the Asian population as well as the rejection that all Asian American populations are not the same are compelling ideas and could use more awareness. I took some Asian American Courses and it was really enlightening and so I think the Asian American Studies Program is really useful. I also think as the article reported, the fact that students are disinterested in the subject is invalid. I see the Asian American Studies Program as interesting and did not think that is was separate from any other academic departments. I like &#8220;I-Hotel&#8221; by Karen Tei Yamashita because it was creative in terms of recreating the atmosphere and the chaos but I thought that &#8220;On Strike!San Francisco State College Strike, 1968-1969&#8221; by Karen Umemoto was much more informative and easier to read in terms of understanding the beginnings of such an influential movement. I think it is great that a movement could have such a lasting impact and created a separate school &#8211; the School of Ethnic Studies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
