<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Gloria Cho &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
	<atom:link href="/asam210/author/gcho/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/asam210</link>
	<description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>	<item>
		<title>Primary Reader on June 26th</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 04:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=660</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Asian American Displacements” by Wanni Anderson and Robert Lee focus on a few frame works including what Asian Americanists study about, the relationship between Asian settlement and the patterns of American history and society, Asian immigrant workers’ role in shaping both the land and social terrain, the connection between American imperialism and the trajectories of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Asian American Displacements” by Wanni Anderson and Robert Lee focus on a few frame works including what Asian Americanists study about, the relationship between Asian settlement and the patterns of American history and society, Asian immigrant workers’ role in shaping both the land and social terrain, the connection between American imperialism and the trajectories of class, race and gender in the U.S. What I found interesting is their idea of four forms of displacement which is including the refugee, the exile, the expatriate, and the migrant.  These four forms have to deal with physical, cultural, psychological, and the intellectual displacement.  The structure of this piece is interesting because it contains a collection of scholar’s references to support their central idea.</p>
<p>In the other piece “Deporting Cambodian Refugees: Youth Activism, State Reform, and Imperial Statecraft” by Soo Ah Kwon is a case study and it includes author’s experience with the AYPAL youth and their campaign to put an end to deportations.  First she chronicles young people’s direct engagement with the state and the political process, and second, “I critically examine how, in confronting the limits of their relationship to the state, AYPAL youth uncovered that the neoliberal state is an imperial state” (Kwon 739).  I think Kwon’s piece is so different from the other pieces we have read because it actually based on author’s own experience in a case study.  Her topic of deportation of Asians got caught my attention because I did not know how these South Asians are living unfairly before I read her article.  She includes documentations in her piece.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/24/primary-reader-on-june-26th/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">660</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>7/8 Primary Reader</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 06:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=573</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the three readings we have to do before class, they are focused on the civil rights movements toward Asians in American and how they tried to achieve their goal and gained their rights along with the movements.  In Aguirre’s piece “Spaces of Mobilization: The Asian American/Pacific Islander Struggle for Social Justice” started with a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the three readings we have to do before class, they are focused on the civil rights movements toward Asians in American and how they tried to achieve their goal and gained their rights along with the movements.  In Aguirre’s piece “Spaces of Mobilization: The Asian American/Pacific Islander Struggle for Social Justice” started with a brief summary of what Asians American went through, like how the society changed their attitudes and point of view toward them changed over time and incidents.  The frame work of this piece is “Space of Mobilization” and the definition is “Space constitutes and structures the processes that produce race, class, and gender identities”.  This piece mainly focuses on how Asians Americans tried to expand their “space” with movements.  In the other article “The ‘Four Prisons’ and the Movements of Liberation” by Glenn Omatsu stated that Asian American movement coincided not with Martin Luther King Jr’s initial campaign for civil rights but with Malcom X’s black liberation.  .Omatsu discussed how Asian American identity changed from the inspiration of activists from 1960s to 1990s.  Prashad’s “Kung Fusion – Organize the ‘Hood Under I-Ching Banners’” is different compares to Omatsu and Aguirre’s piece because Prashad talks about Bruce Lee as an Chinese American to bring out the theme of “orientalism”. “Imperalism”, “Liberation”, etc…Bruce Lee was born in the U.S. but raised in Hong Kong and starred in over twenty movies before he went back to the U.S. for college.  He refused to be an idol for Caucasians because of his strong identity of &#8220;yellow-faced Chinese&#8221;.   But what make these three pieces together is these authors tried to tell us the readers how Asian American movements were under the influence of Marxism, &#8220;Black Maoism&#8221;, and Malcolm X’s black liberation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/08/78-primary-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher 7/3</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/07/03/researcher-73/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/07/03/researcher-73/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 06:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resources]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=544</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/shortsighted-demagogue-who-played-the-race-card-idi-amin-expelled-the-asians-20-years-ago-richard-dowden-africa-editor-explains-why-the-decision-was-supported-by-ugandans-1538196.html The link above is an article about the expelled of Asians in Uganda in 1972 by Idi Amin, it tells us the reason why president Idi Amin explained his reason for the this act is because he thinks Asians in Uganda threaten their economy and encouraging corruption.  He stated an interesting example that Asians [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/shortsighted-demagogue-who-played-the-race-card-idi-amin-expelled-the-asians-20-years-ago-richard-dowden-africa-editor-explains-why-the-decision-was-supported-by-ugandans-1538196.html">http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/shortsighted-demagogue-who-played-the-race-card-idi-amin-expelled-the-asians-20-years-ago-richard-dowden-africa-editor-explains-why-the-decision-was-supported-by-ugandans-1538196.html</a></p>
<p>The link above is an article about the expelled of Asians in Uganda in 1972 by Idi Amin, it tells us the reason why president Idi Amin explained his reason for the this act is because he thinks Asians in Uganda threaten their economy and encouraging corruption.  He stated an interesting example that Asians were living there for 70 years and only six Asian women had married to Ugandan men, and he thinks that is one of the examples of how Asian Ugandan were not trusting in Uganda.  Even though some of them have gained Ugandan citizenship but they still living in Asians areas in the towns and not mix socially with African.  This is the first example mention in Junaid Rana&#8217;s &#8220;Labor Diaspora and Global Racial System&#8221;, she tried to use this example to show us  how transnational labors have to face racism and discrimination.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=Ghcd7ZZ6sy4#at=37">Growing Up Muslim in Post 9/11 America</a></p>
<p>This video show us how Muslim were living in fears to social after 9/11 because they were seen as dangerous terrorists by the others.  In Rana&#8217;s piece, there is an example of Changez who have lived in NY for more than 10 years before the world trade center attack in 2001.  He already settled his life in America because even though he married his wife in Pakistan, and he tried to get his wife to immigrate to U.S. once he gained his green card.  It shows that he sees America as the country to be settle down with.  Rana stated his fear of deportation and the climate of racial anxiety that followed 9/11 in relation to Kokoye (girl in the video).  Kokoye came to the U.S. since the age of 5 and she adopted the American culture to go to the state fair every year, but her father refused to bring her to the fair after the world trade center attack because of the climate of racial anxiety that Rana mentions in her piece.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/03/researcher-73/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">544</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher June 24th &#8211; &#8220;LIFE&#8221; Magazine and &#8220;Japanese War Bride&#8221; film</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/23/httpwww-english-illinois-edumapspoetsa_ffosterlifemag-htmhttpwww-english-illinois-edumapspoetsa_ffosterlifemag-htm/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/23/httpwww-english-illinois-edumapspoetsa_ffosterlifemag-htmhttpwww-english-illinois-edumapspoetsa_ffosterlifemag-htm/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 04:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resources]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=420</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.english.illinois.edu/maps/poets/a_f/foster/lifemag.htm &#8220;The Cold War Origins of the Model Minority Myth&#8221; by Robert Lee mentioned on page 147 that Life magazine&#8217;s descriptions of using Tojo, as the current Premier of Japan during the World War II to represent the Japanese, and how to use him to identify the difference between Japanese and Chinese.   The link above [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.english.illinois.edu/maps/poets/a_f/foster/lifemag.htm">http://www.english.illinois.edu/maps/poets/a_f/foster/lifemag.htm</a></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>The Cold War Origins of the Model Minority Myth</em>&#8221; by Robert Lee mentioned on page 147 that Life magazine&#8217;s descriptions of using Tojo, as the current Premier of Japan during the World War II to represent the Japanese, and how to use him to identify the difference between Japanese and Chinese.   The link above is about the <em>Life</em> magazine that was published in December 22nd, 1941, the time when Japan was invading China.  These two nations were against each other as enemy in WWII.  During WWII,  Americans failed to distinguish these two Asian groups, they cannot tell a Chinese to Japanese.  The purpose of this article is to teach Americans how to &#8220;distinguish friendly Chinese to enemy aliens Japanese&#8221;. Besides the original pictures that was published from the Life magazine, this link also included with the original texts.</p>
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/japanese-war-bride.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-428" alt="japanese-war-bride" src="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/japanese-war-bride.jpg?fit=300%2C300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/japanese-war-bride.jpg?resize=195%2C300 195w, https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/japanese-war-bride.jpg?w=391 391w" sizes="(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a> <a href="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/nakajima.png"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-429" alt="nakajima" src="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/nakajima.png?fit=300%2C300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/nakajima.png?resize=206%2C300 206w, https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/nakajima.png?w=245 245w" sizes="(max-width: 206px) 100vw, 206px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Here are the poster and film scene from &#8220;Japanese War Bride&#8221; directed by King Vidor in 1952.  It was mentioned in &#8220;War, the Homeland, and the Traces of Memory&#8221; by David Palumbo-Liu. This movie is about an American Soldier fell in love with a Japanese Red Cross Nurse in Japan, they fall in love with each other and then they went back to Salinas, California together.  Jim Sterling (the American Soldier)&#8217;s family were separated into two different sides, some of them were willing to accept their marriage while some of them opposed.  Vidor&#8217;s tried to point out the contradictions between American and Japanese after the World War II.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/23/httpwww-english-illinois-edumapspoetsa_ffosterlifemag-htmhttpwww-english-illinois-edumapspoetsa_ffosterlifemag-htm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">420</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; June 17th</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/16/primary-reader-june-17th/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/16/primary-reader-june-17th/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 02:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=380</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The two readings we have to do before class is “Introduction” and “Domesticating Labor” in Collies and Cane: Race, Labor, and Sugar in the Age of Emancipation by Moon-Ho Jung, and “The Racial Triangulation of Asian Americans” by Claire Jean Kim.  We are reading two parts of Jung’s book and the introduction starts with a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The two readings we have to do before class is “Introduction” and “Domesticating Labor” in <span style="text-decoration: underline">Collies and Cane: Race, Labor, and Sugar in the Age of Emancipation</span> by Moon-Ho Jung, and “The Racial Triangulation of Asian Americans” by Claire Jean Kim.  We are reading two parts of Jung’s book and the introduction starts with a Chinese guy called Tye Kim Orr’s journal from China to Singapore to Guiana, Trinidad, Cuba, and finally reached Louisiana.  Orr who is the main character of the book and he symbolized the first Chinese immigrant to the U.S. during the 19<sup>th</sup> century because he tried to help Chinese to migrate to the U.S.  He was educated and has the ability to communicate with people in English.  The introduction also includes a preview for each chapters of the book and it is all about the history of Chinese immigrants in the U.S. and how the “Coolie” identifies the Chinese immigrants.</p>
<p>In the chapter “Domesticating Labor”, it is a chapter about the Chinese immigrant movements in the U.S. During the beginning of 19<sup>th</sup> century, there was a high demand for Chinese labor because of their low salary, but that also created hatred toward the Chinese immigrants because the whites consider the highest class, and black is the lowest.  Asian was ranking between them or with the blacks.  Jung demonstrated an example from the <i>New Orleans Times</i> “presented the Chinese as the vehicle to kill the Fifteenth Amendment, which was to extend the ballot beyond ‘the intelligent white or Caucasian race,’ many of whose members, let alone blacks and Asians, lacked the capacity to vote”.  Jung also listed the examples of “workingmen’s movement” and “Sham- Democracy” which demanded the end the Chinese migration.  This chapter tells us the history of Louisiana’s planters associated with Chinese labor, how they prefer “China men” instead of “Negroes”.  Posters were also being used to against the Chinese labor, and it also provided negative images of “nation of immigrants” to the public.</p>
<p>Jean’s “Racial Triangulation of the Asian Americans” is different from Jung’s book because this is like a research paper done by Jean to support her questions and themes.  In the introduction part of the paper, she stated her purpose of writing this paper and arguments.  Jean argues that “Asian American specifically have been racially triangulated” with the whites and blacks.  Her definition to racial triangulation is how dominant Whites valorize subordinate Asians relative to subordinate Blacks on cultural and/or racial grounds in order to dominate both groups.  Jean then followed with the research of history and how these supported her thesis.  Compare to Jung’s work, her paper is based on her personal thoughts and opinions with the supporting materials she provided, and Jung is focused on the past historical facts to demonstrate us the readers the 19<sup>th</sup> century society of the U.S.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/16/primary-reader-june-17th/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">380</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researcher &#8211; 3</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/11/researcher-3/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/11/researcher-3/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 02:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resources]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[These are the Anti- Chinese poster during the 19th century.  During the mid 19th century, many Asians started to immigrate to the U.S. and that brought the attention of public.  Anti- Asians racism started to raise up because of the cultural difference and they blamed the Asians for making them to lose jobs and the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/anti-chinese-10.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-291" alt="Anti - Chinese Poster " src="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/anti-chinese-10.jpg?fit=300%2C300" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/anti-chinese-10.jpg?resize=216%2C300 216w, https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/anti-chinese-10.jpg?w=324 324w" sizes="(max-width: 216px) 100vw, 216px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><a href="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/Anti-Chinese-5a.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-292" alt="Anti-Chinese-5a" src="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/Anti-Chinese-5a.jpg?fit=300%2C300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/Anti-Chinese-5a.jpg?resize=289%2C300 289w, https://i2.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/Anti-Chinese-5a.jpg?w=320 320w" sizes="(max-width: 289px) 100vw, 289px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a> <a href="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/brk00001484_16a_j.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-293" alt="brk00001484_16a_j" src="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/brk00001484_16a_j.jpg?fit=300%2C300" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/brk00001484_16a_j.jpg?resize=227%2C300 227w, https://i1.wp.com/keithmiyake.info/asam210/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/06/brk00001484_16a_j.jpg?w=568 568w" sizes="(max-width: 227px) 100vw, 227px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a>
<p>These are the Anti- Chinese poster during the 19th century.  During the mid 19th century, many Asians started to immigrate to the U.S. and that brought the attention of public.  Anti- Asians racism started to raise up because of the cultural difference and they blamed the Asians for making them to lose jobs and the spread out of disease because of their style of living.  These posters were used to spread out the Anti- Asians racism, they wanted to kick the Asians out of the U.S. during the mid 19th century.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/11/researcher-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">290</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Primary Reader &#8211; Said and Shah&#8217;s Orientalism and Politics of Knowledge</title>
		<link>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/</link>
		<comments>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 03:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gloria Cho]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edward Said]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nayan Shah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orientalism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=186</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The readings we have to read before class is the introduction from Orientalism by Edward Said and “Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown” by Nyan Shah.  These two readings shared the ideas of how Asians or Chinese were viewed by the Europeans and White Caucasians during the 19th century.  Medias and literature were being [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The readings we have to read before class is the introduction from <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Orientalism</span> by Edward Said and “Public Health and the Mapping of Chinatown” by Nyan Shah.  These two readings shared the ideas of how Asians or Chinese were viewed by the Europeans and White Caucasians during the 19<sup>th</sup> century.  Medias and literature were being used to portray negative image of Asians in the western world, and that created discriminations and against the east side.</p>
<p>Said stated his point of view of how the Europeans declare themselves as orientalism and separated themselves from the East.  They think the West which represents them is more civilized and exotic than the East, and also see the East as a lower class compares to them.  They described the East as orientals because their culture is different from them, which makes the Europeans see them as a cruel, uncivilized, uneducated group of people.  Said also mentioned that the Europeans have the idea to educate this group of uncivilized people (orientals) into a civilized group (orientalisms) like them.  Different countries have different culture and the cultural difference made the Europeans to classify themselves as the higher class just because the east side has a different way of living.  The other point Said mentioned in the introduction is the westerners started to portray Asians as uncivilized group into Medias, literatures, etc… That created a wide spread negative image of the east in the western society.</p>
<p>Shah is trying to tell us the same idea, but the difference between him and Said is he used references to support his idea.  This is including the investigations done by Logan, Anti- Coolie (group against Chinese immigrants in San Francisco) and the acts by government were used against the Chinese immigrants.  During the late 1800, the rapid growth of Chinese immigrants brought the Caucasians’ attention.  White workers started to lose their job because of the Chinese workers and the cholera and smallpox epidemic in San Francisco built discriminations toward the Chinese immigrants.  The Caucasians started to blame Chinese immigrants for making them unemployed and the crowded living spaces in Chinatown created the spread of cholera and smallpox.  Groups like Anti- Coolie were formed to against the Chinese immigrants and wanted to kick them out of the state, investigations on the real side of Chinatown also portrayed negative image of Chinese immigrants to the public.  One of the example is being used by Shah is Logan’s investigation, Shah stated Logan’s ignorance of the good side of Chinatown like the merchant’s homes, drug goods stores, temples, meeting rooms, and Chinese opera theatre.  Logan only focused on gambling house, opium dens, and brothel which brought more attentions from the public on the Chinese immigrants and made the public wanted to explore more negative facts from Chinatown, San Francisco.  This is just like Said’s point of view from the Europeans, because of the cultural differences between the east and west, Chinese/ Asians have an extreme negative image in the Caucasians world during the 19<sup>th</sup> century.  Although there were assumptions on the dirty and crowded environment created by the Chinese immigrants cause harms to others’ health issues, but Shah stated that there were no legal or extralegal action on the Board of Health’s condemnation of Chinatown ever occurred.  The other interesting fact Shah used to support the research is the U.S. congress actually passed the Chinese Exclusion Act in 1882 to disallow the Chinese workers to immigrate, so this will decrease the white workers’ unemployment rate and also a discrimination act made by the congress.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/04/primary-reader-said-and-shahs-orientalism-and-politics-of-knowledge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">186</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
