<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
  >

<channel>
  <title>Siyu (Lucy) Liu &#8211; Asians in the U.S.</title>
  <atom:link href="{{site.baseurl}}/asam210/author/sliu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/asam210</link>
  <description>Hunter College, Summer 2013</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <language>en-US</language>
  <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
  <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">53277463</site>  <item>
    <title>Primary Reader 7/10 readings</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 13:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=602</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In Aoyagi Storm&#8217;s article, the CRAASH movement is described in great details and truly exposed the emotions of the students involved in the movement. Prior to this course I had no idea in such action taken to revitalize the AASP program here at Hunter. After reading this article I admire Olivia Lin for speaking out [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Aoyagi Storm&#8217;s article, the CRAASH movement is described in great details and truly exposed the emotions of the students involved in the movement. Prior to this course I had no idea in such action taken to revitalize the AASP program here at Hunter. After reading this article I admire Olivia Lin for speaking out passionately, at the same time representing the rest who felt the same way about gaining justice and more attention for the program. I like how this article transitions, and in the conclusion it brings a Californian student to provide her take and comparison of the AASP program here to the one in CSUN. I like the quote of, &#8220;This is New York City, this is not Middle America, and we are fighting for Asian American studies. We are fighting for the education we were promised.&#8221; As one of the most diverse and popular city in the world, and one of the only CUNY that offers AASP courses, the students have the right to fight for the best of their education especially if they take great interest in the field.</p>
<p>In Karen Umemoto&#8217;s article, &#8220;the San Francisco State College strike was a microcosm of this struggle over cultural hegemony.&#8221;  The main focus of the strike was to redefine education in links to American society. (25). She analyzes the strike in four stages; from 1964 to Summer of 1969.  She also talks about the concept of &#8220;internal colonialism&#8221; which &#8220;became popular to depict the oppressed status of minorities in America. (30). Also self determination was stressed to be an important term. For PACE members, the term helped people to understand what they were trying to express. The Asian American Political Alliance saw the importance to build alliances based on race and common oppression, and &#8220;political organization should not only effect change but build new non-hierarchical social relationships.&#8221; (36- 37). However they were only to create ideas to effect social, economical and political changes. In Third World Liberation Front, &#8220;the demands of the coalition set a foundation for unity and defined the political issues and struggles which occurred through the course of the strike.&#8221;  (38).  In their goals, the themes of freedom and self- determination are evident. The TWLF people saw self-determination to give &#8220;each nationality the right to determine its own curriculum and hire its own faculty&#8221; for ethnic studies courses. (40). I found it interesting when they said their students found those who lived the ethnic experiences could best teach about it.</p>
<p>In Yamashita&#8217;s I-hotel, which is a 600 pages novel and we were assigned about 76 pages of it, I found the style to be very interesting. It is almost written in a play form sometimes, or overview for an actor or director&#8217;s scripts. I found it interesting when some of the names mentioned were hidden in black highlight, and the voice over&#8217;s job to provide us the settings. On page 136, I found the policeman 1 very violent to punch the student in the stomach with his club and ignorant with the policeman 2 when they thought all the students looked alike because they &#8220;all got black hair and brown eyes&#8221;, while they continued to beat the student up. Then they booked the student for assaulting them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/10/primary-reader-710-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Researcher for 7/8 readings</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/08/researcher-for-78-readings/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/07/08/researcher-for-78-readings/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 01:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=576</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In class we discussed the keywords for Asian Americans in the 1960s, 70s, 80s and 90s. http://www.unlearningracism.org/writings/lib_theory.htm This piece by Ricky Sherover-Marcuse talks about liberation, oppression, differences and conditions between groups and class etc. His definition of liberation is &#8221; both the undoing of the effects and the elimination of the causes of social oppression. The achievement of [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In class we discussed the keywords for Asian Americans in the 1960s, 70s, 80s and 90s.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unlearningracism.org/writings/lib_theory.htm">http://www.unlearningracism.org/writings/lib_theory.htm</a></p>
<p>This piece by Ricky Sherover-Marcuse talks about liberation, oppression, differences and conditions between groups and class etc. <span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif">His definition of liberation is &#8221; both the undoing of the effects and the elimination of the causes of social oppression. The achievement of human liberation on a global scale will require far-reaching changes at the institutional level and at the level of group and individual interactions. These changes will involve transforming oppressive behavioral patterns and &#8220;unlearning&#8221; oppressive attitudes and assumptions.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><a href="https://my.vanderbilt.edu/perkins/files/2011/09/empintro.proquest.pdf">https://my.vanderbilt.edu/perkins/files/2011/09/empintro.proquest.pdf</a></p>
<p>This piece by Douglas Perkins and Marc Zimmerman discusses the theory of empowerment. I like how they talk about the empowerment process and empowerment outcome. Empowerment process includes leadership and decision making in organizations and communities. Empowerment outcome includes control and resource mobilization skills. &#8220;Community level empowerment outcomes might include evidence of pluralism, and existence of organizational coalitions, and accessible community resources. &#8221; (570)</p>
<p>Empowerment allows the enhancement of group participation and the accomplishment of goals in organizations.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I believe there&#8217;s a definite contrast between the two keywords. For liberation, there is a sense of undoing what&#8217;s already been there and done. For empowerment, there is a sense of achieving communication and hoping for the combination of great leadership and group participation in all organizational groups.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/08/researcher-for-78-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">576</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Primary Reader on 7/1 readings</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/07/01/primary-reader-on-71-readings/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/07/01/primary-reader-on-71-readings/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 13:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=517</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Junaid Rana talks about a concept of moral panic. She connects it to the Islamic peril which formed a racial category of &#8220;dangerous Muslims&#8221;.  These relations appeared as the aftermath of 9/11 resulted in violence.  She argues the moral panic is like a racial panic, similar to the fear through out the Pearl Harbor attacks, [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Junaid Rana talks about a concept of moral panic. She connects it to the Islamic peril which formed a racial category of &#8220;dangerous Muslims&#8221;.  These relations appeared as the aftermath of 9/11 resulted in violence.  She argues the moral panic is like a racial panic, similar to the fear through out the Pearl Harbor attacks, (52) and how&#8221; the role of the racial panic is to intensify the categories of racialization within the racial formation.&#8221;  Terror, fear, panic and peril are the main terms flowing around. Terror is simply about manufacturing fear. (55).  And according to Eqhal Ahmad, which I found interesting was how he defines terrorism to be &#8220;both state and the law are potential instruments of terror, an argument that runs counter to postulations of terrorism as violence against the state.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sunaina Maira talks about new meanings for South Asian immigrant youth in terms of citizenship and racialization. She argues that &#8220;young muslim immigrants&#8217; understandings of citizenship shed light on the ways in which nationalism in the U.S is defined in relation to transnationalism and globalization, multiculturalism and polyculturalism, and increasingly overtly, to the links between domestiic and foreign policy that underlie U.S imperial power&#8221; (336). She based this paper on her study in fall 2001 which focused on Indian, Pakistani, etc. students in Cambridge. She said Cambridge is a good location for the research because it is a place to be politically liberal and the school has a diverse group of students, the largest population in the school to be Muslim. (337). And she goes on to talk about cultural citizenship which becomes important after legal citizenship to become not enough for protection under the law with War on Terror going on.  Flexible citizenship, she defines as a concept of the migrants&#8217;usage of transnational links to provide political or material resources not available to them. (339). I found it interesting when she tells us that after 9/11 happened, citizenship seemed to be less important to immigrants within Muslims and South Asians/Arabs comparing to the shield against abuses of civil rights. (340).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Nadine C. Naber argues that the U.S government is also responsible for the purse of imperialist policies, which resulted the inspiration and planning of the attacks on 9/11.  She talks about coalition building in Asian American politics. The separation between categories of Arab, Middle Eastern and Muslim has brought to question. Coalition has centralized racial justice as a basis against impact of war on terror. What I found interesting was, &#8220;the U.S state and media have reproduced the historical contradictions of U.S racial formations that  fuel hate violence, while at the same time promoting tolerance and diversity.&#8221;  (222).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/07/01/primary-reader-on-71-readings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">517</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Researcher on Lisa Lowe, Anderson &#038;  Lee, Kwon 6/26</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/28/researcher-on-lisa-lowe-anderson-lee-kwon-626/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/28/researcher-on-lisa-lowe-anderson-lee-kwon-626/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 01:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=498</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[http://culturemining.blogspot.com/2009/12/journal-of-changing-artwork-lucy.html This blogger Kala Burke wrote a little nice article about her reflection on the Lisa Lowe piece connected to a book called &#8220;Lucy&#8221; by Jamaica Kincaid. The character of Lucy (same name as me, funny),  is an Antiguan girl, who moved to America to become an au pair , which by definition is ,&#8221; a domestic [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://culturemining.blogspot.com/2009/12/journal-of-changing-artwork-lucy.html">http://culturemining.blogspot.com/2009/12/journal-of-changing-artwork-lucy.html</a></p>
<p>This blogger Kala Burke wrote a little nice article about her reflection on the Lisa Lowe piece connected to a book called &#8220;Lucy&#8221; by Jamaica Kincaid. The character of Lucy (same name as me, funny),  is an Antiguan girl, who moved to America to become an au pair , which by definition is ,&#8221; a domestic assistant from a foreign country working for, and living as part of, a host family.&#8221; Since her move, she has been longing Antiguan culture and it applies to “certain identification and relation to [her] homeland,” which cannot be lost or forgotten&#8221;&#8221;. But then she also finds herself adatping to the U.S culture, therefore an example of hybridity.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.helium.com/items/1475727-what-is-psychological-displacement" class="broken_link">http://www.helium.com/items/1475727-what-is-psychological-displacement</a></p>
<p>A brief article on psychological displacement. I thought out of all displacements we&#8217;ve talked about in class, this one stood out the most.</p>
<p>Angela Diggs defines it as &#8221; a cataleptic defense mechanism whereas the mind redistributes effects from an entity felt to be harmful or unacceptable to a thing felt to be acceptable and secure.&#8221; In a way she explains it, it&#8217;s like distributing your emotions on another person. She uses an example of a boy being bullied in school but ignored them and instead displaces his anger on his mother at home. I found this to be very interesting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/28/researcher-on-lisa-lowe-anderson-lee-kwon-626/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">498</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Primary Reader on Lisa Lowe and Leti Volpp</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 05:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=410</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Lisa Lowe introduced the relationship between national culture and citizenship in the beginning. One becomes &#8220;American&#8221; if him or herself becomes, acts or speaks like one. She incorporated how Wars played critical roles in defining Asians as the &#8220;others&#8221;.  I found it interesting when she mentioned how architect Maya Lin&#8217;s monument for the Vietnam War [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lisa Lowe introduced the relationship between national culture and citizenship in the beginning. One becomes &#8220;American&#8221; if him or herself becomes, acts or speaks like one. She incorporated how Wars played critical roles in defining Asians as the &#8220;others&#8221;.  I found it interesting when she mentioned how architect Maya Lin&#8217;s monument for the Vietnam War wasn&#8217;t one that could represent the American nation because American soldiers are the ideal citizen and representative of the nation, and since Lin is Asian and therefore, an &#8220;alien&#8221;,  her monument wasn&#8217;t as valued.  Even if Asian Americans are citizens of the U.S, they are excluded from the racial and cultural boundaries of the U.S.  I like how she emphasizes how when we focus Asian Americans as &#8220;immigrants&#8221;, we have to see how the U.S state determines Asian Americans&#8221; life  through immigration laws, the denial of enfranchisement, processes of citizenship etc. Also, how gender played a role in citizenship was interesting because if a female citizen marries a non citizen male, she loses her citizenship. Feminism did not step to part when it came to citizenship.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Leti Volpp&#8217;s article used some of Lowe&#8217;s points. She explains four/five types of citizenship; citizenship as legal status, as rights, as political activity , as identity and as solidarity. In citizenship as legal status, the inability to naturalize for Asian immigrants was because they did not or could not own land. Land meant a sense of power and it was important to obtain the property of it. The law that took away the citizenship of women when they marry non citizen men &#8220;primarily affected women who married Asian men&#8221; (74) was interesting to me. That means females back then would fear over the loss of their citizenship if they want to marry their true love. The 1943 Magnuson Act allowed Chinese to become citizens but only due to foreign policy reasons. (74). Citizenship as rights -to own civil rights, political rights and social rights. She mentions the discourses of colorblindness and liberal multiculturalism. Citizenship as political activity- that citizens had to be virtuous and be active in politics, also along the side of ownership of property. But Asian Americans were not eligible to even have ownership. Chinese apparently have no understanding of government but despotism (78.79). They are not assimilated due to lack of Republican understandings. Citizenship as identity basically tells if one ties to community and culture in the nation. The identity of Asian Americans were changed from &#8220;yellow peril&#8221; to &#8220;model minority&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/19/primary-reader-on-lisa-lowe-and-leti-volpp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">410</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Researcher: Kim, Claire Jean and Jung, Moon-Ho</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/17/researcher-kim-claire-jean-and-jung-moon-ho/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/17/researcher-kim-claire-jean-and-jung-moon-ho/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 02:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=368</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[http://www.jstor.org.proxy.wexler.hunter.cuny.edu/stable/view/4624907?&#38;Search=yes&#38;searchText=underclass&#38;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3FQuery%3Dmodel%2Bminority%2Band%2Bthe%2Bunderclass%26Search%3DSearch%26gw%3Djtx%26prq%3Dmodel%2Bminority%26hp%3D25%26acc%3Don%26aori%3Da%26wc%3Don%26fc%3Doff 1. Above is an article titled &#8220;Complicating the Image of Model Minority Success: A Review of Southeast Asian American Education&#8221; by authors Bic Ngo and Stacey J. Lee. In order to access, you need your Hunter ID and password. It discusses about the model minority stereotypes of Asian Americans. The popular press or media [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.jstor.org.proxy.wexler.hunter.cuny.edu/stable/view/4624907?&amp;Search=yes&amp;searchText=underclass&amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3FQuery%3Dmodel%2Bminority%2Band%2Bthe%2Bunderclass%26Search%3DSearch%26gw%3Djtx%26prq%3Dmodel%2Bminority%26hp%3D25%26acc%3Don%26aori%3Da%26wc%3Don%26fc%3Doff">http://www.jstor.org.proxy.wexler.hunter.cuny.edu/stable/view/4624907?&amp;Search=yes&amp;searchText=underclass&amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3FQuery%3Dmodel%2Bminority%2Band%2Bthe%2Bunderclass%26Search%3DSearch%26gw%3Djtx%26prq%3Dmodel%2Bminority%26hp%3D25%26acc%3Don%26aori%3Da%26wc%3Don%26fc%3Doff</a></p>
<p>1. Above is an article titled &#8220;Complicating the Image of Model Minority Success: A Review of Southeast Asian American Education&#8221; by authors Bic Ngo and Stacey J. Lee. In order to access, you need your Hunter ID and password. It discusses about the model minority stereotypes of Asian Americans. The popular press or media draws certain Asian American students as high achievers while the rest as dropouts and delinquents. Such stereotypes drew many complications.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/jZkIC7vZT5s?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe></p>
<p>2. Kyung Yoon explains in this short 3 minutes video of the model minority myth. She feels the importance to raise awareness around this topic.</p>
<p><a href="http://infopedia.nl.sg/articles/SIP_87_2004-12-15.html" class="broken_link">http://infopedia.nl.sg/articles/SIP_87_2004-12-15.html</a></p>
<p>3. Above is an article on Chinese &#8220;coolies&#8221; in Singapore. These coolies were recruited by secret societies called sin kheh and would be sent to employers based on their dialects. The transportation is paid by the sin kheh and these coolies were willing contribute labor in all sectors of work. However over time the demand for these coolies decreased due to the increase of economical development in Singapore.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/17/researcher-kim-claire-jean-and-jung-moon-ho/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">368</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>primary reader &#8211; Omi, Winant &#038; Molina, Natalia&#8217;s articles</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/09/primary-reader-omi-winant-molina-natalias-articles/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/09/primary-reader-omi-winant-molina-natalias-articles/#comments</comments>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 02:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Primary Reader]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=250</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In Omi and Winant&#8217;s article, the concept of race has two temptations, which is to think race as an essence, something fixed and to think race as an illusion. (54). They also focus on the understanding of race in relations to political issues. It is clear that race has depth beyond the whole biological distinction. [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Omi and Winant&#8217;s article, the concept of race has two temptations, which is to think race as an essence, something fixed and to think race as an illusion. (54). They also focus on the understanding of race in relations to political issues. It is clear that race has depth beyond the whole biological distinction. I found Omi and Winant&#8217;s question of &#8220;If the concept of race is so nebulous, can we not dispense within it? Can we not &#8220;do without&#8221; race, at least in the &#8220;enlightened present? &#8221; (55) to be quite interesting. The race concept has been a  problem within the past and it has been difficult to treat it as an old belief since everyone has their own understanding and a sense of bias that have been rigid and passed down in their own culture.  Racial formation revolves around hegemony, which by definition, leadership and dominance in social groups. Hegemony draws controversies and of course, racism. Inequality flows around how society is ruled in hegemony. Also, the governmental actions have played roles in the treatment towards people based on their race. There is the neoconservative, which sets it self to be color blind politics, and the liberal which affirms race, but with equality state policy. (58).  I also found the concept of how whites find &#8220;racially defined minority students as racists&#8221; and non whites see racism as &#8220;a system of power, and correspondingly argue that blacks, for example, cannot be racist because they lack power&#8221;. (70) to be intriguing since I never have thought of this. People of the races in the &#8220;minority&#8221; groups sometimes don&#8217;t mind their racist actions and words because they&#8217;ve been represented with inferiority. Stereotyping a race is also unconsciously done and ignored as racism.</p>
<p><em> &#8211; How does the racial formation theory evolve and draw less controversy?</em></p>
<p>Moving on to Natalia Molina&#8217;s article, the great city of Los Angeles has been &#8220;stressing the importance of improving sanitary conditions.&#8221; (1). In the first paragraph,the pollution problems point fingers at Chinatown because of the rotten sewer system, which draw similarity to some points argued by Nayan Shah.  But later on this article, three specific ethnicity of Chinese, Japanese and Mexican are apparently targeted the most in L.A to settle rotten spots as homes. The health officials in L.A wants to create a reputation of the city as &#8220;modern and healthful&#8221; because that creates the standards for &#8220;Americanness&#8221; (2). These people decide which Chinese people could build businesses, which Japanese people could get health care and which Mexicans could leave work camps. I found the concept of how U.S born and foreign born individuals in these three ethnicity to be permanently considered as &#8220;foreign&#8221; to be interesting because it is true. The title of the article is &#8220;Fit to Be Citizen&#8221;, almost sounding like you have to earn the rights to be considered as one in society no matter if you were born in America or an immigrant that has passed the citizen test. The concept of racism plays a crucial role since Asians are labeled to have &#8220;yellow peril&#8221; and Mexicans to be &#8220;naturally dirty&#8221;and inherently too ignorant to rectify their unsanitary living conditions.&#8221; (8). These labels are wild and exaggerated. The public health discourses &#8220;characterized the Chinese in L.A as dirty and unhygienic, disease carriers who, as launderers and produce vendors, threatened the health of citizens&#8221;. (12) The health of citizens is based on their responsibility to take care of themselves, not to point out a specific race to expose &#8220;dirty-ness&#8221; or so.</p>
<p><em>&#8211; How do we look beyond what races that cause sanitary issues and focus more on what can we do to fix the issues?</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>(Also, I have found the term of discourse to reappear constantly within these articles.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/09/primary-reader-omi-winant-molina-natalias-articles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">250</post-id> </item>
    <item>
    <title>Researcher : Nayan Shah&#8217;s article.</title>
    <link>/asam210/2013/06/06/researcher-nayan-shahs-article/</link>
    <comments>/asam210/2013/06/06/researcher-nayan-shahs-article/#respond</comments>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 05:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Siyu (Lucy) Liu]]></dc:creator>
        <category><![CDATA[Further Research]]></category>

    <guid isPermaLink="false">/asam210/?p=238</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[http://library.thinkquest.org/20619/Chinese.html This article provides the history of Chinese immigration and the creation of the first Chinatown in San Francisco. It also includes two black and white photos; first one shows the overcrowded situation Nayan Shah has talked about which led to the danger of health issues. The second images shows the Promontory Point at Central Pacific Railroad [&#8230;]]]></description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://library.thinkquest.org/20619/Chinese.html" class="broken_link">http://library.thinkquest.org/20619/Chinese.html</a></p>
<p>This article provides the history of Chinese immigration and the creation of the first Chinatown in San Francisco. It also includes two black and white photos; first one shows the overcrowded situation Nayan Shah has talked about which led to the danger of health issues. The second images shows the Promontory Point at Central Pacific Railroad which the Chinese helped to build and made shelter with. But no Chinese workers were shown because many of them died under the dangerous work situations around the gold mines and the railroads.  It also touches upon the Naturalization Act of 1870 and the Chinese Exclusion Act of 1882 which restricted Chinese immigration to the United States.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/aMtoUwFdZIM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe></p>
<p>The narrator in this documentary states some facts about Chinese immigration as many relating images are provided in the video.</p>
<p>From 5:40, you hear about the seclusion of new immigrants to Angel Island.</p>
<p>From 8:23, you hear about the exclusion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>/asam210/2013/06/06/researcher-nayan-shahs-article/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
    <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
  <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">238</post-id> </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
